2014-12-31,"Standouts in Tech: Drones, Virtual Reality, Instant Translation and A.I.",Farhad Manjoo picks four products from 2014 that are bringing the future closer.,0,"['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE']",0.0,0.125,neu,0
2015-01-01,Web Freedom Is Seen as a Growing Global Issue,"The new year promises further attempts at online censorship, as the web increasingly serves as a platform for civil rights efforts.",3,['DATE'],0.06818181818181818,0.4772727272727273,pos,1
2015-01-02,A Day With Apple Pay,The success of Apple Pay will in part be determined lies in the hands of the people behind retailers’ counters. How are those people doing two months after the service was introduced?,0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",-0.05000000000000002,0.35,neg,1
2015-01-02,Daily Report: Web Freedom Is Seen as a Growing Global Issue,"The new year promises further attempts at online censorship, as the web increasingly serves as a platform for civil rights efforts.",3,['DATE'],0.06818181818181818,0.4772727272727273,pos,1
2015-01-05,DealBook’s Most Popular Stories of 2014,"Investors fleeing emerging markets, Facebook’s deal for WhatsApp and @GSElevator were some of the most popular articles on DealBook in 2014.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'DATE']",0.55,0.7,pos,1
2015-01-05,"Apps Everywhere, but No Unifying Link","As people spend more time using apps, their Internet has taken a step backward, becoming more isolated — more like the web before search engines.",3,[],0.4875,0.5875,pos,0
2015-01-05,CES: A Push for Higher Resolution and Better-Looking TVs,"The big TV makers, including Samsung and Sony, showed off giant screens with sky-high display resolutions, and in a bid to push ultrahigh definition into the mainstream, several are teaming up with each other and content makers like Netflix.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.03125,0.36875,neg,1
2015-01-06,Moving Videos Between Mac and Android Gadgets,"Plus, how to track system updates on a Windows tablet.",0,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-06,Daily Report: Getting the Apps to Talk to Each Other,"As people spend more time using apps, their Internet has taken a step backward, becoming more isolated — more like the web before search engines.",3,[],0.4875,0.5875,pos,0
2015-01-06,The Year in Market Doublespeak,The last 12 months saw above-average creativity in saying one thing and meaning another. John Foley and Rob Cox of Reuters Breakingviews offer 10 euphemisms they would most like to disappear.,3,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']",0.25,0.2833333333333333,pos,1
2015-01-06,Intel Allocates $300 Million for Workplace Diversity,The fund is intended to help attract more women and minorities to the technology field and make the industry more hospitable to them once they get there.,3,[],0.5,0.5,pos,0
2015-01-07,Daily Report: Intel Pledges $300 Million to Increase Diversity in Tech Industry,The fund is intended to help attract more women and minorities to the technology field and make it more hospitable to them once they get there.,3,[],0.5,0.5,pos,0
2015-01-08,French Streaming Service Acquires Toehold in the U.S.,"Muve, a subscription service for prepaid mobile phones, will be discontinued in February and customers will be moved to Deezer, the company said.",2,"['PERSON', 'DATE', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-08,Mapping the World's Problems,Google Earth Engine works with scientists by using satellite imagery to provide data visualizations for environmental and health issues.,2,['ORG'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-08,Uber Tests a Cargo Delivery Service in Hong Kong,The ride-hailing start-up experiments with a new courier service.,1,[],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,0
2015-01-08,New Clues on Google’s Plans for Insurance,A Forrester analyst has speculated that Google is on the cusp of launching a U.S. insurance-shopping site.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-08,Apple’s Cut From App Sales Reached $4.5 Billion in 2014,"Google’s app store is the largest in the world, but still makes far less money than the Apple App Store.",0,"['ORG', 'LAW']",-0.033333333333333326,0.5333333333333333,neg,1
2015-01-09,"Box, a Data Storage Provider, Seeks Up to $162.5 Million in I.P.O.","Box said that it planned to price its shares at $11 to $13. At the midpoint of that range, the company would be valued at about $1.4 billion.",1,"['MONEY', 'MONEY']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-09,Daily Report: Box Seeks to Raise up to $162.5 Million in I.P.O.,"After several delays, Box is finally ready to make its stock market debut.",0,['PERSON'],0.1,0.25,pos,1
2015-01-09,Looking for the ‘Most Recent’ Facebook Posts,"Facebook eventually reverts to the “Top Stories” view of its news feed even if “Most Recent” is chosen, but there are ways around this.",2,[],0.3333333333333333,0.4166666666666667,pos,0
2015-01-09,"Two Schools of Thought, Adding Up to Success",Three funds that were among the top performers of the fourth quarter of 2014 combined elements of both growth and value investing.,3,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE']",0.25,0.25,pos,1
2015-01-11,Language Translation Tech Starts to Deliver on Its Promise,"It may sound like the stuff of science fiction, but translation tools are improving enough to imagine a day when a Spanish speaker and an English speaker can easily chat.",2,"['NORP', 'LANGUAGE']",0.16666666666666669,0.3466666666666667,pos,1
2015-01-12,"Roche to Buy Majority Stake in Foundation Medicine, Leader in Tumor Testing",The Swiss pharmaceutical giant Roche will pay more than $1 billion in a deal aimed at improving both cancer treatment and drug development.,0,"['NORP', 'ORG', 'MONEY']",0.25,0.75,pos,1
2015-01-12,PC Market Exited 2014 With a Whimper,"Many people and businesses haven’t found compelling reasons to buy new personal computers in recent years, and PC companies didn’t discover any new gimmicks to change their minds over the holidays.",1,"['DATE', 'DATE']",0.1787878787878788,0.4265151515151515,pos,1
2015-01-12,Parents Challenge President to Dig Deeper on Ed Tech,"While President Obama endorsed a voluntary student privacy effort by ed tech companies, some parents seek more comprehensive legislation.",1,['PERSON'],0.5,0.5,pos,1
2015-01-12,"Docker, a Software Start-Up, Sees a Future in Containers of Code",The start-up is in the forefront of a move to package applications much as shipping containers hold physical goods.,1,[],0.1,0.17142857142857143,pos,0
2015-01-13,Why Software ‘Containers’ Won’t Be Bad News for Programmers,The ability to compartmentalize software into sections that can be worked on one at a time will likely change how coders work. But that’s not necessarily a bad thing.,0,[],0.17499999999999996,0.8333333333333333,pos,0
2015-01-14,Google Translate App Gets an Upgrade,The company’s translation service is becoming a lot smarter — and a lot easier to use.,2,[],0.45,0.8500000000000001,pos,0
2015-01-14,Bigger Settlement Said to Be Reached in Silicon Valley Antitrust Case,"Apple, Google, Intel and Adobe are said to be offering $415 million to settle accusations that they conspired against their own employees.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'MONEY']",0.6,1.0,pos,1
2015-01-14,Daily Report: Tech Giants Said to Offer Bigger Settlement in Antitrust Case on Hiring,"Apple, Google, Intel and Adobe say a new deal has been struck to settle a lawsuit that asserts the companies had agreed not to directly solicit one another’s employees.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.11818181818181818,0.42727272727272725,pos,1
2015-01-14,Two Ex-Googlers Reunite at Venture Capital Firm,"Felicis Ventures, a small company (for Silicon Valley) has had some notable investments: Twitch, the video game streaming service that was sold to Amazon, and Rovio, the maker of the Angry Birds video game.",2,"['PERSON', 'LOC', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.21000000000000002,0.5399999999999999,neg,1
2015-01-14,Tracking Data Use to Avoid Hefty Phone Fees,"A number of apps can help monitor and manage data consumption on phones, to keep you within your plan’s limits and avert unpleasant surprises on your bill.",3,[],-0.6499999999999999,0.95,neg,0
2015-01-14,Video Feature: Getting the Most Out of Apple iOS 8,"The new operating system can help you monitor battery use better, help take better photos and make Siri easier to use.",0,['PERSON'],0.37878787878787873,0.48484848484848486,pos,1
2015-01-14,Facebook Looks to the Workplace for Future Growth,"The world’s largest social network of individuals is making a move into the corporate world, hoping to organize the workplace the way it has organized personal relationships.",1,[],0.011111111111111112,0.12222222222222222,pos,0
2015-01-14,"In Detroit, Google Makes a Case for Driverless Cars","Google hopes to have fully autonomous vehicles on the road by 2020, taking the driver out of the equation and handing the virtual wheel to software.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.4,0.7,pos,1
2015-01-15,Morning Agenda: Profit Slides at Bank of America,Bank of America reports uninspiring fourth-quarter results. | New York’s attorney general seeks expanded reporting on data breaches. | A strategy in the fight over Dodd-Frank. | BlackBerry’s stock goes on a wild ride.,2,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.09545454545454546,0.4515151515151515,pos,1
2015-01-15,Google Glass to Leave ‘X’ Research Lab as Nest’s Tony Fadell Takes Over Project,The wearable device will soon be a lot harder to buy as the Glass Explorer program will shut as part of the shift.,0,['ORG'],-0.1,0.0,neg,1
2015-01-16,"Google Said to Be in Talks to Acquire Softcard, a Mobile Payments Company",An unsuccessful e-commerce start-up may sell to one of the largest Internet companies in the world.,3,['CARDINAL'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-18,A Retreat for Google Glass and a Case Study in the Perils of Making Hardware,Consumers were never quite sure what to make of Google’s Internet-connected glasses.,3,['ORG'],0.5,0.8888888888888888,pos,1
2015-01-18,Microsoft Looks to Windows 10 for a Jolt in the Mobile Realm,"Windows 10 is the biggest effort yet by Satya Nadella, Microsoft’s new chief, who has been able to lift the company’s stock to a nearly 15-year high.",0,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.2240909090909091,0.5048863636363636,pos,1
2015-01-18,"Riding High, Biotech Firms Remain Wary",Soaring stock prices and major advances in fighting diseases have some saying the industry has turned a corner and others watching for a bursting bubble.,2,[],0.0625,0.5,pos,0
2015-01-18,Insurance via Internet Is Squeezing Agents,"Technology start-ups with websites that sell many types of insurance and promise savings with comparison shopping are putting pressure on insurance agents, who collect commissions.",2,[],0.5,0.5,pos,0
2015-01-19,Daily Report: Microsoft Looks to Windows 10 for a Boost in Mobile,Microsoft’s new operating system is the biggest effort yet by Satya Nadella to save the company’s moribund smartphone business.,1,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,1
2015-01-20,E.U. Official Urges Google to Offer Greater Concessions in Antitrust Inquiry,"Günther Oettinger, the European Union’s digital economy commissioner, said that while he respected what Google’s founders had achieved, the company must honor European rules.",2,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'NORP']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-20,Abandoning the Lollipop Ship,"Also, how to set up a “hybrid” network of wired and wireless connections.",0,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-20,Google and Fidelity Put $1 Billion Into SpaceX,"Google and Fidelity have invested in the rocketry company founded by Elon Musk, in part to further Google’s goal of extending the Internet’s reach through satellites.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'ORG']",0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-01-21,Daily Report: Google Makes a Big Bet on SpaceX,"Google has teamed up with Fidelity to invest in SpaceX, the rocketry company founded by Elon Musk, in part to further Google’s goal of extending the Internet’s reach through satellites.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'PRODUCT', 'ORG']",0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-01-21,Morning Agenda: Dollar Store Predicament,Shareholders are facing a quandary in the battle for Family Dollar. | President Obama sets agenda to help the middle class. | S.&P. is nearing costly settlements with the U.S. | Profit at Morgan Stanley disappoints.,0,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-21,Video Feature: Conjuring the Most From Google Android,"All of these tips work on the latest version of Android, known as Lollipop, but many of them work on the previous version, too.",3,['GPE'],0.2777777777777778,0.5222222222222223,pos,1
2015-01-21,"Dropbox Buys CloudOn, a Microsoft Document Start-Up","CloudOn, which allows its users to create Word and Excel documents on their mobile devices, will serve as Dropbox’s outpost in Israel.",0,"['ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-21,Venture Capital Outpaces Buyouts in Investment Returns,"Helped by deals like the Twitter I.P.O., the venture capital industry recorded a 25.9 percent internal rate of return in the 12 months through last June. Buyout funds turned in a 22.4 percent return.",0,"['ORG', 'PERCENT', 'DATE', 'PERCENT']",0.0,0.03333333333333333,neu,0
2015-01-21,"At Windows 10 Event, Microsoft Jumps Into Augmented Reality With HoloLens Headset","The HoloLens could help renew some of the luster Microsoft has lost in the last decade, when it reacted late to critical new technology trends.",1,"['GPE', 'ORG', 'DATE']",-0.04090909090909091,0.48030303030303034,neg,1
2015-01-21,"Video Feature: For Musicians, Apps for Tuning, Keeping Time and Organizing Charts","Getting to the music faster is easy with apps for the mundane tasks, like getting in tune and planning your set list.",1,[],0.13333333333333336,0.5,pos,0
2015-01-21,Marissa Mayer’s Plan for Yahoo Takes Hold. The Question Now Is Time.,"Marissa Mayer has made sharp acquisitions and rebuilt crucial products, but her future may depend on reaction to her plans for the Alibaba investment.",1,"['PERSON', 'NORP']",-0.041666666666666664,0.625,neg,1
2015-01-21,SpaceX Is a Throwback to the 1990s,"Google is investing in Elon Musk’s company, which is planning a broadband network of 4,000 satellites. The pioneering Teledesic tried something similar two decades ago but failed, notes Robert Cyran of Reuters Breakingviews.",0,"['ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.25,0.35,neg,1
2015-01-21,"EBay to Cut 2,400 Jobs, and Weighs 2nd Spinoff",The company plans a drastic restructuring in the face of slowing sales and intense competition.,0,[],0.2,1.0,pos,0
2015-01-21,Microsoft HoloLens: A Sensational Vision of the PC’s Future,"The device, which looks like ski goggles, superimposes holograms on reality and could have uses in communication, design, games, science and more.",3,[],0.5,0.5,pos,0
2015-01-21,Google Hopes to Take the Web Directly to Billions Lacking Access,The company believes it can use its growing collection of devices in the sky to spread the Internet to underserved areas around the world.,3,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-22,"Daily Report: Internet in Orbit, Linking Much of World Directly to Google",The company believes it can use its growing collection of devices in the sky to spread the Internet to underserved areas around the world — and sell more ads.,0,[],0.5,0.5,pos,0
2015-01-22,Morning Agenda: Goldman Trumps Volcker Rule,Goldman Sachs’s investments are testing the Volcker Rule. | The European Central Bank is expected to announce it will begin its bond-buying program. | Uber closes $1.6 billion in financing from clients of Goldman’s private wealth arm. | Regulators address “too big to fail.”,2,"['ORG', 'FAC', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'MONEY', 'ORG']",-0.09999999999999999,0.23749999999999996,neg,1
2015-01-22,"Button, a Mobile Start-Up, Looks to Link Apps With Commerce",The idea is similar to what Google did for search more than a decade ago.,2,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.25,0.45,pos,1
2015-01-22,Technology Leaders Define Digital Fault Lines,"Panelists at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, discussed the benefits and challenges of a rapidly changing digital landscape.",3,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']",0.1,0.1,pos,1
2015-01-22,Ford Opens Lab in Silicon Valley,"Mark Fields, Ford’s chief executive, said the company wanted to be seen as part of Silicon Valley’s ecosystem.",0,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-22,Online Storage Provider Box Prices I.P.O. at $14 a Share,"Box will be valued at $1.7 billion when it begins trading on Friday, but concerns have been raised within Silicon Valley about the highflying valuations that some technology darlings have fetched recently.",2,"['MONEY', 'DATE', 'LOC']",0.0,0.25,neu,0
2015-01-23,Vice Uses Virtual Reality to Immerse Viewers in News,"The directors Chris Milk and Spike Jonze, in partnership with Vice News, have created an eight-minute virtual-reality experience that catapults audiences into the center of the Millions March protest in New York in December.",1,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'TIME', 'EVENT', 'GPE', 'DATE']",0.018181818181818174,0.2772727272727273,pos,1
2015-01-23,Daily Report: Box Prices Its Offering at $14 a Share,"Box will be valued at $1.7 billion when it begins trading on Friday, but concerns have been raised within Silicon Valley about the highflying valuations that some technology darlings have fetched recently.",2,"['MONEY', 'DATE', 'LOC']",0.0,0.25,neu,0
2015-01-23,Sharing iTunes With the Whole Family,How to keep a passing interest from following you around on Google Now.,3,[],0.0,0.1,neu,0
2015-01-23,Online Storage Company Box Has Strong Debut in First Day of Trading,"Shares in the online file storage company closed 66 percent higher than its I.P.O. price, surpassing the $2.4 billion valuation that it fetched in its most recent private financing round.",0,"['PERCENT', 'ORG', 'MONEY']",0.075,0.3541666666666667,pos,1
2015-01-25,Tech Giants Invest in New Dreams of Grandeur,"A series of investments by some of the tech industry’s biggest companies may sound odd, but they point to larger ambitions in moving giant amounts of data.",2,[],0.05833333333333334,0.5375,pos,0
2015-01-25,Verizon’s Mobile ‘Supercookies’ Seen as Threat to Privacy,"Advertisers, and possibly other third parties, are finding ways to exploit a hidden tracking mechanism that Verizon Wireless users cannot delete.",0,"['ORDINAL', 'ORG']",-0.09722222222222221,0.23611111111111108,neg,1
2015-01-26,Morning Agenda: U.S. Challenges Insider Trading Ruling,Federal prosecutors seek to reverse a crucial insider trading ruling. | Markets shake off Greek election results. | An obscure law has its day. | PartnerRe and Axis Capital Holdings agree to merge.,2,"['NORP', 'ORG']",0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-01-26,Price Cuts for Crucial Microsoft Products Eroded Holiday-Season Profit,"The company said the weak personal computer market hurt its Windows business, as second-quarter net income dropped to $5.86 billion from $6.56 billion a year ago.",2,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'MONEY', 'MONEY', 'DATE']",-0.125,0.30833333333333335,neg,1
2015-01-27,Twitter Adds Group Messaging and Video Recording,"In an effort to catch up to rival services like Facebook, Twitter will now allow people to shoot, edit and post video directly from its mobile apps. Also, private messages on the service can now be sent to as many as 20 people.",0,"['PRODUCT', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL']",0.19999999999999998,0.425,pos,1
2015-01-27,Yahoo to Spin Off Its Stake in Alibaba,Shedding its 15 percent stake in the Chinese e-commerce site turns the spotlight to Yahoo’s plans to revamp its core Internet advertising business.,3,"['PERCENT', 'NORP', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-28,Avoiding Botnets With a Mac,"Windows PCs are often the main targets of malicious software that loops infected computers into remote-controlled networks called botnets, but Macs are not immune.",0,['PERSON'],0.16666666666666666,0.3333333333333333,pos,1
2015-01-28,Sony Teams Spotify With PlayStation for Music Streaming Plans,Sony announced that Spotify will effectively replace Music Unlimited this spring in 41 countries.,1,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.6,0.8,pos,1
2015-01-28,"After Alibaba Spinoff, Yahoo May Become a Takeover Target","By spinning off the stake into a separate company, Yahoo will be judged by its core Internet businesses.",1,['ORG'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-01-28,Video Feature: Signs That Virtual Reality Is on the Verge of Taking Off,"Major technology and media companies are investing heavily in virtual reality, a signal that the experience may soon be ready for mass consumption.",2,[],0.020833333333333332,0.5,pos,0
2015-01-29,"Microsoft Brings Outlook to iPhone, Other Mobile Devices","Outlook, Microsoft’s workhorse email application, has finally arrived on mobile devices, including iPhones and iPads.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT']",0.0,1.0,neu,0
2015-01-29,Morning Agenda: Yahoo as Takeover Target,Spinning off its stake in Alibaba may make Yahoo a takeover target. |Deutsche Bank swings to profit. | McDonald’s replaces its chief executive. | A push for a greater government role in housing finance.,2,"['GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.5,0.5,pos,1
2015-01-29,F.C.C. Sharply Revises Definition of Broadband,The new broadband benchmark sets downloads at a speed of 25 megabits per second and uploads of 3 megabits per second. The standard is used to guide policy in some areas.,1,"['CARDINAL', 'ORDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORDINAL']",0.03409090909090909,0.11363636363636363,pos,1
2015-01-29,Reddit Issues First Transparency Report,The popular message board gives insight into how often government agencies request data on Reddit users.,0,['NORP'],0.6,0.9,pos,1
2015-01-29,"Google Revenue Is Higher, but Profit Misses Expectations","The company’s results were squeezed by a number of temporary factors, including a strong dollar that ate into overseas sales.",1,[],0.4333333333333333,0.7333333333333333,pos,0
2015-01-30,Morning Agenda: Crackdown on Car Title Loans,Car title loans are drawing scrutiny from regulators. | Law firm founds a project to fight “revenge porn.” | Shake Shack is going public with big dreams. | How Apple beat Microsoft.,3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.06666666666666667,0.18888888888888888,neg,1
2015-02-02,"In Net Neutrality Push, F.C.C. Is Expected to Propose Regulating Internet Service as a Utility","Tom Wheeler, chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, is expected to propose reclassifying high-speed Internet as a telecommunications service.",2,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.1,0.4,neg,1
2015-02-02,Uber to Open Center for Research on Self-Driving Cars,"The ride-hailing service is partnering with Carnegie Mellon University, a hotbed for research in robotics and other artificial intelligence.",2,['ORG'],-0.3625,0.6875,neg,1
2015-02-03,Alibaba and Lending Club to Form Financing Partnership,The partnership will provide financing for U.S. manufacturers to buy products and supplies through Alibaba.com.,0,"['GPE', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-03,Obama’s Budget Seeks International Minimum Tax for Corporations,"A tax on foreign earnings trapped overseas is best thought of as a jobs-friendly international minimum tax, writes Victor Fleischer in the Standard Deduction column.",2,['PERSON'],0.135,0.08499999999999999,pos,1
2015-02-04,Tim O’Reilly Explains the Internet of Things,"The publisher and web guru says the Internet is about to cause its greatest changes, augmenting people with sensors and ever-present computing to create entirely new economic systems, and new ways of thinking about politics.",3,[],0.36818181818181817,0.5272727272727272,pos,0
2015-02-04,F.C.C. Plans Strong Hand to Regulate the Internet,The proposal would create legal authority to ensure that no content is blocked and that the Internet is not divided into fast and slow lanes.,3,[],0.033333333333333326,0.39999999999999997,pos,0
2015-02-04,Traveling With an iPhone,"Using your phone as a GPS unit is handy, but can run the battery down. Always pack a mobile phone charger.",1,[],0.2222222222222222,0.5944444444444444,pos,0
2015-02-05,Twitter and Google Said to Reach Deal on Search,The microblogging service is expected to announce a partnership that will make tweets easier to find in Google search results.,2,['ORG'],-0.1,0.4,neg,1
2015-02-05,Twitter’s Revenue Grows Despite User Stagnation,"The company said it had 288 million regular users in the last quarter, fewer than analysts’ expectations of about 291 million.",0,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.0,0.07179487179487179,neu,0
2015-02-06,"Limit ‘Right to Be Forgotten’ to Europe, Panel Tells Google",An eight-person committee advising Google on complying with a landmark privacy ruling by Europe’s highest court said it should apply only in the 28-nation European Union.,3,"['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'LOC', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-02-06,Dick Costolo of Twitter on Earnings Report,"CNBC interview with Dick Costolo, Twitter’s chief executive, who discusses his company’s earnings, user growth strategy and partnership with Google.",0,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-06,New Data Shows Apple’s Explosive Growth in China,"Both Kantar Worldpanel and Canalys, research firms that track global smartphone sales, said Apple’s mobile operating system gained market share in China at the expense of Google’s Android.",2,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-08,"As Technology Entrepreneurs Multiply in Vietnam, So Do Regulations","A growing list of government rules dictates how technology businesses must be run, including what they can do with their content.",1,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-08,Uncovering Security Flaws in Digital Education Products for Schoolchildren,"The law has long treated educational information as a category worthy of special protections, like credit or medical records, but the reality is often different.",3,[],0.1484126984126984,0.4702380952380953,pos,0
2015-02-08,Comcast-Time Warner Cable Deal Still Up in the Air a Year Later,The air of inevitability around Comcast’s proposed $45 billion acquisition of Time Warner Cable has dissipated as the F.C.C. prepares to vote on a proposal to regulate the Internet like a utility.,0,"['ORG', 'MONEY', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-09,Morning Agenda: U.S. Takes On Payday Lenders,The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau seeks to limit payday lenders. | The prime minister of Greece says he will carry out his campaign to roll back austerity. | Hidden cash is flowing into high-end real estate. | Shares of HSBC fall on tax avoidance claims.,2,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.008333333333333338,0.15833333333333333,pos,1
2015-02-09,"Sidecar, a Ride-Hailing Start-Up, Pushes Into Package Delivery","Sidecar said it planned to use its fleet of cars to power a package delivery service, delivering items like food and groceries for partner companies.",2,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-09,Microsoft and Samsung End Legal Dispute,"Almost six months after Microsoft sued Samsung, accusing it of violating the terms of a patent licensing agreement, the two companies on Monday said they had settled their feud.",3,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-10,A New Mobile Map Captures ‘Internet of Moving Things’,A start-up has released a map for mobile phones that does impressive stuff without connecting to cloud-computing services. More important than its flashy augmented reality is a new kind of database it uses.,1,[],0.356060606060606,0.7257575757575757,pos,0
2015-02-10,Twitter Finance Chief’s Account Briefly Seized by Spammer,"The social network says that the account of its chief financial officer, Anthony Noto, was used to send a blast of spam on Tuesday. The company is investigating the incident.",2,"['PERSON', 'DATE']",0.016666666666666666,0.03333333333333333,pos,1
2015-02-10,Yelp Pays $134 Million for Food-Ordering Service,"The move is a departure for Yelp, whose main business has been selling advertising bought by local businesses with those reviews.",1,['ORG'],0.08333333333333333,0.16666666666666666,pos,1
2015-02-11,Importing Images to iPhoto,"Tips on how to transfer photographs into iPhoto on your Mac, and advice for connecting to a virtual private network from a mobile device.",1,['ORG'],0.0,0.375,neu,0
2015-02-11,Survey of Foreign Companies in China Finds Pollution a Growing Problem,The report by the American Chamber of Commerce reflects on-the-ground attitudes that large Chinese cities have become less hospitable places to work.,2,"['ORG', 'NORP']",0.011904761904761904,0.1238095238095238,pos,1
2015-02-11,"Google, Mighty Now, but Not Forever","The tech giant is trying to evolve beyond a search behemoth, but it faces the same problems as the once-mighty tech companies that came before it.",2,[],0.0,0.5625,neu,0
2015-02-11,Jet.com Gets Investment That Values It at $600 Million,A soon-to-start online marketplace that aims to loosen Amazon’s grip on e-commerce raises $140 million.,0,"['ORG', 'MONEY']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-11,Twitter’s Chief Sees Plenty of Money in Tweet Flow,"Dick Costolo, chief executive of the social network, sketched out his plans for bringing in new revenue, from showing more ads in the feeds of Twitter users to helping brands hire popular users to create sponsored video content.",0,"['PERSON', 'PERSON']",0.3174242424242424,0.48030303030303034,pos,1
2015-02-12,"Aiming to Ease App Discovery, Apple Pairs With Pinterest","App Pins aims to do for smartphone apps what Pinterest’s service has done for photos, recipes and many other types of websites. In short, the service is a type of digital corkboard that lets visitors save, or “pin,” items they like or places they want to go.",3,['PERSON'],0.09375,0.29375,pos,1
2015-02-12,"Daily Report: Google Is a Mighty Force Now, but That May Not Last Forever","The tech giant is trying to evolve beyond a search behemoth, but it faces the same problems as the once-mighty tech companies that came before it.",2,[],0.0,0.5625,neu,0
2015-02-12,Expedia to Acquire Orbitz as Travel Sites Consolidate,"The transaction further solidifies the American market for online travel booking to two companies, Expedia and the much bigger Priceline Group.",2,"['NORP', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.0,0.3333333333333333,neu,0
2015-02-13,Daily Report: Obama Heads to Security Talks Amid Tensions,A long history of quiet cooperation between Washington and America’s top technology companies has been shattered by tension over the government’s use of technology companies for its intelligence purposes.,2,"['GPE', 'GPE']",0.15,0.41111111111111115,pos,1
2015-02-13,Morning Agenda: Standoff Over Greek Debt,All sides in the negotiations on Greek debt are betting others will blink first. | Lyft is is talks to raise about $250 million. | Expedia agrees to buy Orbitz. | Law schools are adding business-related offerings.,1,"['NORP', 'ORDINAL', 'MONEY', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.125,0.16666666666666666,pos,1
2015-02-13,"China’s Internet Restrictions Are Hampering Business, Foreign Companies Say","Businesses are growing increasingly frustrated by obstacles to Internet access, according to a survey by the European Union Chamber of Commerce in China.",2,"['ORG', 'GPE']",-0.25,0.06666666666666667,neg,1
2015-02-13,Obama Calls for New Cooperation to Wrangle the ‘Wild West’ Internet,The president signed an executive order urging companies to exchange data on cyberthreats and receive classified information from the government.,2,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-15,Slice and Carve: The Next Wave in Computer-Aided Creativity,Laser cutters and computer-controlled milling machines are coming out of industrial workshops and planting themselves on desktops.,2,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-15,Cellphone Start-Ups Use Wi-Fi First to Handle Calls and Take On Rivals,"Two start-ups are trying to lower cellphone costs by relying on Wi-Fi routers, and now some of the bigger companies are looking to follow their lead.",0,['CARDINAL'],0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-02-15,Hoping Google’s Lab Is a Rainmaker,"After patiently abiding a steep increase in research and development spending, Wall Street is starting to wonder when — and if — Google’s science projects will pay off.",3,['ORG'],0.0,0.1,neu,0
2015-02-15,Popular Demand,"Every tweet, video or comment online has branding power, just like ads on television or online.",0,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-16,"Astro Teller, Google’s ‘Captain of Moonshots,’ on Making Profits at Google X","Astro Teller, the head of the Google X research group, talks about the company’s efforts to commercialize projects like the self-driving car and why the Glass wearable device will still impact technology.",1,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-17,"IBM, G.E. and Others Create Big Data Alliance",A number of big tech companies with an interest in building out the big data market have announced a standard for core elements of a technology framework for data analysis.,2,[],0.0,0.06666666666666667,neu,0
2015-02-17,Securing a Hotmail Account,How to use two-step verification to guard against unauthorized access to your email.,2,['CARDINAL'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-02-18,Photoshop at 25: A Thriving Chameleon Adapts to an Instagram World,"Adobe, which introduced the image-editing program in 1990, has moved to a less expensive subscription-based model in an effort to democratize access.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",-0.3333333333333333,0.3833333333333333,neg,1
2015-02-18,"Same-Day Delivery Resurges, Adding Alcohol","Millennials accustomed to ordering food for delivery on smartphones have come of legal drinking age, and niche start-ups are poised to take advantage.",2,[],0.2,0.2,pos,0
2015-02-18,Microsoft Has Suddenly Gotten Serious With Mobile,"There’s a new strategy afoot at the company, which has brought apps and services to the Apple and Android devices people actually use, rather than ones that run Windows.",1,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.06818181818181818,0.2772727272727273,pos,1
2015-02-18,Dropcam Keeps an Eye on the Neighborhood,Setting up video surveillance on a driveway highlights the power of putting such tools in the hands of ordinary people.,0,[],-0.125,0.5,neg,0
2015-02-19,Daily Report: Microsoft Zeroes In on Mobile,"There’s a new strategy afoot at the company, which has brought apps and services to the Apple and Android devices people actually use, rather than ones that run Windows.",1,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.06818181818181818,0.2772727272727273,pos,1
2015-02-19,Yahoo Courts Mobile App Makers with New Tools,"Building on its acquisition of the start-up Flurry last year, the Internet company is seeking to broaden its influence with mobile application developers by offering them better analytic and advertising services.",0,"['GPE', 'DATE']",0.25,0.2833333333333333,pos,1
2015-02-19,F.D.A. Reverses Course on 23andMe DNA Test in Move to Ease Restrictions,The agency approved a test that would be administered to parents to see if they carry mutations that could cause a rare disorder called Bloom syndrome in their children.,2,['PRODUCT'],0.3,0.9,pos,1
2015-02-22,"Ellen Pao Suit Against Kleiner Perkins Heads to Trial, With Big Potential Implications",A high-profile harassment lawsuit brought against the prominent venture capital firm comes as attention mounts on gender issues in Silicon Valley.,0,['LOC'],0.15,0.7,pos,1
2015-02-22,Once-Popular Car Technologies at the End of the Road,"With technology in automobiles becoming increasingly sophisticated, some products are destined for the trash heap.",2,[],0.475,0.925,pos,0
2015-02-23,IBM Tries to Paint the Computing Cloud Blue,"IBM is going deeper in the plan of its chief, Virginia Rometty, to rebuild the computing giant as a cloud company. At a giant show in Las Vegas, the company announced new kinds of security and services for cloud applications, along with data centers in new countries.",1,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE']",0.06818181818181818,0.7272727272727273,pos,1
2015-02-23,Google Guns for Apple in Mobile Payments Race,The use of so-called proximity payment services is expected to accelerate in the coming year and Google isn’t ready to cede the market to companies like Apple and Samsung.,3,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.05,0.45,pos,1
2015-02-24,Filing Away Gmail Messages,"Tips on how to archive Gmail messages to tidy up your inbox, and solutions for when your laptop battery begins to fade.",1,[],0.6,0.8,pos,0
2015-02-24,Tough Talk From European Commissioner About U.S. Tech Companies,"Günther Oettinger, the European Commission member in charge of the digital economy, said that if companies did not comply with European data rules, they “ultimately, perhaps, may be thrown out of the single market.”",2,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'NORP']",-0.014285714285714285,0.24285714285714283,neg,1
2015-02-24,Onetime Mystery Informant in Galleon Insider Trading Case Gets No Jail Time,"Thomas Hardin, who worked for the hedge fund Lanexa Management, got some of his tips from the same woman who gave information to Galleon’s founder.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.0,0.125,neu,0
2015-02-24,F.C.C. Net Neutrality Rules Clear Hurdle as Republicans Concede to Obama,"The Republican resistance in Congress surrendered to President Obama’s call to protect an open Internet, with rules likely to be approved by regulators on Thursday.",1,"['NORP', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'DATE']",0.0,0.75,neu,0
2015-02-24,Stretching a City’s Limits,"When Google moved to Mountain View, Calif., in 1999, it had a dozen employees and was known only to computer aficionados.",0,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.0,1.0,neu,0
2015-02-25,"U.S. and British Agencies May Have Tried to Get SIM Encryption Codes, Gemalto Says","The digital security company said it believed attacks by the N.S.A. and its British counterpart occurred over two years, starting in 2010.",3,"['ORG', 'NORP', 'DATE', 'DATE']",0.0,0.03333333333333333,neu,0
2015-02-25,Stretching a City’s Limits,"When Google moved to Mountain View, Calif., in 1999, it had a dozen employees and was known only to computer aficionados. Now, 20,000 local employees make it the biggest employer in a city bursting at the seams.",0,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']",0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-02-25,"Google Plans New Headquarters, and a City Fears Being Overrun","Google’s sometimes testy relationship with community leaders in Mountain View, Calif., a city already bursting at the seams, is likely to get testier.",3,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']",0.0,1.0,neu,0
2015-02-25,A Google Computer Can Teach Itself Games,"A team at Google has developed a way a computer can sense inputs, learn rules and successfully play a number of classic video games. That’s a step up from the Jeopardy!-winning Watson, which was taught rules.",1,['ORG'],0.33888888888888885,0.47222222222222227,pos,1
2015-02-25,Stretching a City’s Limits,"When Google moved to Mountain View, Calif., in 1999, it had a dozen employees and was known only to computer aficionados.",0,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.0,1.0,neu,0
2015-02-25,"Vivek Wadhwa, Voice for Women in Silicon Valley, Is Foiled by His Tone",Mr. Wadhwa was one of the loudest male voices pushing for gender diversity in Silicon Valley. His story is a lesson in how not to handle criticism.,0,"['PERSON', 'LOC']",0.0,0.1,neu,0
2015-02-25,The Push for Net Neutrality Arose From Lack of Choice,"Regulating the Internet like a utility makes sense, proponents say, because Americans often have only one option for high-speed service: cable.",3,"['NORP', 'CARDINAL']",0.0,1.0,neu,0
2015-02-25,Privacy Group Files F.T.C. Complaint Against Samsung’s Voice-Operated TVs,The Electronic Privacy Information Center accused Samsung of violating federal laws with a technology that allows viewers to operate the company’s Internet-connected smart TVs with voice commands.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.057142857142857134,0.37142857142857144,pos,1
2015-02-26,"F.C.C. Approves Net Neutrality Rules, Classifying Broadband Internet Service as a Utility","The agency’s 3-2 vote is intended to ensure a level playing field for Internet content providers, with no so-called pay-to-play fast lanes.",3,['CARDINAL'],0.2,0.6,pos,1
2015-02-26,Will.i.am Start-Up Hires Sony Electronics Executive,"Phil Molyneux, who most recently was president and chief operating officer of Sony Electronics in the United States, will take on the same role at i.am+, a 60-person wearables start-up.",2,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL']",0.16666666666666666,0.2916666666666667,pos,1
2015-02-26,"Amazon Hires Jay Carney, Former Obama Press Secretary","Amazon has hired Mr. Carney as senior vice president for global corporate affairs. The move is unusual, as Amazon is known for grooming employees from within.",0,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.06666666666666667,0.3333333333333333,pos,1
2015-02-26,Dutch Offer Preview of Net Neutrality,"As with the rules adopted by the F.C.C., the Netherlands demands that wireless and fixed-line broadband providers treat all Internet traffic equally.",1,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.0,0.25,neu,0
2015-02-26,"Kobalt, Music Services Company, to Announce $60 Million in New Investment","The company, which handles music publishing rights, will use the money to expand its extensive data-tracking system.",0,[],0.0,0.3333333333333333,neu,0
2015-02-27,"At Aetna, a C.E.O.’s Management by Mantra","Mark Bertolini, the chief executive of Aetna, is betting that bringing yoga, meditation and higher wages to his employees will be good business.",0,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",0.475,0.55,pos,1
2015-02-27,Google Unveils Plan for New Corporate Campus,Google unveiled a radical proposal for a new campus that would replace its current headquarters in Mountain View.,1,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.06818181818181818,0.42727272727272725,pos,1
2015-02-27,Apple’s New Job: Selling a Smartwatch to an Uninterested Public,"The Apple Watch is scheduled to debut in April, a bit later than the company had hoped, because of technology challenges.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-01,"Samsung Galaxy S6 and Galaxy S6 Edge, Unveiled at Mobile World Congress, Offer Best of iPhone and More","Samsung has been accused of being a copycat, but after adding its own design twists to popular features borrowed from the competition, its new flagship phone feels like a real flagship.",1,['ORG'],0.3840909090909091,0.6636363636363636,pos,1
2015-03-01,An Uneasy Relationship Between Telecom and Tech,"Large mobile carriers and tech giants like Facebook and Google rely on one another, but they are competing to be consumers’ main source for Internet use on mobile devices.",2,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",0.19047619047619047,0.38095238095238093,pos,1
2015-03-02,Qualcomm and Intel to Introduce New Biometric Security Technology,Qualcomm has a new fingerprint reading technology that it hopes can eventually replace passwords both for devices and apps.,1,[],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,0
2015-03-02,Microsoft Presents Low-Cost Phones and Windows 10 for Mobile,"At the Mobile World Congress, the company for the first time showed off the operating system for phones and continued its evolving strategy of delivering low-cost Lumia devices.",2,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG']",0.25,0.3333333333333333,pos,1
2015-03-02,"Daily Report: The Apple Watch Is Nearly Ready, but Is the Public?","The Apple Watch is scheduled to start selling in April, but will buyers want it? While consumers have shown little interest in smartwatches so far, few people wanted tablets or smartphones before the iPad and iPhone were released.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.09583333333333333,0.5333333333333333,neg,1
2015-03-02,Google Confirms Plans for Wireless Service,The company is experimenting with a network that would rely primarily on Wi-Fi technology and use cellular towers as a backup.,2,[],0.4,0.5,pos,0
2015-03-02,Mark Zuckerberg Goes on Charm Offensive for Internet.org,"The chief of Facebook outlined why he thinks Internet.org, a service to provide people in emerging markets with free access to some online applications, would help telecommunications carriers persuade customers to spend more on streaming content to their cellphones.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.45,0.65,pos,1
2015-03-03,"At Geneva Auto Show, Worry About Silicon Valley","Apple and Google are using their technology domination to take over car dashboards. Someday, they could try to build entire vehicles.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.0,0.625,neu,0
2015-03-03,Nextdoor Social Network Digs Deep Into Neighborhoods,"The start-up and its investors see opportunities in the company’s more than 53,000 microcommunities.",0,['CARDINAL'],0.5,0.5,pos,1
2015-03-04,"Aids for the Indecisive, When Options Abound","A number of apps can help in decision making, whether you’re wavering over vacation destinations, a baby’s name or what to order for dinner.",1,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-04,Outdated Encryption Keys Leave Phones Vulnerable to Hackers,"Apple and Google said they were releasing patches to fix the problem, which results in part from 1990s American technology export restrictions.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'NORP']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-04,"To Bring Virtual Reality to Market, Furious Efforts to Solve Nausea","Oculus VR, Sony, HTC and other headset makers have incorporated technology to combat motion sickness, paving the way to mass-marketing their products.",1,"['GPE', 'ORG']",-0.125,0.375,neg,1
2015-03-05,Digital Learning Companies Falling Short of Student Privacy Pledge,A number of ed tech companies said they would improve the security and privacy of their services. But a new report concludes they are falling short of expectations.,1,[],0.06818181818181818,0.37727272727272726,pos,0
2015-03-05,Google Introduces Long-Anticipated Insurance Shopping Site,The Google Compare auto insurance shopping site could rattle the insurance industry and change how individual brokers do business.,2,['ORG'],0.0,0.4,neu,0
2015-03-05,"In Ellen Pao’s Suit vs. Kleiner Perkins, World of Venture Capital Is Under Microscope",What is really under examination in this trial is the question of why there are so few women in leadership positions in Silicon Valley.,0,['LOC'],0.0,0.15000000000000002,neu,0
2015-03-06,"In Boon to Its Stock, Apple Will Replace AT&T in Dow Index",The step is a reminder of the soaring valuations among consumer-driven technology and social media companies.,2,[],0.03333333333333333,0.06666666666666667,pos,0
2015-03-06,Troubleshooting Android in Safe Mode,Third-party apps and recent operating system updates are often the cause; starting the phone in Safe Mode can help narrow down the search for a culprit.,1,['PERSON'],0.02888888888888888,0.3077777777777778,pos,1
2015-03-08,Surge in Smartphones Sets Off New Wave of Corporate Self-Reinvention,"Companies like Ford, Procter & Gamble, Under Armour and the Spanish bank BBVA are working to outmaneuver start-ups for dominance on mobile devices.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'NORP', 'PERSON']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-09,"Kleiner Perkins, Disrupted","In an era of self-promotion and runaway hype, where every supporting player wants to be a star, it is nearly impossible to retain earlier ideals of restraint.",2,[],-0.054166666666666655,0.4625,neg,0
2015-03-09,Fighting Back Against Malware,"A flurry of pop-up ads, an unfamiliar search toolbar and a changed home page are just some of the symptoms of malicious software.",2,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-10,Facebook’s Status Update for Computing,"The latest development in Facebook’s push of open-source hardware: a new kind of networking switch, a powerful low-energy computer server and a steadily-increasing number of partners.",2,['PERSON'],0.3840909090909091,0.8136363636363636,pos,1
2015-03-10,"Google C.F.O. Is Retiring to Spend More Time With Family (No, Really)","While watching a sunrise from the highest point in Africa, Patrick Pichette decided it was time to “hit the road” with his wife and find his bliss, he wrote in a goodbye note.",2,"['LOC', 'PERSON']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-11,Google Offers Cheap Storage for Certain Kinds of Data,"Google just matched Amazon for cheap online storage, with an important difference: While Amazon promises to fetch the cheap data in hours, Google offers to do it in three seconds.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'TIME', 'ORG', 'TIME']",0.32500000000000007,0.6,pos,1
2015-03-11,Device Syncing: Call From Computers and Text From Tablets,"Technology from Apple, Google, BlackBerry and Motorola is increasingly allowing users to send texts and make phone calls from almost any device.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-11,Bento Wants to Be Your App Matchmaker,Bento is one of a number of start-ups that are trying to re-imagine search for mobile phones by anticipating what you want to do with your device.,0,['GPE'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-11,Review: Google Chromebook Pixel,"The top-of-the-line Google laptop, back in a new version, is meant more as a testing ground for new technology than a mass-market product.",1,['ORG'],0.19318181818181818,0.3522727272727273,pos,1
2015-03-11,Managing Estate Sales Becomes Big Business,The estate sale business is growing as the parents of baby boomers reach the end of their lives and the boomers themselves retire and downsize.,1,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-11,"Slack, the Office Messaging App That May Finally Sink Email","The start-up Slack is changing the way workers communicate, with a group chat app that eschews privacy and automatically archives almost everything.",1,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-11,Utah Passes White-Collar Felon Registry,"The Utah Legislature has approved legislation to build the nation’s first white-collar offender registry, affixing a scarlet letter of sorts on the state’s financial felons.",1,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL']",0.125,0.16666666666666666,pos,1
2015-03-11,"InMobi Plans to Stay Independent, Dismissing Rumors of Talks With Google",The chief executive of the Indian mobile advertising start-up denied reports that the company was discussing a possible acquisition by Google.,0,"['NORP', 'ORG']",0.0,1.0,neu,0
2015-03-12,Zuckerberg Lawsuit Documents Show Animosity With Would-Be Neighbor,Documents filed Wednesday accuse the Facebook chief executive of reneging on a promise to introduce a would-be neighbor to powerful Silicon Valley friends.,0,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.3,1.0,pos,1
2015-03-12,How to Find Old or Expired Websites,An Internet Archive offers a large and growing collection of web pages as they used to appear.,3,[],0.15714285714285714,0.21428571428571427,pos,0
2015-03-12,What Net Neutrality Rules Say,Excerpts from and analysis of rules and explanations released by the Federal Communications Commission regarding an Open Internet.,3,['ORG'],0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-03-14,"For Tech Titans, Sharing Has Its Limits",Lesser and major luminaries in the tech world are demanding that contractors and tradesmen working on their homes sign nondisclosure agreements.,3,[],0.03125,0.5,pos,0
2015-03-16,Uber’s Chief Financial Officer to Leave Company,"Brent Callinicos, the chief financial officer of Uber, plans to leave the ride-sharing company, in what will be one of the highest-level departures yet for the six-year-old start-up.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-17,General Motors’ Stock Buyback Follows a Worrying Trend,The automaker gave in to the demands of activist shareholders looking for a quick return at the expense of the harder work of building value.,1,[],0.11666666666666665,0.25,pos,0
2015-03-17,Recent Commercial Transactions,"Notable properties that have been recently listed for sale, sold or leased in New York City.",1,['GPE'],0.21212121212121213,0.40151515151515155,pos,1
2015-03-17,Orange Seeks Foreign Partner for Video Site Dailymotion,Orange’s chief executive discusses the non-French future of the video site Dailymotion.,0,"['ORG', 'NORP', 'ORG']",0.0,0.125,neu,0
2015-03-17,Demise of Gigaom Doesn’t Faze Its Rivals,"When the technology news site ceased publishing, it seemed like a cautionary tale for a new gilded age, but insiders say it faced its own special problems.",1,[],0.3645021645021645,0.6753246753246754,pos,0
2015-03-18,"Suddenly, Plenty of Options for Cord Cutters","Here are some prominent services offering live TV, à la carte networks and other on-demand streaming options in the United States.",2,['GPE'],0.17045454545454544,0.625,pos,1
2015-03-18,Video Feature: Design Gains Importance as Devices Get More Personal,"Experts say it’s not enough for a smartphone or other gadget to have all the software bells and whistles, it must also look and feel good.",3,[],0.19166666666666665,0.4916666666666667,pos,0
2015-03-18,Microsoft Backs Further Away From Selling Software,"Microsoft’s move to make Windows 10 upgrades free in China echoes a shift at the company and the software industry’s around the world. The days of charging customers for an operating system are slowly coming to an end, piece by piece.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'DATE']",0.04999999999999999,0.6,pos,1
2015-03-19,Elon Musk Says Self-Driving Tesla Cars Will Be in the U.S. by Summer,The automaker’s chief executive says a software update will allow the Model S to navigate highways without the driver’s touching the wheel or pedals. But is it legal?,0,['FAC'],0.35,0.35,pos,1
2015-03-19,Google and Intel to Team Up with TAG Heuer on a Luxury Smartwatch,"A new generation of luxury smartwatches, essentially tiny computers meant to be fashion statements, is beginning to take shape.",1,[],0.06818181818181818,0.4772727272727273,pos,0
2015-03-19,"Take Google to Court, Staff Report Urged F.T.C.",An internal Federal Trade Commission report recommended that the agency take action against Google for anticompetitive practices. The F.T.C. voted not to bring charges.,2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.05,0.05,pos,1
2015-03-20,European Lawmaker Pushes Europe to Take Stronger Stance on Google,"The antitrust case against Google in Europe has already gained more traction than in the United States. But like their American counterparts, competition officials at the European Commission in Brussels have been loath to bring formal charges against such a successful and powerful company.",0,"['ORG', 'LOC', 'GPE', 'NORP', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.25833333333333336,0.4916666666666667,pos,1
2015-03-20,Turning Off the Android Texting Nanny,Some people would rather do without the word suggestions the software makes as they type a message.,0,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-20,A Real-Time Peek at Traffic to U.S. Government Websites,"This week, the federal government unveiled a new tool that makes public the user analytics for many government websites.",1,['DATE'],0.21212121212121213,0.34040404040404043,pos,1
2015-03-23,"Square Opens Square Cash App to Businesses, for a Fee",Square is bringing peer-to-peer payments to businesses and trying to make money on the venture.,0,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-23,Restoring the iCloud Drive Icon,"With a few steps, the icon — and any other deleted icon on a Mac — can be brought back. Also, why Windows sometimes must restart when updating.",2,['PERSON'],-0.10833333333333334,0.15833333333333333,neg,1
2015-03-23,Microsoft Partners With Android Makers in Its Latest Mobile Push,"Microsoft is serious about making its most lucrative business, Office, relevant for mobile users. What is less clear is how much money it will be able to make from them.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.17142857142857143,0.4773809523809524,pos,1
2015-03-23,Google Fiber Plans Experiment With Targeted Ads for Television,"While Google Fiber is growing fast, it is still minuscule compared with its traditional rivals. But it shows the potential for delivering specific kinds of ads to local markets.",0,['ORG'],0.04,0.495,pos,1
2015-03-24,Google Hires Finance Chief Ruth Porat From Morgan Stanley,"Ms. Porat, who has been Morgan Stanley’s chief financial officer since 2010, will become one of the most powerful women in Silicon Valley.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'LOC']",0.26666666666666666,0.5,pos,1
2015-03-24,Slack Said to Be in Talks to Raise Money at More Than $2 Billion Valuation,"The talks come just four months after Slack, which is run by the entrepreneur Stewart Butterfield, raised $120 million at a valuation of more than $1 billion.",2,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'MONEY', 'MONEY']",0.5,0.5,pos,1
2015-03-24,Google Should Feel Lucky in Its Finance Chief Hire,"The challenge for both Wall Street and Silicon Valley is to create more women like Ruth Porat, with financial, tech and government know-how.",0,"['LOC', 'PERSON']",0.25,0.25,pos,1
2015-03-24,YouTube’s ‘Sunshine Girl’ Comes to Print,"Paige McKenzie, known for her mockumentary web series “The Haunting of Sunshine Girl,” is trying to extend her brand with a series of young adult novels.",3,"['PERSON', 'WORK_OF_ART']",0.1,0.35,pos,1
2015-03-24,Wall St. Stars Join Silicon Valley Gold Rush,"Ruth Porat, Morgan Stanley’s chief financial officer, is leaving for Google in the most visible example yet of the flow of talent from Wall Street to Silicon Valley.",0,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.25,0.25,pos,1
2015-03-25,Daily Report: Trying to Sway the Jury in Kleiner Perkins Discrimination Trial,"In closing arguments on Tuesday, top litigators from both sides presented their cases in the gender discrimination trial against Kleiner Perkins.",0,"['DATE', 'PERSON']",0.5,0.5,pos,1
2015-03-25,Facebook Opens Messenger for App Developers,"The social media giant has ambitious plans for its messaging service, including linking business to its user base.",2,[],-0.12916666666666668,0.7041666666666666,neg,0
2015-03-25,Parrying the Latest Predictions of Facebook’s Demise,A theory making the rounds in Silicon Valley warns that Facebook relies too heavily on app ads from start-ups inflated by venture capital. But the threat is overblown.,0,['LOC'],-0.2,0.5,neg,1
2015-03-25,F.T.C. Addresses Its Choice Not to Sue Google,The agency issued a rare statement defending its choice not to take legal action after investigating Google for anticompetitive behavior in 2011 and 2012.,3,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE']",0.19999999999999998,0.4000000000000001,pos,1
2015-03-26,Facebook’s Yann LeCun Discusses Digital Companions and Artificial Intelligence (and Emotions),"The head of Facebook’s Artificial Intelligence Lab foresees a day when we all have artificial helpers that understand us, all of the information in the world, and what we need to know next.",3,['ORG'],-0.39999999999999997,0.6666666666666666,neg,1
2015-03-26,"New Google C.F.O. Gets $70 Million Pay Package (and $7,500 to Move)",Google’s new financial chief will join the search giant in May after a long career at Morgan Stanley.,1,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG']",0.021590909090909088,0.4636363636363636,pos,1
2015-03-27,"In Silicon Valley, Auto Racing Becomes a Favorite Hobby for Tech Elites",A small but growing group of mostly men gather to drive fast and network with clients and others in the tech industry.,2,[],0.15,0.5,pos,0
2015-03-27,Cleaning Out Gmail,"Messages moved to Trash must be manually deleted to regain space immediately. Also, how to convert audiobook CDs for the iPhone.",3,['ORG'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-27,Google and Johnson & Johnson Team for Robotic Surgery Projects,Google and Johnson & Johnson announced a partnership to develop new robot-assisted surgery technologies but offered few details.,1,"['ORG', 'ORG']",-0.03181818181818183,0.2772727272727273,neg,1
2015-03-27,Ellen Pao Loses Silicon Valley Bias Case Against Kleiner Perkins,"A jury rejected allegations of gender discrimination against the venture capital firm, after a hitch caused the judge to order further deliberations.",3,[],-0.1,0.45,neg,0
2015-03-28,"After Kleiner Trial, Expect Less Shooting From the Hip in Silicon Valley",A recurring issue was who originated investment ideas at the venture capital firm and the lack of documentation to support claims.,3,[],-0.2,0.4,neg,0
2015-03-30,The Path Toward Tomorrow’s Internet,The role of government in nurturing new technology and the rising importance of the Internet of Things were themes of a conference on the next-generation Internet.,1,[],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,0
2015-03-30,China Appears to Attack GitHub by Diverting Web Traffic,"The attack on GitHub, a code library that includes methods for viewing Internet sites blocked in China, comes as the country has increased its censorship.",2,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-03-31,IBM Scores Weather Data Deal and Starts Internet of Things Unit,IBM adds another big data source to its data analysis business in a partnership with the Weather Company.,2,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.0,0.1,neu,0
2015-03-31,"Investing Early On for Insights, Not Profits","BBVA, the global Spanish bank, has established a venture capital fund in Silicon Valley that is more interested in fruitful partnerships than profits.",3,"['ORG', 'NORP', 'LOC']",0.1875,0.25,pos,1
2015-04-01,Wall Street and Silicon Valley Form an Uneasy Alliance,"Entrepreneurs and venture capitalists have done their best to resist or reduce Wall Street’s entreaties, but it appears that a new relationship has begun to develop.",0,[],0.5681818181818181,0.37727272727272726,pos,0
2015-04-01,GoDaddy Shares Jump in Market Debut,"The shares opened at $26.15, about 30 percent above the initial public offering price of $20, a dollar more than the top end of the expected range.",1,"['MONEY', 'PERCENT', 'MONEY']",0.15,0.2611111111111111,pos,1
2015-04-01,"With Galaxy S6 and S6 Edge, Samsung Tries to Regain Its Footing",The elegant new smartphones aim to answer many criticisms leveled at Samsung’s phones but are most likely not quite enough to fix what ails the company.,1,['ORG'],0.2727272727272727,0.6590909090909091,pos,1
2015-04-01,The PayPal Mafia’s Golden Touch,Alumni from the payments company have established a reputation as the best in Silicon Valley at finding and funding the latest hot product or company.,0,['LOC'],0.5833333333333334,0.6833333333333332,pos,1
2015-04-02,European Commission Asks Companies to Go Public With Google Complaints,The move is part of an antitrust inquiry into whether the search giant has used its dominant position to give preferential treatment to its own services.,3,[],0.3,1.0,pos,0
2015-04-02,Uber Hires a Security Chief From Facebook,"Joe Sullivan, the ride-hailing company’s new chief security officer, will work in areas like securing driver data, and driver and passenger safety.",3,['PERSON'],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,1
2015-04-04,"Jay Edelson, the Class-Action Lawyer Who May Be Tech’s Least Friended Man","The class-action lawyer, who specializes in filing privacy lawsuits against technology companies, has raised the ire of Silicon Valley executives.",3,['LOC'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-06,ZenPayroll Start-Up Raises $60 Million From Group Led by Google Investment Arm,"The funding round valued the payroll processor, which was created in 2012, at $500 million.",3,"['DATE', 'MONEY']",-0.2,0.4,neg,1
2015-04-06,Weinstein Company Is Said to Be Set to Sell TV Unit to ITV Studios,"A $950 million deal would allow Bob and Harvey Weinstein to retain control, according to people briefed on the possible sale.",0,"['MONEY', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']",0.0,1.0,neu,0
2015-04-07,Consumer Groups to Ask F.T.C. to Investigate YouTube Kids App,"Close to a dozen consumer groups are asking the commission to investigate an application recently released by Google, arguing that its ads deceive children.",0,"['CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.0,0.25,neu,0
2015-04-07,"With Meld, Another Step Toward the Internet of Tasty Things","Think of Meld as a Nest thermostat for your kitchen. Both add I.Q. points to the (usually) dumb systems in peoples’ homes that control different forms of heating — Nest for the furnace, Meld for the stove.",0,"['LOC', 'ORG', 'LOC']",-0.1875,0.55,neg,1
2015-04-07,Measuring Social ‘Trust’ to Make Loans,Vouch Financial is putting a digital-age spin on the old banking concept of using social references to make lending decisions.,1,[],0.044444444444444446,0.08888888888888889,pos,0
2015-04-07,Vivendi in Talks to Buy 80% Stake in Dailymotion,"The French conglomerate is trying to revamp the fortunes of the video-sharing website, which has long struggled to live up to its early promise as the next YouTube.",0,"['NORP', 'ORG']",0.03727272727272727,0.24,pos,1
2015-04-07,HP Comes to Terms With the Cloud,"Hewlett-Packard has decided it cannot compete with the likes of Amazon and Google for one of the hottest new businesses. Instead, on the eve of its split into two companies, HP is learning about collaborative technologies, and not just for its customers.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,1
2015-04-08,Dear Diary: My Week Wearing an Apple Watch,"Spending seven days learning to use, and getting used to, the Apple Watch proved to be a mostly rewarding experience.",0,"['DATE', 'ORG']",0.5,1.0,pos,1
2015-04-08,Amazon Web Services Takes Fuller Aim at Enterprise Computing,AWS kicked off the first of 16 meetings with a daylong direct assault on the existing corporate computing business. The Seattle-based cloud giant is now offering features and services for so-called hybrid clouds.,0,"['ORDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE']",0.0875,0.43333333333333335,pos,1
2015-04-09,How to Verify if That Port Is Indeed a USB 3.0,"If you do not have the computer’s manual or specifications sheet, there are several ways to check, including looking for a blue light at the jack.",3,[],0.13333333333333333,0.26666666666666666,pos,0
2015-04-09,The Must-Attend Event for Education Technology Investors,The annual ASU+GSV Summit has become the central event for investors and companies scouting for the next big thing in ed tech — a melting pot for executives from a wide range of companies.,1,['DATE'],-0.025,0.1875,neg,1
2015-04-09,Amazon to Sell Predictions in Cloud Race Against Google and Microsoft,"Amazon Web Services, the world’s biggest cloud company, is now selling cheap data analysis and prediction. It’s likely to get baked into all kinds of applications, bringing pain to the old guard.",0,['ORG'],0.16666666666666666,0.6333333333333333,pos,1
2015-04-10,Fund-Raising May Value Spotify Above $8 Billion,"If the investment round closes, it will place Spotify firmly in the ranks of some of the most richly valued technology companies, joining the likes of Uber, Airbnb and Snapchat.",1,"['GPE', 'ORG']",0.11875,0.5125,pos,1
2015-04-12,Formal Charges May Be Next in Europe’s Google Antitrust Inquiry,"Margrethe Vestager, Europe’s antitrust regulator, is expected to change course with her predecessor and file charges that could hasten a settlement.",0,['LOC'],-0.1,0.4,neg,1
2015-04-13,Creating a Windows Recovery Drive,"For owners of computers without floppy or CD drives, they can use a pocket flash as a start-up device instead.",2,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-13,"How Europe Is Going After Apple, Google and Other U.S. Tech Giants","The biggest American tech companies face intensifying scrutiny by European regulators, with — pressure that could potentially curb their sizable profits in the region and affect how they operate around the world.",2,"['NORP', 'NORP']",0.0,0.3333333333333333,neu,0
2015-04-14,Nokia in Advanced Merger Talks With Alcatel-Lucent,"The Finnish telecommunications equipment company said it was in talks to buy Alcatel-Lucent of France, a deal that would continue the consolidation of the global industry.",1,"['NORP', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-14,"Daily Report: In Silicon Valley, Helping the Homeless With Tech","Some companies in the Bay Area turn to technology to help people who sleep on the streets, for whom a phone can be a lifeline.",1,['LOC'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-14,"AOL Unveils ONE by AOL, an Advertising Platform",The company says the platform will help brands spend their ad money to maximize the effectiveness of campaigns across various media.,0,[],0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-04-14,Google Expected to Face Antitrust Charges in Europe,"Europe’s antitrust chief is expected to accuse the search giant of using its dominant position to favor its own services, a case that could force a change in its practices.",0,['LOC'],0.16666666666666666,0.7999999999999999,pos,1
2015-04-14,The Robotics Inventors Who Are Trying to Take the ‘Hard’ Out of Hardware,"A handful of low-budget innovators are working to reinvent rigid, heavy machines and robots with materials that are soft, light, cheap and squeezable.",2,[],0.17500000000000002,0.5625,pos,0
2015-04-14,Report Questions Whether Health Apps Benefit Healthy People,"Health apps could turn healthy people into self-monitoring neurotics, according to a new article in a leading medical journal.",1,[],0.21212121212121213,0.3181818181818182,pos,0
2015-04-15,Nokia Agrees to $16.6 Billion Takeover of Alcatel-Lucent,The combined company is expected to become the world’s second-largest telecom equipment manufacturer behind Ericsson of Sweden.,3,"['ORDINAL', 'GPE']",-0.25,0.55,neg,1
2015-04-15,"Europe Challenges Google, Seeing Violations of Its Antitrust Law","The charge focuses on accusations that the company diverts traffic from its rivals to favor its own products and services, particularly websites for shopping.",0,[],0.3833333333333333,0.6666666666666666,pos,0
2015-04-15,Bits Daily Report: E.U. Antitrust Chief Formally Accuses Google of Abuse,"The charge focuses on accusations that the company diverts traffic from its rivals to favor its own products and services, particularly websites for shopping.",0,[],0.3833333333333333,0.6666666666666666,pos,0
2015-04-15,Google Accused of Cheating Competitors,"Margrethe Vestager, the European Union’s competition commissioner, accused Google of distorting Internet search results and began an antitrust investigation into its Android mobile operating system.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-15,The Danish Politician Who Accused Google of Antitrust Violations,"Margrethe Vestager, the European Union competition commissioner, has brought an assertive approach to the competition ministry since taking over last year.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.0,0.03333333333333333,neu,0
2015-04-15,Google Joins Its U.S. Peers Under Europe’s Scrutiny,"American technology companies are no strangers to antitrust challenges by European regulators, but the cost has tended to be measured in money and time, not business practices.",2,"['NORP', 'NORP']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-15,Case Against Google May Be Undercut by Rapid Changes in Technology,"As the antitrust case against Microsoft showed, the giants that look most unbeatable can falter in ways that have nothing to do with the actions of government regulators.",2,['ORG'],0.5,0.5,pos,1
2015-04-15,"Microsoft, Once an Antitrust Target, Is Now Google’s Regulatory Scold","The European Union is accusing Google of abusing its dominance, and Microsoft has links with the three initial complainants that sparked the antitrust investigation.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-16,"Daily Report: Joining American Peers, Google Gets Caught in Europe’s Cross Hairs","American technology companies are no strangers to antitrust challenges by European regulators, but the cost has tended to be measured in money and time, not business practices.",2,"['NORP', 'NORP']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-16,Cycling Start-Up Peloton Raises $30 Million,The new round of funding is the latest sign of interest in Peloton’s bikes — sleek black spinning cycles with customized tablet displays.,1,['ORG'],0.06742424242424241,0.5469696969696969,pos,1
2015-04-16,A Yale Graduate Leaves a Trail of Ventures and Debts,"Joshua Bryce Newman seems to fit the part of the young, successful entrepreneur. But the lawsuits filed against him paint a different picture.",0,['PERSON'],0.3125,0.5875,pos,1
2015-04-16,Former JPMorgan Chase Broker Charged in $20 Million Fraud,Michael J. Oppenheim is accused of embezzling money from his clients over the last four years.,0,"['PERSON', 'DATE']",0.0,0.06666666666666667,neu,0
2015-04-17,"Taking a Facebook Break, Temporarily or for Good","The site lets users deactivate their accounts and then return with all content intact. Permanently deleting an account wipes it, and all the content, out.",0,[],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-19,IBM Venture With China Stirs Concerns,"IBM’s partnership with Teamsun, a Beijing company, to provide key technologies is similar to ones it has made elsewhere, but it has collided with political and trade issues.",0,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE']",0.0,0.5,neu,0
2015-04-19,"Box, Provider of Cloud-Computing Services, Faces Make-or-Break Moment",Box is nearing a point other young companies are also likely to face: Find a way to cut losses and stay ahead of deep-pocketed competition or disappear.,2,[],-0.008333333333333331,0.5916666666666667,neg,0
2015-04-20,Morgan Stanley Profit Jumps on Higher Trading Revenue,The Wall Street bank was helped by the same active trading conditions that have helped its competitors.,0,[],-0.06666666666666667,0.3625,neg,0
2015-04-20,Europe Is Expected to Bring Antitrust Charges Against Gazprom,"Gazprom is expected to be accused of abusing its dominance in natural gas markets, and countries like Lithuania and the United States have been pushing for a crackdown.",0,"['GPE', 'GPE']",0.0,0.4,neu,0
2015-04-22,Working With Old Office Files on a New Mac OS,"Even with an upgrade, there are several ways to work with Microsoft Office files. Also, backing up data on an Amazon Fire tablet.",3,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-22,Backers Say USB-C Is the Cable of the Future,"A successor to the USB connector, it is smaller to work with thinner devices, and it is designed to handle high speeds for data transfers and lots of power.",3,['ORG'],0.08,0.52,pos,1
2015-04-22,Google Introduces Wireless Service Called Project Fi,"The service aims to blend several communication tools — cellular calls, online calls like Skype — into a single phone number and service.",2,['ORG'],-0.03571428571428571,0.10714285714285714,neg,1
2015-04-22,"Facebook’s Growth Slows Slightly, but Mobile Shift Intensifies",The company said that three-quarters of its first-quarter ad revenue and most of its visitors came from mobile devices.,1,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE']",0.5,0.5,pos,1
2015-04-22,Homes Try to Reach Smart Switch,"As technology advances, smart homes face challenges of adoption and economics while the impact on energy consumption remains uncertain.",2,[],0.21428571428571427,0.6428571428571429,pos,0
2015-04-22,"Box Opens Tools for Developers, Suggesting the Future of Business Software",Box was initially known as a way to store digital content cheaply online. No more.,1,[],0.037500000000000006,0.3,pos,0
2015-04-23,"With Mi 4i Smartphone, Xiaomi Turns to India","With the growth of China’s smartphone market slowing, turning to India is an obvious next stop for a company like Xiaomi.",1,"['GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.0,0.25,neu,0
2015-04-23,Family Office of Google’s Eric Schmidt Buys Stake in Hedge Fund D.E. Shaw,The 20 percent stake of the $36 billion hedge fund is one of the last vestiges of the bankrupt Lehman Brothers.,0,"['PERCENT', 'MONEY', 'ORG']",0.0,0.06666666666666667,neu,0
2015-04-23,"With Amazon Atop the Cloud, Big Tech Rivals Are Giving Chase","Amazon said in its first-quarter earnings report that its cloud division, Amazon Web Services, had revenue of $1.57 billion and operating income of $265 million.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'MONEY', 'MONEY']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-24,"Daily Report: Amazon Dominates Cloud Computing, but Tech Giants Are in Pursuit","Amazon said in its first-quarter earnings report that its cloud division, Amazon Web Services, had revenue of $1.57 billion and operating income of $265 million.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'MONEY', 'MONEY']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-24,Google’s Eric Schmidt Plays the Adult in D.E. Shaw Investment,"The Google executive chairman makes a big bet that is far afield from the frivolity of, say, a sports team investment like Steve Ballmer’s.",0,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.05,0.55,pos,1
2015-04-25,‘Google Adventurer’ Dies on Mt. Everest,Dan Fredinburg helped Google’s Street View project document many of the world’s most majestic peaks before his death in Nepal in an earthquake-related avalanche.,3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.5,0.5,pos,1
2015-04-26,Packed Field Stokes Competition for Digital Ad Dollars,"Heavyweights like AOL, Google and Yahoo will vie with upstarts like Refinery29 and Vice in an increasingly crowded two-week frenzy to secure upfront advertising commitments.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'DATE']",0.4,0.6,pos,1
2015-04-26,"Fashion Is Trending, in Google Searches",What’s in or out: an analysis of six billion Google searches shows how clothing styles spread from state to state.,2,"['CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-26,"The Latest Fashion, Trending on Google",The search giant is scanning its wealth of user-generated data for signs of fashion trends as it works to enhance its sales of online advertisements.,2,[],0.0,1.0,neu,0
2015-04-27,"Daily Report: The Latest Fashion, Trending on Google",Google is scanning its wealth of user-generated data for signs of fashion trends as it works to enhance its sales of online advertisements.,2,['ORG'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-27,Facebook Adds Free Video Calls to Messenger App,"The social networking company has allowed free voice calls on its Messenger app for about two years, but now it is adding video calling, matching a key feature offered by rivals.",1,"['PRODUCT', 'DATE']",0.14444444444444446,0.6222222222222222,pos,1
2015-04-27,"Apple’s Earnings Surge, as iPhone Sales Jump and China Business Rises","More than one-quarter of the company’s revenue last quarter came from China, which is becoming an increasingly vital part of Apple’s business.",1,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.2625,0.4541666666666667,pos,1
2015-04-27,"Twitter’s Dick Costolo Delivers on Change, but the Right Mix Remains Elusive",Twitter has introduced new features but continues to wrestle with an old problem: how to help new users enjoy the best of the service.,0,['PERSON'],0.35454545454545455,0.38181818181818183,pos,1
2015-04-28,Fashion Site Raises Funds to Speed Its Global Growth,"The fashion and lifestyle media company is now valued at about $300 million, according to a person with knowledge of the deal.",0,['MONEY'],0.0,0.0,neu,0
2015-04-29,Google Tripled Spending on Lobbying in Brussels Last Year,"The company multiplied its spending by three from 2010 to 2013, and again in 2014, spending at least $4.2 million and as much as $4.8 million last year, according to its latest disclosure report.",0,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'MONEY', 'MONEY', 'DATE']",0.1,0.3916666666666667,pos,1
2015-04-29,Microsoft Takes Steps to Close Its App Gap on Mobile Devices,Microsoft has steadily lost influence in the technology industry as software developers gravitated to mobile technologies like Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS.,2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.16666666666666666,0.5,pos,1
2015-04-29,Twitter’s Costolo on Earnings,"CNBC interviews Dick Costolo, chief of Twitter, who discusses the company’s earnings, which were released early and missed expectations, as well as Twitter’s new ad partnership with Google.",1,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.11818181818181818,0.37727272727272726,pos,1
2015-04-29,"A Founder of Secret, the Anonymous Social App, Is Shutting It Down",Secret’s rapid rise and fall illustrates the flash-in-the-pan nature of Silicon Valley’s current technology boom.,2,['LOC'],-0.2,0.55,neg,1
2015-04-29,Twitter Troubles Lie in Marketers’ Reluctance to Buy New Kind of Ad,Twitter’s shares have been punished since it reported its earnings because advertisers and investors are having trouble figuring it out.,3,['PERSON'],-0.2,0.2,neg,1
2015-04-30,"Microsoft (Yes, Microsoft) Has a Far-Out Vision","The reshaped Microsoft that Satya Nadella, the new chief executive, envisions has fewer internal fiefs and is more willing to favor big bets on new technologies over protecting legacy cash cows.",1,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.17045454545454544,0.3765151515151515,pos,1
2015-04-30,Social Media Punished as Results Fall Short,The performances illustrate the way investors are questioning whether social media companies can keep their growth rates vigorous enough to justify their valuations.,0,[],0.016666666666666666,0.2833333333333333,pos,0
2015-05-01,What an Android Update May Get You,"An Android update may be particularly helpful to users of Nexus 7 tablets, and resources on the web can give users an idea of what to expect.",3,"['GPE', 'CARDINAL']",0.16666666666666666,0.3333333333333333,pos,1
2015-05-01,The Rise of Emoji on Instagram Is Causing Language Repercussions,The use of emoji — the collection of happy faces and other images that can be used to communicate feelings and sentiments — has become so pervasive on Instagram that the use of Internet slang formed from letters has decreased.,2,['ORG'],0.09166666666666667,0.6916666666666668,pos,1
