0,2015-10-26,Daily Report: Facebook Goes to India … Again,"Facebook’s Internet.org effort has been criticized as an attempt to promote the company’s own interests. This week, Mark Zuckerberg, the social media giant’s chief executive, is expected to discuss the project during a visit to New Delhi.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'PERSON', 'GPE']",0.1339393939393939,0.5842424242424242,pos,0
1,2017-12-28,Moving Your Number to Google Voice,"Google’s telephony service can give you a unified number and with a little extra work, you may be able to use your original landline digits.",1,['ORG'],0.171875,0.49375,pos,0
2,2018-03-31,"Hey, Alexa, What Can You Hear? And What Will You Do With It?","Amazon and Google have filed patent applications, many still under consideration, that outline how digital assistants can monitor more of what users say and do.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.3333333333333333,0.3333333333333333,pos,0
3,2016-06-27,Amazon Unveils Online Education Service for Teachers,"The new Amazon site will offer free lesson plans, teaching modules and other digital resources for educators.",3,['ORG'],0.1028409090909091,0.4073863636363636,pos,0
4,2018-08-28,NYT: Weekend Business for 02/27/2009,This week: Jeff Sommer and David Leonhardt on the Obama administration’s vision for the economy; Gretchen Morgenson on the effect of sloppy bookkeeping on foreclosure proceedings; and Tim O’Brien and Laura Holson on Google’s design guru.,1,"['DATE', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.4166666666666667,0.75,neg,0
5,2022-03-15,Prepare for Interest Rate Liftoff,How high will the Fed go?,0,['ORG'],0.16,0.5399999999999999,pos,0
6,2021-07-02,Amazon After Bezos,The founder of the e-commerce giant steps down as C.E.O. in two days. Then what?,0,['DATE'],-0.0777777777777777,0.6444444444444445,neg,0
7,2016-11-21,Fake News Onslaught Targets Pizzeria as Nest of Child-Trafficking,A Washington restaurant is reeling from menacing calls and online abuse after a fake story: that Hillary Clinton abuses children there.,2,"['GPE', 'PERSON']",-0.75,1.0,neg,0
8,2021-06-15,"Biden Names Lina Khan, a Big-Tech Critic, as F.T.C. Chair","Ms. Khan, who first attracted notice as a critic of Amazon, was confirmed by the Senate as a commissioner on the agency on Tuesday.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.325,0.6666666666666666,pos,0
9,2018-08-24,The Week in Tech: Democracy Under Siege,"Microsoft busted Kremlin-linked hackers who broadened their targets in the United States. And Facebook, YouTube and others found new influence campaigns originating from Russia and Iran.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
10,2019-05-04,"Facebook Faces a Big Penalty, but Regulators Are Split Over How Big",The F.T.C. chairman seems to have the votes to approve a settlement. One of the biggest issues has been whether to hold Mark Zuckerberg liable for future violations.,2,"['PRODUCT', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON']",-0.05,0.3125,neg,0
11,2016-12-11,Google Effect Rubs Off on Schools in One Rural Oklahoma Town,A $2.5 billion data center transforms the learning experiences of a rural community’s students in a state where schools are struggling.,2,['MONEY'],-0.05,0.05,neg,0
12,2017-06-20,What to Do When Chrome Wants to Update — but Can’t,"If Google’s browser trips up trying to install a new version, check your system and settings before reinstalling the software.",3,['ORG'],0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
13,2016-02-20,Apple Sees Value in Its Stand to Protect Security,Apple’s refusal to help the F.B.I. break into its secure mobile operating system may benefit its brand in the rest of the world.,1,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.4,0.6,pos,0
14,2018-10-25,Apple News’s Radical Approach: Humans Over Machines,"While Google, Facebook and Twitter face scrutiny for spreading misinformation, Apple has avoided scandal by using people to pick what news to show. Is that good for news outlets?",2,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'PRODUCT', 'ORG']",0.7,0.6000000000000001,pos,0
15,2015-07-31,"Yahoo Buys Polyvore, a Site Focused on Shopping","Yahoo has acquired Polyvore, a social shopping site that lets users pick and share clothing ensembles — and purchase all items shown.",0,['ORG'],0.0333333333333333,0.0666666666666666,pos,0
16,2015-03-24,Wall St. Stars Join Silicon Valley Gold Rush,"Ruth Porat, Morgan Stanley’s chief financial officer, is leaving for Google in the most visible example yet of the flow of talent from Wall Street to Silicon Valley.",0,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.25,0.25,pos,0
17,2018-02-16,How Good Were the Paydays for Bank Chiefs … and Shareholders?: DealBook Briefing,"Citigroup’s C.E.O. enjoyed a big bump in take-home pay, as did Goldman’s chief. Were those merited?",3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.25,0.3999999999999999,pos,0
18,2022-05-19,"Buffalo gunman’s video is surfacing on Facebook, sometimes with ads beside it.","The company relies on automated systems to spot violent content, but people are still uploading and sharing the Buffalo video.",3,['GPE'],-0.8,1.0,neg,0
19,2017-02-28,"Morning Agenda: Ethereum, Uber and Money Management Fees","Microsoft, JPMorgan Chase and other corporate giants are joining forces to create a computing system based on a virtual currency network, Ethereum.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.0625,0.1875,neg,1
20,2021-02-10,Woman Accused of Defaming Dozens Online Is Arrested,"Nadire Atas trashed the reputations of people she saw as enemies, and their relatives. On Tuesday, she was charged by the Toronto police with harassment and other offenses.",0,"['PERSON', 'DATE', 'GPE']",-0.125,0.375,neg,0
21,2015-08-04,Netflix Offers Expanded Maternity and Paternity Leave,The company said it was offering unlimited leave for new mothers and fathers for one year after the birth or adoption of a child.,3,['DATE'],0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
22,2019-06-03,DealBook Briefing: Big Tech’s Antitrust Reckoning Is Coming,Google and Amazon have thrived as regulators largely kept their distance. Moves by the Justice Department and the F.T.C. suggest that may be changing.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.2142857142857142,0.4285714285714285,pos,0
23,2018-10-02,Why You Shouldn’t Use Facebook to Log In to Other Sites,Facebook offered a convenient and secure way to sign up for online services. A major hack shows it failed at its one job.,2,['CARDINAL'],-0.0124999999999999,0.4666666666666667,neg,0
24,2015-01-19,Daily Report: Microsoft Looks to Windows 10 for a Boost in Mobile,Microsoft’s new operating system is the biggest effort yet by Satya Nadella to save the company’s moribund smartphone business.,0,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
25,2020-10-09,"Apple Does Not Need to Return Fortnite to App Store, Judge Rules","Fortnite’s parent company, Epic Games, had broken its contract with Apple, a federal judge found. The case goes to trial next year.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']",-0.1,0.2666666666666666,neg,0
26,2015-01-14,"In Detroit, Google Makes a Case for Driverless Cars","Google hopes to have fully autonomous vehicles on the road by 2020, taking the driver out of the equation and handing the virtual wheel to software.",3,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.4,0.7,pos,0
27,2018-07-20,"Trying to Flip the House, ZIP Code by ZIP Code","Swing Left, a Democratic political action committee founded after the 2016 election by three relative novices, resembles a Silicon Valley start-up more than a traditional political organization.",0,"['NORP', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'LOC']",0.0857142857142857,0.2214285714285714,pos,0
28,2021-12-30,The Metaverse’s Dark Side: Here Come Harassment and Assaults,"As Meta and other companies bet big on an immersive digital world, questions about its harms are rising.",1,['PERSON'],-0.0416666666666666,0.1583333333333333,neg,0
29,2021-11-18,Judge Tries to Block New York Times’s Coverage of Project Veritas,"The state court order, which The Times said it would immediately oppose, raised concerns from First Amendment advocates.",3,"['ORG', 'LAW']",0.25,0.3333333333333333,pos,0
30,2017-08-18,Judge Says Waymo Can Tell Jurors That Uber Withheld Evidence,A new ruling in a bitter legal battle over the future of driverless car technology could hurt Uber when the case goes to trial.,1,['PERSON'],0.059090909090909,0.3198863636363636,pos,0
31,2016-03-14,"As a Data Deluge Grows, Companies Rethink Storage","At Pure Storage, a device introduced on Monday holds five times as much data as a conventional unit.",3,"['FAC', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.0904761904761904,0.3523809523809524,pos,0
32,2017-05-17,Movers: Stocks Slide,We’re following major developments in the markets throughout the day. Check here for the latest updates.,0,['DATE'],0.1875,0.5,pos,0
33,2016-03-20,Amazon Leans on Government in Its Quest to Be a Delivery Powerhouse,"New uses for commercial drones, 33-foot trucks, improved roads and bridges: Amazon and its lobbyists urge officials to support expansion efforts.",0,"['QUANTITY', 'ORG']",0.0681818181818181,0.2272727272727272,pos,0
34,2015-09-10,Answers to Questions About Apple’s New Products,Here are our responses to reader queries about the new Apple devices introduced at a company event on Wednesday.,0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
35,2016-03-06,"The Right Wing’s Casting Agency, and Its Agent","As executive director of Talent Market, Claire Kittle Dixon uses her vast connections to fill posts for prominent and obscure conservative organizations.",1,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.25,1.0,pos,0
36,2021-09-14,"America’s Grand Reopening, Postponed","New York Times photographers around the United States spent the past six months documenting the coronavirus economy. As its path veered, so did our sense of where the finish line was.",0,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'DATE']",-0.0712121212121212,0.2681818181818182,neg,0
37,2015-10-06,"Silicon Valley Investment Funds Still Lack Diversity, Study Shows",The new study highlights the large gap between Silicon Valley’s diversity ambitions and reality.,0,['LOC'],0.1753246753246753,0.4415584415584415,pos,0
38,2015-01-25,Verizon’s Mobile ‘Supercookies’ Seen as Threat to Privacy,"Advertisers, and possibly other third parties, are finding ways to exploit a hidden tracking mechanism that Verizon Wireless users cannot delete.",3,"['ORDINAL', 'ORG']",-0.0972222222222222,0.236111111111111,neg,0
40,2018-05-07,"After Fatal Uber Crash, a Self-Driving Start-Up Moves Forward",Drive.ai said it would start a taxi service in Texas. It was the first new rollout of autonomous cars in the United States since one operated by Uber killed a pedestrian in March.,2,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORDINAL', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'DATE']",0.1465909090909091,0.3719696969696969,pos,0
41,2018-03-05,Fed Considers ‘Material Changes’ to Volcker Rule: DealBook Briefing,The Federal Reserve is in the process of working with other regulatory agencies to make “material changes” to the rule.,2,['ORG'],-0.125,0.375,neg,0
42,2018-03-23,Uber’s Self-Driving Cars Were Struggling Before Arizona Crash,"Company documents obtained by The New York Times show Uber was becoming more aggressive with its autonomous car research, even as the technology faltered.",3,['ORG'],0.3715909090909091,0.6261363636363637,pos,0
43,2015-12-17,Daily Report: Google’s Lousy Time at the D.M.V.,"Proposed rules in California would require self-driving cars to have a licensed driver ready to take over the wheel. There’s one problem: Google’s autonomous vehicle prototypes don’t have steering wheels — with good reason, the company says.",1,"['GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.4333333333333333,0.6,pos,0
44,2015-06-11,Daily Report: Google Sets Its Sights on Improving City Life,"Google’s new venture, Sidewalk Labs, will pursue technologies to cut pollution, curb energy use, streamline transportation and reduce the cost of urban living.",0,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.0681818181818181,0.2272727272727272,pos,0
45,2020-02-22,"Digital Edits, a Paid Army: Bloomberg Is ‘Destroying Norms’ on Social Media",His campaign is testing the boundaries of what platforms like Twitter and Facebook allow in politics. They’re having trouble coming up with an answer.,3,"['PERSON', 'PERSON']",-0.2,0.2,neg,1
46,2016-10-31,"Morning Agenda: Competition Heats Up, the Fight Over Global Trade","The stakes are rising for antitrust cases, especially in Europe, where Margrethe Vestager, the European competition chief, has picked some prominent fights.",1,"['LOC', 'NORP']",0.1666666666666666,0.6666666666666666,pos,0
47,2017-01-08,Detroit Auto Show Reveals a Google-Designed Van That Could Steer the Industry,"The minivan, built by Fiat Chrysler with self-driving sensors from Waymo, is the first heavyweight collaboration between a major automaker and one of Silicon Valley’s elite.",2,"['ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'ORDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'LOC']",0.15625,0.4166666666666666,pos,0
48,2022-01-12,The Newest Corporate Perk,Need a Covid rapid test? One solution is to work for the right big company.,3,"['NORP', 'CARDINAL']",0.1428571428571428,0.3178571428571428,pos,0
49,2016-10-12,Snap Is Said to Pick Bankers for an I.P.O.,Morgan Stanley and Goldman Sachs would help lead the most eagerly awaited new internet stock offering since Twitter.,0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.3181818181818182,0.4772727272727273,pos,0
50,2015-10-08,Twitter Renews Efforts to Court Advertisers,"The service’s biggest advantage for advertisers is that it has become the public square where people gather to discuss live events, giving advertisers a rapt audience.",2,['PERSON'],0.0681818181818181,0.2833333333333333,pos,0
51,2016-10-11,Twitter’s Troubles and Snap’s Appeal: It’s All About the Mojo,"In Silicon Valley, momentum means everything, the Deal Professor writes. Twitter appears to have little, while Snap, formerly Snapchat, has plenty, but faces risks of its own.",2,"['LOC', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.1374999999999999,0.5,pos,1
52,2018-07-13,How to Go Back to the Old Gmail,"Google’s overhaul for the web may not be everyone’s cup of tea, but you can return to the previous version for a while longer.",3,['ORG'],-0.1666666666666666,0.1666666666666666,neg,0
53,2016-07-15,"Apple, in Seeming Jab at Spotify, Proposes Simpler Songwriting Royalties",Apple proposed that streaming services pay 9.1 cents for every 100 plays of a song. That would significantly increase what its rival Spotify pays.,3,"['ORG', 'MONEY', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE']",0.375,0.875,pos,0
54,2015-11-27,Black Friday Shopping Shifts Online as Stores See Less Foot Traffic,"Total online sales are expected to generate $2.6 billion on Black Friday, a 14 percent increase compared to the same day last year.",0,"['MONEY', 'EVENT', 'PERCENT', 'DATE']",-0.0533333333333333,0.355,neg,0
55,2017-08-03,China’s Internet Censors Play a Tougher Game of Cat and Mouse,"New efforts to tighten online controls show a shift in the way Beijing regulates content, with potential implications for researchers and businesses.",0,['GPE'],0.0681818181818181,0.7272727272727273,pos,0
56,2022-06-17,Tracking Fear on Wall Street,"Plus, with Revlon’s bankruptcy, Wall Street bankers get ready for a wave of distressed situations.",0,['ORG'],0.2,0.5,pos,0
57,2022-06-30,"Post-Roe, Her Facebook Group Went Viral","Veronica Risinger made a little online spot for neighbors to share information on abortion. Then 30,000 people joined.",1,"['PERSON', 'CARDINAL']",-0.1875,0.5,neg,0
58,2021-03-05,The Pandemic Needs Its Smokey Bear,"Instead it has a nearly empty hotel for Covid patients in London, celebrities in masks — and no public health message that has broken through.",1,"['PERSON', 'GPE']",-0.1666666666666666,0.3222222222222222,neg,0
59,2020-05-08,White-Collar Companies Race to Be Last to Return to the Office,"Google, Facebook, Amazon, Capital One and others are extending work-from-home policies to September and sometimes far beyond.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.1,1.0,pos,0
60,2020-11-12,2020’s Hot Gadget Is the Computer,"Computers are no longer boring. This year, they’re everything.",1,['DATE'],-1.0,1.0,neg,0
61,2017-08-31,Morning Agenda: An Uber I.P.O.? It’ll Be Awhile.,"Uber’s new chief executive, Dara Khosrowshahi, said that an initial public offering wouldn’t come until 2019 at the earliest.",1,"['PERSON', 'DATE']",0.0454545454545454,0.1737373737373737,pos,0
62,2019-07-31,Jeffrey Epstein Hoped to Seed Human Race With His DNA,"Mr. Epstein, the accused sex trafficker, was fascinated by eugenics. He told scientists and others of his vision of using his New Mexico ranch to impregnate women.",0,"['PERSON', 'GPE']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,1
63,2022-03-18,"As Offices Open and Mask Mandates Drop, Some Anxieties Set In","Using local guidelines, many companies are loosening Covid safety rules, leaving workers to navigate masking and social distancing on their own.",1,['PERSON'],0.2833333333333333,0.3916666666666666,pos,0
64,2022-06-15,Tesla Autopilot and Other Driver-Assist Systems Linked to Hundreds of Crashes,The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration released data on 10 months of crashes involving cars with automated components. A few were fatal.,2,"['ORG', 'DATE']",-0.2,0.1,neg,0
65,2017-03-08,White House Echoes Tech: ‘Move Fast and Break Things’,"Defying political norms, President Trump has embraced the philosophy of disruption and management styles that have powered successful start-ups.",1,['PERSON'],0.375,0.525,pos,0
66,2016-11-01,New Research Center to Explore Ethics of Artificial Intelligence,"The president of Carnegie Mellon University, which will establish the center, said injecting ethical discussions into A.I. is necessary as the technology advances.",1,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.0333333333333333,0.5666666666666667,pos,1
67,2017-05-23,Google’s AlphaGo Defeats Chinese Go Master in Win for A.I.,The software’s victory over the world’s best player of the Chinese game demonstrates how artificial intelligence can increasingly outperform humans at complex tasks.,3,['NORP'],-0.06,0.42,neg,0
68,2016-08-04,Finding Alternatives to Microsoft Excel,"Many other programs and online software services can open, view and even edit spreadsheets created by Microsoft’s flagship business application.",3,['ORG'],0.125,0.4583333333333333,pos,0
69,2016-02-10,Florist-Friendly Marketplaces Help Local Flower Shops Hang On,"National merchants like 1-800-Flowers and FTD.com take more than 25 percent of a sale, squeezing local florists. But start-ups are challenging that model.",1,"['CARDINAL', 'PERCENT']",0.3333333333333333,0.5,pos,0
70,2018-03-14,"In Hollywood, Cutting the Cord and Other Disruptions","Brooks Barnes, who covers Hollywood for The New York Times, discussed how the tsunami of technology has forced the entertainment industry to change.",3,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']",-0.0818181818181818,0.3272727272727272,neg,0
71,2016-12-14,"‘I’m Here to Help,’ Trump Tells Tech Executives at Meeting","The president-elect met with Jeff Bezos of Amazon and Timothy D. Cook of Apple, among other tech leaders, in a surprisingly genial gathering.",1,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.2875,0.4375,pos,0
72,2016-10-17,"IBM Is Counting on Its Bet on Watson, and Paying Big Money for It","The years of investment in its artificial intelligence effort, IBM executives say, are increasingly turning into moneymaking opportunities in sizable markets like health care and manufacturing.",0,"['DATE', 'ORG']",-0.6,1.0,neg,0
73,2017-12-14,Trump Congratulated Murdoch on the Disney Deal: DealBook Briefing,"While the Trump administration has moved to block one media deal, the president offered support to another — and said that it would be a “great thing” for jobs.",2,"['ORG', 'CARDINAL']",0.8,0.75,pos,0
74,2016-09-02,Alphabet Ends Effort to Create Modular Smartphone,The decision to shelve Project Ara comes after the company announced plans in May to release an early version of the product for developers.,3,"['PERSON', 'DATE']",0.1,0.3,pos,0
75,2019-10-26,Symbol of ’80s Greed Stands to Profit From Trump Tax Break for Poor Areas,"The financier Michael Milken is a major investor in a property that became eligible for a federal tax break — after his longtime friend, Steven Mnuchin, intervened.",2,"['PERSON', 'PERSON']",0.0625,0.5,pos,0
76,2022-03-02,Set Your Schedule in Your Smartphone’s Free Calendar,"As daily life feels more familiar, apps from Apple and Google can keep you organized and get you to your in-person events on time.",3,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.2916666666666667,0.3333333333333333,pos,0
77,2022-08-24,"Amazon says it will shut down Amazon Care, its primary and urgent health care business.","Last month, the company said it planned to acquire One Medical, a much larger competitor to its own health care business.",0,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.15,0.3916666666666666,pos,0
78,2018-05-16,"A Battle for Control of CBS, With Far-Reaching Consequences","No matter who wins in the fight over the proposed reunion of CBS and Viacom, both companies will be profoundly affected and the media landscape will be transformed.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.1916666666666666,0.6,pos,0
79,2017-06-06,Apple Needs to Reinvent Itself. It Just Might Be Doing So.,"With the announcement of HomePod, a new home assistant, the company seems to be finally embracing the technologies it has long put on the back burner.",0,['ORG'],0.021590909090909,0.4636363636363636,pos,0
80,2015-05-07,"Google, Dominant in Search, Tries Disruptor Role in Wireless and Broadband",Google’s foray into cellular and broadband is a strategic move aimed at enhancing its position in search and exploiting new profit opportunities.,0,['ORG'],0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
81,2015-12-03,"Number26, German Banking Start-Up, Expands Across Europe",The rise of new banking-focused start-ups like Number26 is forcing traditional players like Deutsche Bank and JPMorgan Chase to respond to people’s desire to access financial services through their smartphones.,0,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.0454545454545454,0.4015151515151515,pos,0
82,2018-03-07,How Foreign Is Broadcom? A Tale of the Tape: DealBook Briefing,National security has become a central issue in Broadcom’s bid for Qualcomm. But is Broadcom substantially a foreign company?,3,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']",-0.0625,0.1875,neg,0
83,2017-09-27,Can You Run Android on an iPad?,"If you like Android software and Apple hardware, you can usually find iPad versions of all your favorite Google apps to install.",3,"['GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.125,0.625,pos,0
84,2016-07-27,"Alexa, What Else Can You Do? Getting More From Amazon Echo","Making Amazon’s voice-activated speaker smarter is not intuitive, but with a little tinkering, consumers can expand its skills.",3,['ORG'],-0.1875,0.5,neg,0
85,2019-09-09,How Apple’s Apps Topped Rivals in the App Store It Controls,"The top results of many common searches in the company’s App Store were packed with its own apps, as concerns grow that Apple may be tipping the scales in its own favor.",3,['ORG'],0.38,0.7,pos,0
86,2016-03-08,The End of the Road for Picasa,Google is retiring the free photo-editing program and urging its users to give the newer Google Photos software a try.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.4,0.8,pos,0
87,2020-02-12,Britain to Create Regulator for Internet Content,"To push Google, Facebook and other internet giants to police their own platforms, Britain said its media watchdog would become an internet authority.",2,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE']",0.2375,0.6875,pos,0
88,2019-10-22,"China Sharpens Hacking to Hound Its Minorities, Far and Wide","New, more sophisticated attacks are targeting Uighurs’ phones — even iPhones and even abroad, security researchers say. They warn that foreigners could be next.",2,['ORG'],0.284090909090909,0.4886363636363636,pos,0
89,2019-09-08,"The Week in Business: Walmart Takes a Stand on Gun Control, and Brexit Goes Off the Rails","Plus, YouTube promises to stop collecting data from children, and Apple unveils new iPhones.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
90,2017-09-06,"Blocked in China, Facebook Is Said to Seek a Shanghai Office","The office search indicates the company is growing more positive about its prospects in mainland China, where it has been unavailable for nearly a decade.",3,"['GPE', 'DATE']",0.2757575757575757,0.4818181818181817,pos,0
91,2019-08-08,The Secret History of ‘Easter Eggs’,"Yes, Google, Tesla, Amazon and others are still hiding quirky software surprises in their products, mostly to give you a chuckle.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.25,0.75,pos,0
92,2016-05-25,"Microsoft Cutting 1,850 Jobs in Smartphone Unit","As sales dwindle, most of the reduction will come in Finland, where the mobile business bought from Nokia originated.",0,"['GPE', 'ORG']",0.5,0.5,pos,0
93,2021-04-12,Hearing Aids for the Masses,Relatively simple technology and a change in government policy could unleash more innovation for Americans who have difficulty hearing.,2,['NORP'],0.25,0.4285714285714286,pos,0
94,2018-04-02,Looming China Trade Action Divides Industry and Roils Markets,"Companies are united around the idea of addressing China’s unfair trade practices, but details of the president’s plan have set off fierce opposition.",3,['GPE'],-0.5,1.0,neg,0
95,2017-02-27,Daily Report: A New Week for Uber Dawns,"The ride-hailing giant experienced an avalanche of a bad news last week, including claims of harassment and a lawsuit.",3,['DATE'],0.025,0.6583333333333333,pos,0
96,2018-11-08,Google Overhauls Sexual Misconduct Policy After Employee Walkout,"A week after 20,000 employees around the globe staged a walkout over the handling of sexual harassment and assault cases, Google said it was altering some of its policies.",2,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.5,0.8333333333333334,pos,0
97,2019-04-22,DealBook Briefing: Tesla Wants You to Focus on Its Robo-Taxis (Not Its Finances),"The electric-car maker plans to show off its latest self-driving vehicle technology, two days before it is expected to announce another quarterly loss.",1,"['DATE', 'DATE']",0.2,0.65,pos,0
98,2017-08-16,The Technology Our Personal Finance Columnist Trusts His Money With,"The Times’s Your Money columnist on his favorite finance apps, the gadgets he would love to dream into existence and his Spotify singalong sessions.",3,['GPE'],0.5,0.8,pos,0
99,2017-10-04,Keeping Your Reading List in Sync,Microsoft Edge can keep the web pages and e-books you’ve saved up to date on your other Windows 10 devices.,1,"['ORG', 'PRODUCT']",-0.125,0.375,neg,0
100,2020-08-14,A Steal Might Actually Be a Raw Deal,"Netflix, Apple and the rest must figure out what bundles we love, and which we’ll grow to hate.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG']",-0.15,0.75,neg,0
101,2020-02-11,"F.T.C. Broadens Review of Tech Giants, Homing In on Their Deals","The agency ordered Amazon, Apple, Facebook, Alphabet and Microsoft to turn over a decade’s worth of information on small acquisitions.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.0249999999999999,0.25,pos,0
102,2019-09-26,"At Tech’s Leading Edge, Worry About a Concentration of Power","A.I. research is becoming increasingly expensive, leaving few people with easy access to the computing firepower necessary to develop the technology.",3,['ORG'],0.0366666666666666,0.6966666666666667,pos,0
103,2015-06-08,"Looking for Robots That Will Cooperate, Not Terminate",A Darpa robotic competition in California focused on machines that can perform ordinary tasks that were the furthest thing from the killer automatons of science fiction.,1,"['ORG', 'GPE']",-0.175,0.35,neg,0
104,2019-11-10,Building a World Where Data Privacy Exists Online,"Dawn Song, an expert in computer security and trustworthy artificial intelligence, is working on making that vision a reality.",3,['PERSON'],-0.6,1.0,neg,0
105,2015-11-17,Lyft Said to Seek $500 Million in Funding,"The ride-hailing start-up is seeking a valuation of about $4 billion, say people briefed on the fund-raising round.",3,['MONEY'],-0.2,0.4,neg,0
106,2015-11-18,Andreessen Horowitz Starts Health Care Fund,The venture capital firm has raised $200 million for a new fund devoted to start-ups at the intersection of biology and software.,3,['MONEY'],-0.0318181818181818,0.4272727272727272,neg,0
107,2018-09-25,DealBook Briefing: Instagram’s Co-Founders Are Leaving,"Kevin Systrom and Mike Krieger, who carefully shaped the company even after Facebook acquired it, have resigned — and tension with Mark Zuckerberg may be to blame.",0,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON']",-0.1,1.0,neg,0
108,2017-10-11,Procter & Gamble and Peltz Spar Over Who Won: DealBook Briefing,"Even if the company prevails in the costliest board fight ever, that fact that many big investors sided with Mr. Peltz highlights the power of activists.",3,['PERSON'],0.25,0.3,pos,0
109,2018-02-23,Facebook and Google Struggle to Squelch ‘Crisis Actor’ Posts,"The tech companies vowed this week to stamp out conspiracy videos and misinformation on the Parkland, Fla., shooting. So far, they are falling short.",1,"['DATE', 'GPE', 'GPE']",0.05,0.65,pos,0
110,2020-05-07,"After the Bailouts, Will Taxes Go Up?","BlackRock’s C.E.O., Larry Fink, is worried about what happens when the bill for government rescues comes due.",2,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",-0.125,0.375,neg,0
111,2019-07-12,Ford and VW Agree to Share Costs of Self-Driving and Electric Cars,A deal announced Friday is an example of how carmakers are joining forces to survive a major shift in technology. But can two longtime rivals cooperate?,2,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.0625,0.5,pos,0
112,2015-07-26,Facebook and Other Tech Giants Expand Internet Access in Africa,Facebook and other leading American technology companies see Africa as a place to experiment with new ways of expanding Internet access.,2,"['NORP', 'LOC']",0.0037878787878787,0.2765151515151515,pos,0
113,2019-11-24,Internet Companies Prepare to Fight the ‘Deepfake’ Future,Researchers are creating tools to find A.I.-generated fake videos before they become impossible to detect. Some experts fear it is a losing battle.,2,['CARDINAL'],-0.5833333333333333,1.0,neg,0
114,2017-10-25,Cisco and Google Find Mutual Interest in Cloud Computing,Two generations of Silicon Valley giants are finding that working together is better than falling behind competitors like Amazon and Microsoft.,3,"['CARDINAL', 'LOC', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.0499999999999999,0.6,pos,1
115,2020-12-20,The Week in Business: We’ve Been Hacked,"A sophisticated cyberattack breached multiple government agencies and major private companies, and no one noticed for months.",1,['DATE'],0.140625,0.46875,pos,0
116,2020-04-28,"Alphabet’s Profit Is Up, but Company Warns of Difficulties",The chief executive of Google’s parent company said it experienced a “significant and sudden slowdown” in advertising in March.,1,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.3916666666666666,0.7583333333333333,pos,0
117,2019-05-09,Uber Is Going Public: How Today’s Tech I.P.O.s Differ From the Dot-Com Boom,"Uber, Lyft and others going public this year are more established than their tech counterparts from the late 90s, but as some see slowing growth, there are questions about where they go from here.",3,"['DATE', 'DATE']",0.0666666666666666,0.3888888888888888,pos,0
118,2020-03-03,Stocks Tumble After the Fed Cuts Rates,The drop in stocks and bond yields suggests investors think the Federal Reserve’s interest-rate cut won’t contain the economic impact of the coronavirus.,2,['ORG'],0.2,0.2,pos,0
119,2018-08-16,Google Employees Protest Secret Work on Censored Search Engine for China,"About 1,400 of the internet company’s employees have signed a letter demanding transparency, saying censored search results raise “urgent moral and ethical issues.”",2,['CARDINAL'],0.1,0.425,pos,0
120,2016-02-18,Marissa Mayer Meets Yahoo Developers at a Confrontation-Free Gathering,Anyone hoping for dramatic confrontations or big plot twists at Yahoo’s mobile developer conference was sorely disappointed.,3,['ORG'],-0.3944444444444444,0.4833333333333333,neg,0
121,2020-10-08,Black LinkedIn Is Thriving. Does LinkedIn Have a Problem With That?,"The social network’s tone has long reflected corporate America: staid, monolithic, white. Now Black users are speaking up — and saying the site is limiting their voice.",3,['GPE'],-0.0366666666666666,0.18,neg,0
122,2017-02-05,Not Everyone in Tech Cheers Visa Program for Foreign Workers,Tech companies say the H-1B program is needed to find highly skilled employees. But it has also been used to lower labor costs and cut jobs.,3,['PRODUCT'],0.5,0.5,pos,0
123,2021-02-19,Why We Want Tech Copycats to Fail,Big Tech likes to copy the hot new thing. But that’s not always good for the rest of us.,3,['ORG'],0.2715909090909091,0.5011363636363637,pos,0
124,2021-01-20,President Biden’s Tech To-Do List,"The new administration will try to restrain Big Tech, manage China and expand internet access.",2,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.0681818181818181,0.2772727272727273,pos,0
125,2021-09-27,A Strange Voice on the Phone,The digital media company Ozy was close to securing a $40 million investment from Goldman Sachs before things got weird.,0,"['GPE', 'MONEY', 'ORG']",-0.25,0.5,neg,0
126,2018-08-28,NYT: Today's Business With Miguel Helft,Jeff Sommer and Miguel Helft on Google's new operating system for personal computers.,0,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.0681818181818181,0.3772727272727272,pos,0
127,2017-11-01,"Facebook, Under Fire in Russia Inquiry, Posts 79% Rise in Profit",Facebook’s top executives skipped congressional hearings on Russian meddling to report the company’s blockbuster financial results to shareholders.,0,"['ORG', 'NORP']",0.1666666666666666,0.1666666666666666,pos,0
128,2018-08-24,Alphabet’s Plans for a China Comeback Go Beyond Google Search,"The company’s driverless-car unit, Waymo, has registered a Shanghai subsidiary — the latest sign of the breadth of its interest in the country. Yet hurdles are plentiful.",1,"['PRODUCT', 'GPE']",0.5,0.9,pos,0
129,2022-06-16,How a Religious Sect Landed Google in a Lawsuit,A video producer claims he was fired after he complained that an obscure group based in the Sierra foothills dominated a business unit at Google.,1,"['ORG', 'ORG']",-0.3,0.2,neg,0
130,2015-04-15,Nokia Agrees to $16.6 Billion Takeover of Alcatel-Lucent,The combined company is expected to become the world’s second-largest telecom equipment manufacturer behind Ericsson of Sweden.,3,"['ORDINAL', 'GPE']",-0.25,0.55,neg,0
131,2020-10-13,Apple Unveils a Smaller HomePod,The company’s smart speaker product has not been as successful as Amazon Echo and Google Home.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.4821428571428571,0.7964285714285715,pos,0
132,2021-04-27,Another tech company bans employees from talking politics at work.,"The announcement by Basecamp, a company that makes productivity software, follows a surge of employee activism and corporate action on social issues.",3,['GPE'],0.0444444444444444,0.0555555555555555,pos,0
133,2021-10-04,The Stock Market’s Hot Summer Became a Swoon. Where Does It Go Next?,Inflation and supply chain problems have been a concern since the pandemic began. But action by the Federal Reserve and pressure on corporate profits put those worries in sharp focus.,3,['ORG'],-0.0083333333333333,0.2833333333333333,neg,0
134,2020-06-05,Don’t Kid Yourself: Online Lectures Are Here to Stay,"The economic forces are too powerful for virtual instruction to go away after the pandemic. The important question is who will benefit financially, a Cornell economist says.",3,['GPE'],0.225,0.55,pos,0
135,2016-06-07,Using Google Now for iOS,"Google makes a version of its predictive assistant software for Apple devices, but the native Android version has more features.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.5,0.5,pos,0
136,2017-04-03,The Digital Nomad Life: Combining Work and Travel,"Dozens of new programs allow the experience of living and working in far-off places, weeks or months at a time.",0,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
137,2016-09-20,"In Backing Autonomous Cars, U.S. Tells Automakers to Figure It Out","Federal guidelines stress safety but give automakers, one of the country’s most regulated industries, plenty of room to innovate.",0,['CARDINAL'],0.5,0.5,pos,0
138,2016-09-03,"Goodbye, Ivory Tower. Hello, Silicon Valley Candy Store.","The promise of big data and big paychecks is drawing some of academia’s top economists to study consumer behavior for tech companies like Airbnb, Amazon and Uber.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.1666666666666666,0.2333333333333333,pos,0
139,2015-10-07,Daily Report: Microsoft Turns On the Hardware Charm,"New hardware, including the $1,500 Surface Book, shows Microsoft is serious about adjusting to competition from the likes of Apple and Google.",0,"['MONEY', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.0984848484848484,0.5606060606060606,neg,0
140,2017-08-24,"After Charlottesville, Even Dating Apps Are Cracking Down on Hate",OKCupid and other dating sites are the latest tech companies to ban extremists.,3,['ORG'],0.1875,0.6375,pos,0
141,2015-07-13,"CrowdStrike, Cybersecurity Services Provider, Raises $100 Million","The investment was led by Google Capital, in what it says will be the first of several cybersecurity deals.",1,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL']",0.125,0.1666666666666666,pos,0
142,2021-12-01,How to Carry Your Covid Health Data on a Smartphone,"To plan for safe travels and gatherings this holiday season, here are some simple ways to take your Covid-related health data with you.",2,['DATE'],0.25,0.4285714285714286,pos,0
143,2018-07-09,A Taste of Lime: Uber Invests in an Electric Scooter Company,"The investment in Lime, an electric scooter start-up, is the latest effort by Uber to expand beyond ride-hailing.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.5,0.9,pos,0
144,2015-08-05,‘Right to Be Forgotten’ Online Could Spread,Some countries’ demands for the erasure of search engine results on privacy grounds could soon affect even information available in the United States.,2,['GPE'],0.4,0.4,pos,0
145,2021-01-30,The Silicon Valley Start-Up That Caused Wall Street Chaos,"Robinhood pitched itself to investors as the antithesis of Wall Street. It didn’t say that it also entirely relies on Wall Street. This past week, the two realities collided.",3,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL']",-0.125,0.4375,neg,0
146,2021-11-30,Dorsey’s Twitter Departure Hints at Tech Moguls’ Restlessness,"Jack Dorsey, who is stepping down after six years as Twitter’s chief executive, is one of the tech leaders who seem to have grown tired of managing their empires.",1,"['PERSON', 'DATE', 'PERSON']",-0.2777777777777778,0.4944444444444444,neg,0
147,2020-07-27,What to Do About TikTok,"Instead of banning the app, U.S. officials could force it to be more transparent.",0,['GPE'],0.5,0.5,pos,0
148,2017-07-13,Morning Agenda: Britain Bolsters Its Bid for Aramco I.P.O.,A potential change to the London Stock Exchange’s rules could make a British listing for Saudi Aramco look more attractive.,2,"['ORG', 'NORP', 'NORP']",0.325,0.625,pos,0
149,2016-05-15,Warren Buffett and Dan Gilbert Unite in Bid to Acquire Yahoo,The unusual presence of Mr. Gilbert and Mr. Buffett in the bidding suggest just how far Yahoo and its advisers have cast their net to find potential buyers.,0,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.075,0.75,pos,0
150,2022-05-16,Are You Happy? Your Boss Is Asking.,"To some, the pursuit of workplace happiness — and its price, like an $18,000 “happiness M.B.A.” for managers — can seem like a corporate attempt to turn feelings into productivity.",1,['MONEY'],0.4666666666666666,0.1333333333333333,pos,0
151,2021-06-06,The Cost of Being an ‘Interchangeable Asian’,"At some top companies, Asian Americans are overrepresented in midlevel roles and underrepresented in leadership. The root of this workplace inequality could stem from the all-too-common experience of being confused for someone else.",1,['NORP'],0.0333333333333333,0.3999999999999999,pos,0
152,2020-06-12,"For Online Learning, Business Has Never Been Better","Demand for Chegg roughly doubled when schools shut down, but its chief executive, Dan Rosensweig, now needs to figure out how the company will adapt.",1,"['PERSON', 'PERSON']",-0.1277777777777778,0.3444444444444444,neg,0
153,2015-11-01,SAP Chief Bill McDermott Embarks on Health Care Mission After Losing His Eye,"SAP’s chief executive lost his eye after an accident in July. Now he wants his company to delve deeper into health care, following a tradition of tech leaders who have turned to their industry when, or after, experiencing health problems.",1,"['GPE', 'DATE']",0.1,0.1,pos,0
154,2019-04-27,The Week in Business: Tesla’s Driverless Taxis and Uber’s I.P.O.,"Plus, Boeing’s plane problems are adding up, and Facebook prepares for a big fine — or a slap on the wrist?",2,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.2083333333333333,0.3,pos,0
155,2015-09-21,"4chan Message Board Sold to Founder of 2Channel, a Japanese Web Culture Pioneer","4chan, an anonymous online message board with more than 20 million monthly visitors, is being acquired by the founder of 2channel, a Japanese message board that inspired 4chan’s founder.",2,"['TIME', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'NORP', 'PERCENT']",0.25,0.25,pos,0
156,2015-08-04,Siebel Institute Seeks to Make the Smart Grid Smarter,The new Siebel Energy Institute is backing research into the software needed to deliver the energy-saving promise of smart-grid technology.,3,['ORG'],0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
157,2016-12-06,Donald Trump Summons Tech Leaders to a Round-Table Meeting,"During the presidential race, Silicon Valley leaders shunned Mr. Trump and all he stood for. Next week, they’ll meet in New York.",0,"['LOC', 'PERSON', 'DATE', 'GPE']",0.0681818181818181,0.2272727272727272,pos,0
158,2015-06-10,What Apple’s Tim Cook Overlooked in His Defense of Privacy,"When Apple’s chief executive gave a speech on the tech industry’s privacy practices, he failed to fairly explore the benefits of free, ad-supported services.",3,['ORG'],0.1999999999999999,0.6666666666666666,pos,0
159,2019-04-14,DealBook Briefing: Everything You Need to Know About the Pinterest I.P.O.,How much will the company be valued at? What can go wrong? Who stands to get rich? What does it mean for other I. P. O.s? Let us answer all those questions and more.,3,['PERSON'],0.0229166666666666,0.56875,pos,0
160,2018-06-13,"DealBook Briefing: Media Mergers Coming in 3, 2, 1 …",AT&T’s legal victory in the fight over its takeover bid for Time Warner means we can expect a flood of M.&A. in the coming months.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.2,0.2,pos,0
161,2017-06-15,"Jeff Bezos Wants Ideas for Philanthropy, So He Asked Twitter","The Amazon chief asked for tips where his money could be used in the “here and now,” unlike many of his business investments.",1,['ORG'],0.5,0.5,pos,0
162,2015-09-02,Competitors Accuse Google of Using Search to Diminish Apps,"In November, Google will start penalizing the search rankings of sites that show “please install our app” ads, a move that rivals say has less to do with providing users with a good experience and more to do with protecting Google’s business.",2,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.3444444444444444,0.3888888888888889,pos,0
163,2017-08-16,Microsoft Teaches Autonomous Gliders to Make Decisions on the Fly,Microsoft is building gliders that adapt to surprises. The goal is to teach autonomous vehicles of all sorts to deal with uncertainty the way humans do.,2,['ORG'],0.4,0.7,pos,0
164,2016-11-20,‘Fantastic Beasts’ Is a Hit for Warner Bros.,"The J.K. Rowling-scripted fantasy is a boon for the studio, whose last three big-budget efforts drew cool reactions from critics.",3,['CARDINAL'],0.175,0.3583333333333333,pos,0
165,2016-07-07,"Kevin Turner, Microsoft Executive, to Join Citadel Securities","Mr. Turner, Microsoft’s chief operating officer, is the latest in a spate of technology executives to join a financial firm.",1,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",0.0999999999999999,0.4333333333333333,pos,0
166,2017-10-10,How Israel Caught Russian Hackers Scouring the World for U.S. Secrets,"Exploiting the popular Kaspersky antivirus software, Russian hackers searched millions of computers for American intelligence keywords. Israeli intelligence tipped off American officials.",3,"['NORP', 'CARDINAL', 'NORP', 'NORP', 'NORP']",0.15,0.225,pos,0
167,2021-01-19,How to Make Data Privacy Real,"We need control over how our data is used. Thanks to California, there’s a promising new path.",1,['GPE'],0.1787878787878788,0.3848484848484848,pos,0
168,2018-03-16,Jacobs’s Pursuit of Qualcomm Faces Long Odds: DealBook Briefing,"When Michael Dell took Dell private in 2013, he had a clearly stated mission and a large stake in the company.The same can’t be said so far of Paul Jacobs in his bid for Qualcomm.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.0828571428571428,0.4623809523809523,pos,0
169,2019-11-08,American Companies Tiptoe Toward China’s Big Shopping Day,Taylor Swift will be there. But tensions over trade and Hong Kong have made some U.S. retailers wary ahead of Singles Day.,1,"['PERSON', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'EVENT']",-0.5,0.7,neg,0
170,2017-12-08,Farhad and Mike’s Week in Tech: The Big Bitcoin Boom,"In this week’s tech newsletter, our correspondents discuss Bitcoin, Amazon and the tech industry’s ongoing problems with sexual harassment.",3,"['DATE', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.5,0.8333333333333334,pos,0
171,2018-01-02,Peter Thiel Is a Bitcoin Believer: DealBook Briefing,The value of the digital currency jumped this afternoon after Mr. Thiel’s Founders Fund venture firm emerged as an investor.,3,"['TIME', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.1,0.2,neg,1
172,2017-02-21,"Morning Agenda: Snap, Financial Regulation, Kraft Heinz and Unilever",Google produced a horde of millionaires in Silicon Valley when it debuted on the stock market in 2004. Many in Los Angeles hope Snap’s I.P.O. will have a similar impact.,2,"['ORG', 'LOC', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.25,0.45,pos,0
173,2018-07-03,Silicon Valley’s Giants Take Their Talent Hunt to Cambridge,A boom in artificial intelligence research has drawn the tech industry’s biggest companies and their checkbooks to the storied English city.,3,['LANGUAGE'],-0.3,0.5,neg,0
174,2019-02-15,DealBook Briefing: The Bigger Picture Behind Amazon Ditching N.Y.,The company’s decision could be a turning point for corporate-civic relations in the U.S. and a sign that leftist views are gaining traction.,0,['GPE'],-0.05,0.6,neg,0
175,2020-10-28,PayPal Invests in Racial Equality,The company is putting $50 million in Black- and Latino-led venture capital firms.,3,['MONEY'],-0.1666666666666666,0.4333333333333333,neg,0
176,2016-09-02,How Spy Tech Firms Let Governments See Everything on a Smartphone,"The NSO Group sells expensive surveillance tools for criminal and terrorism inquiries, but critics say they are also used to track journalists and rights activists.",2,['ORG'],-0.45,0.625,neg,0
177,2015-04-29,Twitter’s Costolo on Earnings,"CNBC interviews Dick Costolo, chief of Twitter, who discusses the company’s earnings, which were released early and missed expectations, as well as Twitter’s new ad partnership with Google.",3,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.1181818181818181,0.3772727272727272,pos,0
178,2017-06-26,"Google Said to Face $1.2 Billion Antitrust Fine, but Battle With Europe Looms",The hefty penalty is likely to be quickly overshadowed by a more complex problem: How should Google comply with the decision to rein in its power?,3,['ORG'],0.1333333333333333,0.6,pos,0
179,2018-04-30,Investment Boom From Trump’s Tax Cut Has Yet to Appear,Analysts are still waiting for hard evidence that the new tax law is setting off the investment explosion that President Trump and Republicans promised.,2,"['PERSON', 'NORP']",-0.0776515151515151,0.4981060606060605,neg,0
180,2016-06-03,Shareholder Initiatives Show Their Value,"A plethora of examples involving companies like Dell, Facebook and Tribune Publishing prove that shareholder votes can be of great consequence.",1,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",0.8,0.75,pos,0
181,2018-10-25,Amazon Squeezes Out More Profit as Sales Growth Slows,"The company reported a net income of $2.9 billion in the third quarter, partly by being more efficient in its warehouses and data centers.",3,"['MONEY', 'DATE']",0.1666666666666666,0.1666666666666666,pos,0
182,2021-09-14,"Apple’s new iPhone 13 is better, but not by much.","Apple said its new iPhone 13 models have better screens, cameras and battery life, but it didn’t announce any major new advances.",0,"['ORG', 'PRODUCT']",0.2088068181818181,0.4772727272727273,pos,0
183,2019-04-11,A Charity Accepts Uber Stock as Donations. Then Uses It to Pay Staff Bonuses. Is That O.K.?,Entrepreneurs who own stakes in private companies can donate some of their equity to Charity: water. The proceeds will eventually be paid out to the nonprofit’s employees.,1,['ORG'],0.3,0.6875,pos,0
184,2015-05-12,"For Verizon and AOL, Mobile Is a Magic Word",The Verizon-AOL deal is just the latest corporate reaction to a staggering shift in the way people across the globe get their news and entertainment.,0,['ORG'],0.25,0.45,pos,0
185,2017-02-03,Snap’s Plan Is Most Unfriendly to Outsiders,"The company behind the popular disappearing-message app Snapchat is offering three types of shares, and outsiders will get no voting rights.",3,['CARDINAL'],0.0999999999999999,0.8,pos,0
186,2017-11-17,"DealBook Briefing: Corporate Taxes, Musk vs. Buffett, and Will Fox Strike a Deal?","Will companies invest their cash windfall from the Republican tax plans? Also, the Murdochs are in talks with suitors interested in pieces of their empire. But will they sell?",3,"['NORP', 'PERSON']",0.25,0.5,pos,0
187,2018-05-25,What Advertising History Says About the Future of Fake News,"Technological advances have made it easy to spread fake news. But after these fabrications become familiar, their danger is likely to recede, the economist Austan Goolsbee says.",0,['PERSON'],0.0770833333333333,0.8333333333333334,pos,0
188,2020-01-10,"The Week in Tech: New Decade, Same Old Trouble in Washington","If the tech industry was hoping for some relief from lawmakers’ pressure, the start of the year had to have been a disappointment.",3,['DATE'],-0.6,0.4,neg,0
189,2017-10-10,The E.P.A. Move’s Winners and Losers: DealBook Briefing,"As the Trump administration seeks to repeal Obama-era clean power rules, expect coal companies to come out ahead — but not by as much as people might think.",2,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.2833333333333333,0.45,pos,0
190,2018-08-30,Here’s the Conversation We Really Need to Have About Bias at Google,President Trump’s charges that Google shows anti-conservative search bias is wrong. But Google may well be biased against minorities and others who lack real-world power.,2,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.5,0.9,neg,0
191,2022-01-26,"John Arrillaga Sr., Who Helped Build Silicon Valley, Dies at 84","Starting in the 1960s, he developed the area’s farmland into office parks that housed fast-growing technology companies.",1,['DATE'],0.05,0.2,pos,0
192,2019-06-10,Fiat Chrysler in Deal for Self-Driving Car Technology,"The agreement, with Aurora Innovation, underscores the heavy emphasis automakers are placing on autonomous cars.",2,['PERSON'],0.1,0.6,pos,0
193,2018-06-13,Apple to Close iPhone Security Hole That Law Enforcement Uses to Crack Devices,"Apple is closing a technological loophole that let authorities hack into locked iPhones, infuriating law enforcement officials and reigniting a debate over security versus privacy.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG']",-0.6,0.8,neg,0
194,2015-03-02,Microsoft Presents Low-Cost Phones and Windows 10 for Mobile,"At the Mobile World Congress, the company for the first time showed off the operating system for phones and continued its evolving strategy of delivering low-cost Lumia devices.",1,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG']",0.25,0.3333333333333333,pos,0
195,2019-11-27,A Big Screen to Sift Through Recruits,"Many people joining the newsroom are digitally savvy and helping media with a digital transition, says Theodore Kim, who runs fellowships and internships.",1,['PERSON'],0.1666666666666666,0.1666666666666666,pos,0
196,2017-09-14,Morning Agenda: Blocking of Lattice Sale Weighs on China Deals,The White House move to prevent the chip maker from selling itself to a Chinese-backed buyer may signal trouble for similar proposed takeovers.,2,"['ORG', 'NORP']",-0.0666666666666666,0.2,neg,0
197,2021-07-18,"Smartphone Directions May Put Novice Hikers in Danger, Experts Say","From New Hampshire to Scotland, services like Google Maps can direct ill-prepared hikers onto trails that would challenge even the most experienced climbers, mountaineers said.",2,"['GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.3840909090909091,0.5636363636363636,pos,1
198,2018-01-04,Companies Warn of Hits From Tax Cuts. Don’t Be Fooled.,Companies are expected to report billions of dollars in short-term losses stemming from the new tax law. But they are a prelude to much larger profits.,3,['MONEY'],0.0121212121212121,0.4515151515151515,pos,0
199,2017-05-21,"As Profit Dwindles, Ford Is Said to Replace Its C.E.O.","Jim Hackett, who oversees the unit working on autonomous vehicles, will take over an automaker under fire over its stock price and stagnant sales.",2,['PERSON'],0.4,0.7,pos,0
200,2017-05-18,Daily Report: Remembering When Uber and Google Were Allies,"Not all that long ago, Google was an early investor in the ride-hailing service. Now they are fighting in federal court.",2,['ORG'],0.025,0.35,pos,0
201,2017-03-28,Uber Releases Diversity Report and Repudiates Its ‘Hard-Charging Attitude’,"The report, which excludes drivers, showed Uber’s employees are overwhelmingly male and the largest ethnic group is white, though the figures are not so different from other tech companies.",3,['PERSON'],-0.03125,0.26875,neg,1
202,2020-06-17,Tackling the Unsolvable Problem: The Bottomless Email Inbox,"For $99 a year, Hey wants to help us restore some control. The new service has a way to go — and so does email, come to think of it.",1,['MONEY'],0.1681818181818181,0.2772727272727273,pos,0
203,2018-10-26,"Stocks Resume Slide, Pulling S.&P. 500 Briefly Into a Correction",The benchmark index fell to 10 percent off its most recent peak in early trading on Friday but recovered some of those losses. It is down more than 9 percent from its high in September.,0,"['PERCENT', 'DATE', 'PERCENT', 'DATE']",0.184074074074074,0.3964814814814815,pos,0
204,2017-01-25,"Morning Agenda: Shareholder Rights, Stealing Code, Trump Policies","The total disenfranchisement of public shareholders has been a long time coming in the tech sector, but with Snap’s I.P.O. it may be just around the corner.",3,['ORG'],-0.0166666666666666,0.4055555555555556,neg,0
205,2017-08-19,The Moral Voice of Corporate America,"C.E.O.s are speaking out on social and political issues in sometimes startling ways, recasting the role business plays in the national debate.",1,['ORG'],-0.1555555555555555,0.2222222222222222,neg,0
206,2020-01-14,Apple Takes a (Cautious) Stand Against Opening a Killer’s iPhones,"The Silicon Valley giant is preparing for a legal fight over encryption, even as it works to reduce tensions with the Justice Department.",2,"['LOC', 'ORG']",0.1,0.6,pos,0
207,2017-10-12,Have a Group Chat on an iPad,"Apple’s FaceTime software doesn’t yet support more than one-to-one video calls, but other compatible apps let you chat with a several people at once.",3,"['ORG', 'CARDINAL']",0.125,0.2916666666666667,pos,0
208,2022-04-28,An Unsteady Moment for Tech,The past decade has been one long party for tech. Where we go from here isn’t so clear.,3,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL']",-0.0666666666666666,0.3444444444444444,neg,0
209,2018-03-27,"Breitbart, Facing Headwinds, Tries a New Tack: Live Events",The right-wing website is taking a cue from one of its foes — the mainstream media — and sponsoring a town-hall event in suburban New Orleans next month.,2,"['GPE', 'DATE']",0.0454545454545454,0.1515151515151515,pos,0
210,2020-12-03,Google Researcher Says She Was Fired Over Paper Highlighting Bias in A.I.,"Timnit Gebru, one of the few Black women in her field, had voiced exasperation over the company’s response to efforts to increase minority hiring.",3,"['ORG', 'CARDINAL']",-0.1833333333333333,0.2666666666666666,neg,0
211,2020-10-31,The Election Work Diary of a Reporter With 2.5 Million Subscribers,"Peter Hamby hosts “Good Luck America” on Snapchat. “My North Star is really the low-information news consumer,” he says. “That’s not an insult.”",2,"['PERSON', 'WORK_OF_ART']",0.4499999999999999,0.4,pos,0
212,2016-10-08,"Swarovski, Maker of All Things Bejeweled, Tries On a Hoodie","In a village in the Austrian Alps, Swarovski, which has been making crystals for more than a century, is refashioning itself as a tech company.",3,"['NORP', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'DATE']",0.5,0.5,pos,0
213,2015-10-08,"Seattle, in Midst of Tech Boom, Tries to Keep Its Soul","The city’s leaders are hoping to avoid the pitfalls bedeviling San Francisco — surging home prices, less diversity — as its tech scene expands.",3,['GPE'],-0.1666666666666666,0.0666666666666666,neg,0
214,2017-10-26,"Russia Fanned Flames With Twitter, Which Faces a Blowback","A troll account linked to Moscow shows how easily social media fanned the flames of outrage. Unlike other tech giants, Twitter could have a harder time dealing with the fallout.",3,"['GPE', 'PERSON']",-0.0638888888888889,0.1472222222222222,neg,0
215,2017-02-23,Google Self-Driving Car Unit Accuses Uber of Using Stolen Technology,"A lawsuit says an employee took thousands of secret files on self-driving car design when he left Google to start his own company, later sold to Uber.",3,"['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.0499999999999999,0.425,pos,0
216,2020-07-20,U.S. Imposes Sanctions on 11 Chinese Companies Over Human Rights,"The move, which affects suppliers to major international brands such as Apple, Ralph Lauren and Tommy Hilfiger, could force companies to sever some ties to China.",1,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'GPE']",0.0208333333333333,0.3333333333333333,pos,0
217,2018-03-25,"Uber to Sell Its Southeast Asia Business to Grab, a Regional Rival","After ceding China and Russia in recent years, the ride-hailing giant is pulling out of another region where it faced tough — and costly — competition.",1,"['GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE']",-0.1296296296296296,0.6944444444444445,neg,0
218,2019-10-15,Ad Giant Wins Over Disney With Big Data Pitch,"After a “painful” earnings report, the advertising company Publicis trotted out what it knows about consumers in its “most important pitch of the year.”",0,"['PERSON', 'DATE']",0.0666666666666667,0.7999999999999999,pos,0
219,2017-09-26,Microsoft C.E.O. Says Tech’s Progress on Gender Equality Is ‘Not Sufficient’,Satya Nadella said Silicon Valley had “a significant distance to cover” in offering equal opportunities for female workers.,0,"['PERSON', 'LOC']",0.125,0.4305555555555556,pos,0
220,2015-05-04,Apple TV Remote Expected to Add Touch Pad in Redesign,"When Apple introduces its new TV box this summer, the remote control will gain a touch pad and also be slightly thicker than the current version.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",-0.0325757575757575,0.3053030303030303,neg,0
221,2016-11-11,Erasing the Past From Google Search,"The United States doesn’t have “right to be forgotten” laws as Europe does, but Google considers some requests to remove information from search results.",1,"['GPE', 'LOC', 'ORG']",0.2857142857142857,0.5357142857142857,pos,0
222,2022-03-18,Lawsuit Accuses Google of Bias Against Black Employees,The lawsuit echoes many of the complaints Black employees have expressed over the years about working at the company.,0,['DATE'],0.1666666666666666,0.4666666666666667,pos,0
223,2016-08-02,Getting Chatty in Gmail,Google’s mail program offers its users the choice between a no-frills instant-messaging service and a more full-featured communications hub.,3,['ORG'],0.3,0.25,pos,0
224,2017-06-01,Morning Agenda: Will Trump Pull U.S. From Paris Accord?,"White House officials said that they expected him to abandon the landmark global warming agreement, but they also said that decision could change.",2,['ORG'],-0.0333333333333333,0.1333333333333333,neg,0
225,2021-04-07,Job Training That’s Free Until You’re Hired Is a Blueprint for Biden,"Social Finance, a nonprofit, is spreading a model in which training programs get paid if students get hired, not just if they enroll.",3,['ORG'],0.0333333333333333,0.0666666666666666,pos,0
226,2016-04-21,"Despite Strong Earnings, G.M. Has Much to Prove to Investors","Much of the credit for G.M.’s earnings has gone to a strong car market in the United States, not the company’s improving balance sheet and new models.",0,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.2565656565656565,0.4626262626262626,pos,0
227,2021-04-06,Corporate America’s Not-So-New Allies,Democrats are coming to business’ political aid over social issues. That’s not as big a shift as it might seem.,1,['NORP'],0.0111111111111111,0.0888888888888889,pos,0
228,2020-03-25,Nurses Share Coronavirus Stories Anonymously in an Online Document,"A health care worker in New Jersey created a digital venue for people in the field to chronicle poor working conditions that may put patients at risk. “It is disgusting,” one nurse wrote.",0,"['GPE', 'CARDINAL']",-0.3159090909090909,0.5136363636363637,neg,0
229,2019-01-26,Why Are Young People Pretending to Love Work?,I saw the greatest minds of my generation log 18-hour days — and then boast about #hustle on Instagram. When did performative workaholism become a lifestyle?,2,"['TIME', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']",1.0,1.0,pos,0
230,2015-11-10,Facebook to Appeal a Belgian Court’s Ruling on Data Privacy,The social media giant was told by a court in Brussels that it must stop collecting online data about people in Belgium who are not its users.,1,"['GPE', 'GPE']",0.0166666666666666,0.5333333333333333,pos,0
231,2016-01-24,Drone Lobbying Heats Up on Capitol Hill,"The efforts in the halls of Congress are part of a multifront intervention by advocates for broader drone use as well as by their opponents, who argue that the machines pose significant safety and privacy risks.",3,['ORG'],0.375,0.875,pos,0
232,2018-03-24,Timeline: Facebook and Google Under Regulators’ Glare,"In 2011, the F.T.C. first required a company to create a comprehensive data privacy program for consumers. Europe will soon take another big step.",1,"['DATE', 'ORDINAL', 'LOC']",0.125,0.2166666666666666,pos,0
233,2016-10-02,"Google to Unveil New Devices, and Labor Dept. Will Report on Jobs",Google is expected to reveal Google Home; and the Labor Department will report the penultimate jobs report scheduled before the presidential election.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.1,0.4,neg,0
234,2017-02-27,"Amit Singhal, Uber Executive Linked to Old Harassment Claim, Resigns","The head of Uber’s engineering efforts did not disclose the circumstances of his departure from Google last year, according to a person familiar with the matter.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.1875,0.2833333333333333,pos,0
235,2021-04-07,JPMorgan’s Chief Sees a Boom Coming,Jamie Dimon tells the bank’s investors to prepare for an economic upswell.,2,['PERSON'],0.2,0.2,pos,0
236,2015-11-13,The War on Campus Sexual Assault Goes Digital,Students at some colleges can use a service called Callisto to anonymously record the details of a sexual assault and later file a report if they choose.,3,['ORG'],0.25,0.4166666666666667,pos,0
237,2017-03-07,"Selfie With Merkel by Refugee Became a Legal Case, but Facebook Won in German Court","The picture of Anas Modamani with the German chancellor was used in fake news posts about terrorism, and he wanted the social media giant to prevent its use.",0,"['PERSON', 'NORP']",-0.1166666666666666,0.5166666666666666,neg,0
238,2016-05-12,Changing Android’s Default Apps,"If you want to use something other than Google’s own Chrome browser as your go-to app, you can choose a different program.",3,"['ORG', 'PRODUCT']",0.1583333333333333,0.6583333333333333,pos,0
239,2019-04-12,"In the Stock Market, Value Again Lags Growth","For a decade, value stocks have failed to surge ahead. Investing in them may be a smart move, but it is likely to require patience.",2,['DATE'],-0.0952380952380952,0.6476190476190476,neg,0
240,2021-09-01,New surveys show how pandemic workplace policies are shifting.,"Most companies now have plans to require that employees get vaccinated by the end of the year, one survey shows.",0,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.5,0.5,pos,0
241,2015-03-19,"Take Google to Court, Staff Report Urged F.T.C.",An internal Federal Trade Commission report recommended that the agency take action against Google for anticompetitive practices. The F.T.C. voted not to bring charges.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.05,0.05,pos,0
242,2021-12-22,The Year in Tech Empires,"In 2021, the tech titans became both more powerful and more vulnerable.",3,['DATE'],0.2,0.625,pos,0
243,2017-02-01,IBM Gives Watson a New Challenge: Your Tax Return,A partnership with H&R Block shows IBM’s strategy for artificial intelligence: Watson will be a smart assistant tailored for specific industries.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON']",-0.1285714285714285,0.5892857142857143,neg,0
244,2016-06-19,Janet Yellen to Testify Before Congress and Britain to Vote on ‘Brexit’,"Analysts will be looking for any hint of policy change in Ms. Yellen’s testimony, and immigration remains a main factor in the upcoming ‘Brexit’ vote.",0,['PERSON'],0.1666666666666666,0.3333333333333333,pos,0
245,2015-02-27,Google Unveils Plan for New Corporate Campus,Google unveiled a radical proposal for a new campus that would replace its current headquarters in Mountain View.,0,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.0681818181818181,0.4272727272727272,pos,0
246,2021-04-06,Google Won. So Did Tech.,"In siding with Google, the Supreme Court gave software experts some love.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.5,0.6,pos,0
247,2021-09-11,A Nick to Apple’s Profits Could Be a Windfall for App Developers,"After a judge opened up a way to avoid Apple’s commission on their sales, companies big and small are seeing dollar signs.",2,['ORG'],-0.125,0.25,neg,0
248,2020-02-11,She Wants to Break Up Big Everything,"Trustbusting advocates like Sarah Miller, who target corporate power, have finally found themselves at the center of the political conversation.",0,['PERSON'],-0.025,0.3,neg,0
249,2021-03-16,Google reduces some app-store fees amid criticism.,"Google said that starting July 1, it would take 15 percent of the first $1 million developers take in from certain app sales, down from 30 percent.",2,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'PERCENT', 'MONEY', 'PERCENT']",0.0771825396825396,0.3234126984126984,pos,0
250,2017-01-06,Russia Requires Apple and Google to Remove LinkedIn From Local App Stores,The move came after a November court ruling found the professional networking service in violation of Russia’s internet laws.,2,"['DATE', 'GPE']",0.1,0.1,pos,0
251,2019-01-31,Apple Shows Facebook Who Has the Power in an App Dispute,"After two days of disruptions, the iPhone maker restored the social network’s access to internal apps that its employees rely on in their jobs.",0,"['DATE', 'ORG']",0.0166666666666666,0.0333333333333333,pos,0
252,2019-11-13,"In Data Journalism, Tech Matters Less Than the People","Ben Casselman, an economics reporter, uses a programming language called R and works with vast data sets. But he says interviews still make for the best stories.",2,['PERSON'],0.5,0.65,pos,0
253,2020-07-08,"Facebook’s Decisions Were ‘Setbacks for Civil Rights,’ Audit Finds",An independent audit faulted the social network for allowing hate speech and disinformation to thrive — potentially posing a threat to the November elections.,1,['DATE'],-0.1916666666666666,0.5229166666666667,neg,0
254,2017-04-15,"Finding Growth in Pizza, Paint and Credit-Card Companies","Alphabet and Facebook are growth stocks, sure. But MasterCard, Domino’s and Sherwin-Williams are also in growth fund portfolios.",2,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.5,0.8888888888888888,pos,0
255,2018-05-20,U.K. vs. U.S.: How Much of Your Personal Data Can You Get?,We decided to test how easy it soon might be for people in Europe to access their personal data compared with users in the United States.,0,"['LOC', 'GPE']",0.2166666666666666,0.5666666666666667,pos,0
256,2021-04-13,"‘Master,’ ‘Slave’ and the Fight Over Offensive Terms in Computing","Nearly a year after the Internet Engineering Task Force took up a plan to replace words that could be considered racist, the debate is still raging.",3,['DATE'],0.1,0.4,pos,0
257,2016-10-02,"Disney’s Hot Streak Stalls, Prompting Rumors That It’s Looking to Grow","Robert Iger, chief of the mass media company, has a history of reinvigorating the company by making deals, but despite a string of good decisions, shares are dipping and investors are getting antsy.",3,['PERSON'],0.7,0.6000000000000001,pos,0
258,2015-10-04,Finance Ministers Meet to Discuss Greek Bailout,European finance ministers are set to discuss how soon Greece receives its next disbursement of funds from the country’s latest international bailout.,1,"['NORP', 'GPE']",0.125,0.225,pos,0
259,2019-12-06,Saudi Aramco Sells $25.6 billion in Shares for I.P.O.,"Saudi Arabia’s state-owned oil company priced its offering at a level that would raise $25.6 billion, becoming the largest stock market debut on record.",3,"['GPE', 'MONEY']",0.45,0.8500000000000001,pos,0
260,2019-08-22,YouTube Disables 210 Channels That Spread Disinformation About Hong Kong Protests,"Days after Facebook and Twitter cracked down on China-backed accounts that were spreading such disinformation, YouTube did the same.",2,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'ORG']",-0.0518518518518518,0.3046296296296296,neg,0
261,2015-08-14,Daily Report: Google Stays in the News with Chromebooks and Antitrust Issues,"Google unveiled a new version of its Chrome operating system, along with Chromebook computing devices made by Dell. It’s been busy week for the company that’s reinventing itself as Alphabet while dealing with antitrust concerns in Europe.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.1181818181818181,0.3772727272727272,pos,0
262,2021-10-21,Why the Cable Company Is Selling TVs,It all comes down to having power over what Americans watch and how.,0,['NORP'],-0.1555555555555555,0.2888888888888889,neg,0
263,2017-09-28,"Australia’s Big Media Set to Get Bigger, With Help From Lawmakers",New legislation would ease ownership limits to help local owners compete with Google and Facebook. Critics say it would largely benefit Rupert Murdoch.,2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON']",0.1168831168831168,0.2943722943722943,pos,0
264,2018-11-14,New York Is a Genuine Tech Hub (and That Was Before Amazon),The Bay Area in California remains the nation’s high-tech epicenter. But New York’s tech work force has been growing impressively.,1,"['LOC', 'GPE', 'GPE']",0.5681818181818181,0.7272727272727273,pos,0
265,2016-10-23,Apple and Tesla to Report Earnings,Apple’s report will offer the first look at sales of the iPhone 7 and the extra business it is getting since Samsung’s troubles with the Galaxy Note 7.,0,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'LAW', 'ORG']",0.125,0.2166666666666666,pos,0
266,2021-11-10,When a Logo Doesn’t Risk It All: Meta’s Brand Is Designed for Unknown Worlds,"The emblem for Facebook’s new parent company is built for the metaverse, even if it disappoints in the real world.",0,['ORG'],0.1681818181818181,0.3772727272727273,pos,0
267,2020-05-06,Apple iPhone SE Review: A Superb Smartphone for a Humble Price,"For $399, this smartphone hits the high notes: speedy, a great camera and a nice screen. Took long enough, didn’t it?",0,['MONEY'],0.302,0.638,pos,0
268,2016-02-22,Mark Zuckerberg Backs Apple in Its Refusal to Unlock iPhone,"Speaking at the Mobile World Congress, Mr. Zuckerberg said he was sympathetic to Apple’s resistance to helping the government open a locked phone.",2,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.25,0.75,pos,0
269,2017-06-13,"The G.E. Puzzle, and the Pieces a New Chief Will Have to Make Fit","John Flannery, named to lead General Electric, is reviewing its portfolio of businesses — some of them core properties, others prospectively for sale.",0,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",0.05,0.5,pos,0
270,2022-07-27,The Default Tech Settings You Should Turn Off Right Away,"These controls, which are buried inside products from Apple, Google, Meta and others, make us share more data than we need to.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.5,0.5,pos,0
271,2021-07-01,Why Didn’t Microsoft Die?,"Microsoft made epic mistakes for years, but it’s again one of the tech world’s superstars.",1,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.1,0.4,pos,0
272,2017-08-11,"To Fit Into Silicon Valley, Wear These Wool Shoes","Silicon Valley has gone through many shoe style trends, including Crocs and Vibrams. Now it’s Allbirds, the wool shoe that techies love to wear.",0,"['LOC', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.5,0.55,pos,0
273,2021-01-11,Fringe Groups Splinter Online After Facebook and Twitter Bans,Tracking what may be planned in the coming days could become even more difficult as the groups take to lesser-known networks and apps that can’t be easily monitored.,3,['DATE'],0.1444444444444444,0.7777777777777778,pos,0
274,2020-05-13,"A Guide to Pandemic Scams, and What Not to Fall For",Fraudsters see opportunities to target us in these uncertain times. Here are their most popular schemes and how we can protect ourselves.,3,['NORP'],0.55,0.7,pos,1
275,2020-02-05,Was Instagram the Steal of the Century?,"The social network, which Facebook bought for $1 billion in 2012, reportedly collected $20 billion in ad revenue last year — surpassing YouTube’s ad sales.",0,"['ORG', 'MONEY', 'DATE', 'MONEY', 'DATE', 'ORG']",0.0166666666666666,0.0666666666666666,pos,0
276,2018-05-06,"What the G.D.P.R., Europe’s Tough New Data Law, Means for You","The European Union is introducing the G.D.P.R, some of the strictest online privacy rules in the world. The aim is to give internet users more control.",3,['ORG'],0.25,0.25,pos,0
277,2016-07-08,Sukhinder Singh Cassidy: Either You Manage Me or I Manage You,"Ms. Singh Cassidy, founder and chairman of the video shopping site Joyus, says if she has to manage employees’ time, they’re not at their best, and neither is she.",1,"['PERSON', 'PERSON']",1.0,0.3,pos,0
278,2015-12-02,Yahoo Struggles as an Afterthought to Advertisers,"Twenty years after its founding, Yahoo, which still has a billion people using its apps and websites, is an also-ran in many ad budgets.",0,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']",0.5,0.5,pos,0
279,2019-04-10,"Net Neutrality Vote Passes House, Fulfilling Promise by Democrats","The legislation, called the Save the Internet Act, faces long odds in the Republican-led Senate.",2,"['NORP', 'ORG']",-0.05,0.4,neg,0
280,2019-12-08,This Man May Be Big Tech’s Biggest Threat,Representative David Cicilline doesn’t just want to enforce the laws governing the tech industry. He wants to change them.,3,['PERSON'],0.2,0.1,pos,0
281,2019-12-19,"Many Facial-Recognition Systems Are Biased, Says U.S. Study","Algorithms falsely identified African-American and Asian faces 10 to 100 times more than Caucasian faces, researchers for the National Institute of Standards and Technology found.",2,"['NORP', 'NORP', 'CARDINAL', 'NORP', 'ORG']",0.0333333333333333,0.3666666666666667,pos,0
282,2017-01-06,"In Sweden, Happiness in a Shorter Workday Can’t Overcome the Cost","A six-hour experimental workday in one of Sweden’s largest cities made employees happier and healthier, but the test is unlikely to be expanded.",0,"['TIME', 'GPE']",-0.2,0.45,neg,0
283,2019-05-08,Capturing What’s Online in China Before It Vanishes,"It’s important to preserve snapshots of China’s internet before they vanish without a trace, says Raymond Zhong, a Times tech reporter in Beijing.",3,"['GPE', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.4,1.0,pos,0
284,2017-09-11,It Distracted Us. It Gave Us Uber. It Made Selfies a Thing.,The first iPhone was released 10 years ago and swiftly turned the smartphone from a curiosity into our constant companion.,0,"['ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.125,0.3333333333333333,pos,0
285,2018-03-02,"Farhad’s Week in Tech: Spotify’s Tough Road, and Our Pile of Reader Feedback","In this week’s tech newsletter, we discuss Spotify’s plans to go public, and a wide range of suggestions for tech coverage in The Times.",3,"['DATE', 'ORG']",-0.05,0.2333333333333333,neg,0
286,2020-08-07,"Trump Swings Against TikTok, WeChat",President Trump signed executive orders against two popular China-based apps. Let me try to explain.,3,"['PERSON', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE']",0.6,0.9,pos,0
287,2019-04-19,‘Medicare for All’ Is Hammering Health Care Stocks. For Now.,"The popularity of proposals for a government-run, single-payer system among Democratic presidential candidates has hurt health care stocks, despite their strong earnings.",2,['NORP'],0.4333333333333333,0.7333333333333333,pos,0
288,2021-12-06,Inside Tesla as Elon Musk Pushed an Unflinching Vision for Self-Driving Cars,"The automaker may have undermined safety in designing its Autopilot driver-assistance system to fit its chief executive’s vision, former employees say.",2,['ORG'],0.2,0.2,pos,0
289,2016-11-16,Facebook Acts to Restore Trust After Overstating Video Views,"Facebook promises to increase use of outside measurement services for ads and to expand use of metrics services, among other measures.",2,['ORG'],-0.0625,0.2125,neg,0
290,2019-08-27,The Baroness Fighting to Protect Children Online,"Beeban Kidron says tech giants exert too much leverage over young users and has pushed laws to change that. “It’s little Timmy in his bedroom versus Mark Zuckerberg in his Valley,” she said.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'LOC']",0.0375,0.3666666666666667,pos,0
291,2018-01-29,"For His Next Act, Ken Chenault Turns His Focus on Silicon Valley","Seeing an opportunity to have a larger impact on Silicon Valley and its business culture, Mr. Chenault plans to join the venture capital firm General Catalyst Partners.",2,"['LOC', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.0499999999999999,0.4666666666666666,neg,0
292,2018-04-05,YouTube Shooting Puts a Focus on Workplace Security,"Active shooter trainings, security cameras and “behavioral threat assessment teams” try to avoid or mitigate office attacks like the one at YouTube.",1,['ORG'],-0.1333333333333333,0.6,neg,0
293,2017-05-12,Morning Agenda: Snap Serves as a Warning to Start-Ups,The market reaction to the Snapchat parent’s $2.2 billion loss is a powerful lesson that “your house has to be in order before you go public.”,3,"['ORG', 'MONEY']",0.15,0.5333333333333333,pos,0
294,2015-05-14,Rdio Introduces a Cheaper Limited Subscription for Music Streaming,"The new service, Rdio Select, will cost $4 a month, significantly lower than the industry’s $10 standard price.",2,"['PERSON', 'MONEY', 'MONEY']",0.1704545454545454,0.4431818181818182,pos,0
295,2019-01-06,Netflix’s Bow to Saudi Censors Comes at a Cost to Free Speech,The decision to remove an episode from its service in Saudi Arabia raises questions of whether entertainment giants will fight for values like free expression.,3,['GPE'],0.4,0.8,pos,0
296,2019-06-18,DealBook Briefing: Say Hello to Facebook’s Cryptocurrency,"Facebook has unveiled its ambitious and hotly anticipated plan to create an alternative financial system, but critics abound.",3,['ORG'],0.1666666666666666,0.5333333333333333,pos,1
297,2017-02-02,Who’s Going to Be a Billionaire? The Biggest Winners of Snap’s I.P.O.,"Public offerings by Google, Facebook and other technology companies created paths for a lucky few to become billionaires. Snap’s offering looks to be no exception.",1,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.0020833333333333,0.34375,pos,0
298,2019-03-19,"Myspace, Once the King of Social Networks, Lost Years of Data From Its Heyday","More than a decade’s worth of data was corrupted in a 2016 server transfer, the company said.",2,"['DATE', 'DATE']",0.4,0.3,pos,0
299,2019-06-10,DealBook Briefing: Meet the New Defense Industry Giant,Uniting the aerospace unit of United Technologies and Raytheon will create a huge maker of jet engines and missiles — and could force more mergers in the industry.,2,['ORG'],0.45,0.7,pos,0
300,2015-04-10,Fund-Raising May Value Spotify Above $8 Billion,"If the investment round closes, it will place Spotify firmly in the ranks of some of the most richly valued technology companies, joining the likes of Uber, Airbnb and Snapchat.",3,"['GPE', 'ORG']",0.11875,0.5125,pos,0
301,2017-09-06,Red Sox Cheating Scandal Highlights Apple Watch’s Illicit Uses,"The Apple Watch, which is bound for an update Sept. 12, has been called the “new easiest way to cheat” on exams.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
302,2015-05-24,Amazon to Stop Funneling European Sales Through Low-Tax Haven,"Pressure is mounting for American tech companies, including Google, to stop using complex tax structures and pay more on their European operations.",3,"['NORP', 'ORG', 'NORP']",0.05,0.225,pos,1
303,2017-08-02,Amazon’s Jobs Fair Sends Clear Message: Now Hiring Thousands,Amazon’s nationwide jobs fair on Wednesday offered a vivid illustration of its ascendance and seemingly insatiable need for workers to fuel its growth.,2,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.4125,0.825,pos,0
304,2018-10-18,DealBook Briefing: SoftBank’s Big Saudi Problem,The Japanese company became the most powerful tech investor with $45 billion from Saudi Arabia. Now that money is causing it some headaches.,3,"['NORP', 'MONEY', 'GPE']",0.2666666666666666,0.5,pos,0
305,2016-08-24,"Daily Report: More Clean Energy, Brought to You by the Cloud","Big data centers for the likes of Apple, Facebook and Google are increasing the demand for renewable energy, which may spur the construction of green facilities.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG']",-0.1,0.2,neg,0
306,2019-01-09,"To Cover China, There’s No Substitute for WeChat","Li Yuan conducts much of her work on the WeChat mobile app, including spotting trends — and prodding sources to get back to her.",1,"['PERSON', 'LOC']",0.1,0.1,pos,0
307,2019-06-11,A Fake Zuckerberg Video Challenges Facebook’s Rules,"Last month, the social media company would not remove a doctored video of Speaker Nancy Pelosi. Facebook said the video of Mr. Zuckerberg will get the same treatment.",3,"['DATE', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON']",0.0111111111111111,0.0861111111111111,pos,0
308,2022-08-22,McDonald’s Orders a Board Shake-Up,The restaurant chain has made the first big change to its board in three years after seeing off a campaign by the activist investor Carl Icahn.,2,"['ORDINAL', 'DATE', 'PERSON']",0.125,0.2166666666666666,pos,0
309,2017-08-02,Why Apple Is Experiencing Another Growth Spurt,"The company, whose stock hit a record Wednesday, is leaning on the 1.2 billion iPhones it has sold to push other products and services.",3,"['DATE', 'MONEY']",-0.125,0.375,neg,0
310,2022-01-06,"Google Infringed on Sonos Speaker Technology, Trade Court Rules","The company will not be allowed to import products that infringe on Sonos patents, including smart speakers, video streaming devices, and some computers and phones.",1,['ORG'],0.2142857142857142,0.6428571428571429,pos,0
311,2018-05-30,How Technology Is Changing Visual Art,"Minh Uong, a visual editor at The Times, uses both low- and high-tech tools to create editorial art, but tech does not necessarily make it easier to become a professional illustrator.",3,['ORG'],0.025,0.35,pos,0
312,2022-06-21,Meta Agrees to Alter Ad Technology in Settlement With U.S.,"The Justice Department had accused Meta’s housing advertising system of discriminating against Facebook users based on their race, gender, religion and other characteristics.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT']",-0.125,0.375,neg,0
313,2016-12-22,Apple and Nokia Battle Over Cellphone Patents,"While companies like Apple now dominate smartphones, an earlier generation of phone makers like Nokia developed some of the technology.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.05,0.4,pos,0
314,2020-06-29,The New York Times Pulls Out of Apple News,The Times said Apple News did not align with its strategy of building direct relationships with paying readers.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.1,0.4,pos,0
315,2017-03-12,Miscue Calls Attention to Amazon’s Dominance in Cloud Computing,A rare service breakdown has provided an opportunity for rivals like Google and Microsoft to preach the benefits of working with multiple providers.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.15,0.45,pos,0
316,2016-01-22,Amit Singh of Google for Work: A Respectful Clash of Ideas,The president of Google for Work says it’s important to create a culture where people can present diverse points of view.,1,['ORG'],0.2,0.5,pos,0
317,2016-03-04,U.N. Rights Chief Says Unlocking Gunman’s iPhone Could Open ‘Pandora’s Box’,"U.S. officials need to weigh the uncertain benefits against the broader implications of breaching personal security, the high commissioner said.",0,['GPE'],0.08,0.4199999999999999,pos,0
318,2015-01-23,Vice Uses Virtual Reality to Immerse Viewers in News,"The directors Chris Milk and Spike Jonze, in partnership with Vice News, have created an eight-minute virtual-reality experience that catapults audiences into the center of the Millions March protest in New York in December.",3,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'TIME', 'EVENT', 'GPE', 'DATE']",0.0181818181818181,0.2772727272727273,pos,0
319,2018-07-18,E.U. Fines Google $5.1 Billion in Android Antitrust Case,"European officials hit the internet giant with the record penalty for abusing its power in the smartphone market, the region’s latest move to rein in the clout of tech companies.",3,['NORP'],0.1666666666666666,0.6333333333333333,pos,0
320,2017-08-16,Fiat Chrysler Joins BMW in Race to Make Self-Driving Cars,"The alliance, which also includes Intel and Mobileye, could help Fiat Chrysler catch up in new technologies and fend off competitors from Silicon Valley.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
321,2018-11-30,DealBook Briefing: A Dinner Could Make or Break the Trade War,"On the sidelines of the Group of 20 meeting in Buenos Aires, President Trump and President Xi Jinping of China will sit down to a vitally important meal.",0,"['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'GPE']",0.1222222222222222,0.6444444444444445,pos,0
322,2015-05-18,"YouTube Wrongly Forced to Remove Anti-Muslim Movie Trailer, Appeals Court Rules","A ruling reverses a “weak copyright claim” that had forced the website to remove the video on “Innocence of Muslims,” which set off protests in 2012.",2,"['WORK_OF_ART', 'DATE']",-0.3375,0.4125,neg,0
323,2017-01-30,Morning Agenda: Immigration Chaos Spurs Business to the Barricades,"President Trump’s executive order on immigration has sowed chaos and confusion, and driven business leaders — particularly in the tech sector — to move against it.",1,['ORG'],0.1666666666666666,0.3333333333333333,pos,1
324,2017-05-10,Tech’s Frightful Five: They’ve Got Us,"Amazon, Apple, Microsoft, Facebook and Google dominate our day-to-day activities. Imagining being forced to give up some of them could lead to hard choices.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.2958333333333334,0.3708333333333333,neg,0
325,2017-09-05,"Samsung’s Galaxy Note 8: The Best Screen, for a Hefty Price","At nearly $1,000, Samsung’s new device is part of a new category of high-end smartphones with cutting-edge technology. But it has plenty of flaws.",0,"['MONEY', 'ORG']",0.1242424242424242,0.4363636363636363,pos,0
326,2017-04-14,"Amex, Challenged by Chase, Is Losing the Snob War",Amex’s hold on the affluent fantasies of up-and-coming elites is starting to wobble as other credit card companies are beating it at its own game.,3,['ORG'],0.145,0.565,pos,0
327,2015-06-03,Europe’s Next Generation of Venture Capital Funds,A new generation of venture capitalists are betting that their local knowledge and industry expertise can still find the latest start-ups hoping to compete with American rivals.,0,['NORP'],0.1590909090909091,0.3386363636363636,pos,0
328,2017-04-29,Farhad’s and Superior Mike’s Week in Tech: There’s No Flying Car,"The so-called flying car is really a hovercraft, people. Also we chat about net neutrality, earnings and Uber.",0,['ORG'],0.1,0.1,pos,0
329,2022-06-07,"Shell, the Oil Giant, Will Sell Renewable Energy to Texans",The European oil company has been expanding into green energy even as many U.S. energy giants have kept their focus on fossil fuels.,3,"['NORP', 'GPE']",0.0999999999999999,0.2666666666666666,pos,0
330,2016-06-29,Lionsgate Is Said to Be Near Deal to Buy Starz,"If an agreement is reached, it would be the end of a long road for Starz, which has been the subject of merger speculation for three years.",0,"['PERSON', 'DATE']",-0.1083333333333333,0.3666666666666667,neg,0
331,2021-06-10,Google Seeks to Break Vicious Cycle of Online Slander,"In response to Times articles, the search giant is changing its algorithm, part of a major shift in how Google polices harmful content.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.03125,0.75,pos,0
332,2019-03-17,Why a Big Tech Breakup Looks Better to Washington,"Antitrust is the nuclear bomb of regulatory moves, but at a moment when nearly everything in America seems contentious, proposals to break up internet giants are gaining support.",2,['GPE'],0.1,0.4,pos,0
333,2018-07-25,"Waymo Teams Up With Walmart, Avis and Others for Short Driverless Rides",The autonomous vehicle company spun off from Google is offering people in the Phoenix area rides for running errands.,3,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.4,0.7,pos,0
334,2020-08-03,The Strange Saga of TikTok,The chief executive of a big tech company negotiated directly with the U.S. president over an app. Say what?,3,['GPE'],0.05,0.25,pos,0
335,2015-07-21,A $7 Billion Charge at Microsoft Leads to Its Largest Loss Ever,A $7.5 billion accounting charge for the company’s acquisition of Nokia was a drag on the software maker’s fourth-quarter.,3,"['MONEY', 'ORG', 'DATE']",-0.1,0.0708333333333333,neg,0
336,2019-08-20,DealBook Briefing: C.E.O.s Look Beyond Their Shareholders,"The Business Roundtable said companies should also invest in their employees, protect the environment and deal fairly with suppliers — a sign that shareholder democracy hasn’t worked.",2,['ORG'],0.7,0.9,pos,0
337,2016-04-26,"IPhone Sales Drop, and Apple’s 13-Year Surge Ebbs","Revenue fell 13 percent, to $50.6 billion, as sales of the company’s flagship product fell with little else to take its place.",0,"['PERCENT', 'MONEY']",-0.1875,0.5,neg,0
338,2019-10-17,These Apps Are an Uber Driver’s Co-Pilot,"Gridwise, Mystro and others help drivers predict where to get the best routes, and also manage the nitty-gritty for tax purposes.",2,['GPE'],1.0,0.3,pos,0
339,2015-10-19,Daily Report: Tech Tussles Take Center Stage in Earnings,"Tech earnings season is going into full swing, with companies including Yahoo, IBM, Google and Microsoft set to report quarterly results this week. Their financial data may offer insight into which companies are gaining the upper hand in some tech battles.",3,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE']",0.1166666666666666,0.1833333333333333,pos,0
340,2017-05-28,The Future of European Transit: Driverless and Utilitarian,"Across Europe, some fledgling driverless projects are focused on utilitarian self-driving vehicles for mass transit that barely exceed walking pace.",1,['LOC'],0.05,0.1,pos,0
341,2018-05-23,Macron Vowed to Make France a ‘Start-Up Nation.’ Is It Getting There?,"France has quickly become one of the hottest destinations in Europe for technology investment, but it faces big challenges in its mission to become a leader.",0,"['GPE', 'LOC']",0.1666666666666666,0.3,pos,0
342,2017-11-21,Net Neutrality Repeal: What Could Happen and How It Could Affect You,"For you and me, the repeal of net neutrality rules can be boiled down to two questions: What might happen? And who do you trust?",0,['CARDINAL'],-0.0777777777777777,0.1444444444444444,neg,1
343,2016-05-21,Farhad and Mike’s Week in Tech: The Herd Mentality of Tech C.E.O.s,"If one company has a small success, the others pile on, and you get “30 different versions of some dumb wearable.” Also, meet Mike’s flower guy, Guy.",0,"['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']",-0.08125,0.375,neg,0
344,2021-01-09,"A Hong Kong Website Gets Blocked, Raising Censorship Fears","Users of major mobile carriers can no longer access a service that detailed the personal information of police officers, a possible sign that the city is turning to tactics used in mainland China.",3,['GPE'],0.115625,0.6375,pos,0
345,2020-01-21,Davos Warms to Trump’s Results (if Not Him Personally),Many of the elite who gather at the World Economic Forum were horrified by his election. But most seem to have come to accept the U.S. president.,1,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.3999999999999999,0.3999999999999999,pos,0
346,2019-03-26,Europe Adopts Tough New Online Copyright Rules Over Tech Industry Protests,"The strict copyright law will require Google and other technology companies to compensate musicians, authors and news publishers.",3,['ORG'],-0.125,0.375,neg,0
347,2020-07-14,U.K. Bars Huawei for 5G as Tech Battle Between China and the West Escalates,Banning the use of the Chinese tech giant’s equipment in high-speed wireless infrastructure is a major reversal by Prime Minister Boris Johnson — and a big victory for the Trump administration.,3,"['NORP', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.015625,0.4,pos,0
348,2022-03-10,Microsoft’s Pursuit of Climate Goals Runs Into Headwinds,"The company aims to be “carbon negative” by the end of the decade, but its emissions rose sharply in the most recent year measured.",1,"['DATE', 'DATE']",0.135,0.5700000000000001,pos,0
349,2018-12-17,"Facebook, Twitter and YouTube Withheld Russia Data, Reports Say",Reports to the Senate on Russian interference in the 2016 election and beyond criticized the tech companies for failing to disclose important details.,3,"['ORG', 'NORP', 'DATE']",0.2,0.5,pos,1
350,2017-07-02,Pinterest Wants to Show Advertisers It Can Run With the Big Dogs,"The site, which made a splash at Cannes, has 175 million active users and is eager to make its case that its connection to users offers unique potential.",3,"['PRODUCT', 'CARDINAL']",0.0854166666666666,0.65,pos,0
351,2022-04-16,The Battery That Flies,A new aircraft being built in Vermont has no need for jet fuel. It can take off and land without a runway. Amazon and the Air Force are both betting on it. So who will be in the cockpit?,0,"['GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.1363636363636363,0.4545454545454545,pos,0
352,2019-04-04,Condé Nast Selects a Deal-Making Tech Executive as Its New Chief,"The once-cushy publisher of Vogue, The New Yorker and Vanity Fair chose Roger J. Lynch, formerly of Pandora, to steer it through a challenging time.",0,"['GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE']",0.3340909090909091,0.5886363636363636,pos,0
353,2022-02-16,"Google Plans Privacy Changes, but Promises to Not Be Disruptive",It says it will give other companies plenty of time to adapt to changes to its Android software. Similar changes made by Apple affected big internet companies.,1,"['GPE', 'ORG']",-0.0416666666666666,0.2916666666666667,neg,0
354,2022-01-14,"Google’s chief executive signed off on deal at center of antitrust case, states say.",The states argue that Google reached a deal with Facebook to have the social network join its effort in an effort to “kill” a competing ad network.,2,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.0333333333333333,0.0666666666666666,pos,0
355,2018-04-04,"‘Vegan Bodybuilder’: How YouTube Attacker, Nasim Aghdam, Went Viral in Iran","Nasim Najafi Aghdam, the woman who attacked YouTube on Tuesday, had a strong following for her often bizarre videos.",1,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'DATE']",0.2777777777777777,0.4777777777777777,pos,0
356,2017-01-31,Uber Partners With Daimler in a Step Toward a Driverless Future,The move marks the first time a major automaker will provide its own self-driving vehicles specifically to operate on the ride-hailing company’s network.,1,['ORDINAL'],0.3041666666666666,0.611111111111111,pos,0
357,2016-02-04,"Super Bowl Pressure, for Advertisers as Well as Teams","The cost of a 30-second ad is $5 million, and marketers are wrestling with how best to get their money’s worth.",1,"['TIME', 'MONEY']",0.65,0.2,pos,0
358,2015-07-24,The New Stars of the Tech Sector,"James B. Stewart, on CNBC, discusses how chief financial officers like Ruth Porat of Google are bringing new success to technologies companies.",1,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.1454545454545454,0.1515151515151515,pos,0
359,2019-02-01,DealBook Briefing: Trump May Leave Tariffs on China in Place,"The president described negotiations between Washington and Beijing in positive terms but said, “Without the tariffs, we wouldn’t be talking.”",1,"['GPE', 'GPE']",0.2272727272727272,0.5454545454545454,pos,0
360,2018-08-21,"Slack Raises $427 Million More, at $7.1 Billion Valuation",Slack’s appetite for funding and its eye-popping leaps in valuation are becoming normal in the private investment market.,0,['ORG'],0.1999999999999999,0.625,pos,0
361,2016-10-02,"Google, Lagging Amazon, Races Across the Threshold Into the Home","Google is unveiling its answer to Echo, an artificially intelligent home device that vaulted Amazon ahead of Google in a race to build technology that interacts as humans do.",3,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.8,0.9,pos,0
362,2021-07-23,How Tech Won the Pandemic and Now May Never Lose,"As the world reeled, Silicon Valley supplied the tools that made life and work possible. Now tech companies are awash in money — and questions about what it means to win amid so much loss.",1,['LOC'],0.3333333333333333,0.5333333333333333,pos,0
363,2017-10-26,Twitter Says It Overstated Monthly-User Figures for 3 Years,"The disclosure is another blow to the company as it faces scrutiny over how fast it is adding users, its efforts to fight abuse and its role in Russia’s push to meddle in the presidential race.",3,['GPE'],0.2,0.6,pos,0
364,2016-08-09,Chinese Tech Firms Forced to Choose Market: Home or Everywhere Else,The internet filters that keep foreign companies out have created an environment that pens China’s tech firms inside their home country.,3,['GPE'],-0.125,0.125,neg,0
365,2018-12-20,DealBook Briefing: The Fed Raised Rates. The Markets Didn’t Like It.,The central bank has defied critics by increasing rates for a fifth straight quarter. Whether that was a good idea remains to be seen.,1,['DATE'],0.3,0.4166666666666667,pos,0
366,2016-02-08,"For Some Cord Cutters, Streaming Super Bowl Was a Nonstarter",Users complained that a CBS Sports app cut out while they were trying to watch the big game.,2,['ORG'],-0.2333333333333333,0.2333333333333333,neg,0
367,2022-08-03,Taking Stock of Pelosi’s Taiwan Trip,More fallout may be ahead for businesses and investors from a visit that tested China’s appetite for confrontation.,2,['GPE'],0.5,0.5,pos,0
368,2015-09-28,"Facebook and Google, Two Giants in Digital Ads, Seek More","At an advertising industry convention, the digital ad powerhouses Facebook and Google introduced services meant to attract even more digital ad revenue.",2,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",0.1666666666666666,0.1666666666666666,pos,0
369,2016-02-02,"Magic Leap, an Augmented Reality Firm, Raises $793 Million","Magic Leap has drawn attention for attracting investors like Google, Fidelity Investments and Warner Brothers, although it has shown the public little about its products.",3,"['PRODUCT', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.1041666666666666,0.5222222222222223,pos,0
