2015-05-01,DealBook’s Most Popular Stories of 2014,"Investors fleeing emerging markets, Facebook’s deal for WhatsApp and @GSElevator were some of the most popular articles on DealBook in 2014.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'DATE']",0.55,0.7,pos,1,1
2015-05-01,CES: A Push for Higher Resolution and Better-Looking TVs,"The big TV makers, including Samsung and Sony, showed off giant screens with sky-high display resolutions, and in a bid to push ultrahigh definition into the mainstream, several are teaming up with each other and content makers like Netflix.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.03125,0.36875,neg,1,1
2015-06-01,The Year in Market Doublespeak,The last 12 months saw above-average creativity in saying one thing and meaning another. John Foley and Rob Cox of Reuters Breakingviews offer 10 euphemisms they would most like to disappear.,3,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']",0.25,0.2833333333333333,pos,1,1
2015-09-01,Daily Report: Box Seeks to Raise up to $162.5 Million in I.P.O.,"After several delays, Box is finally ready to make its stock market debut.",0,['PERSON'],0.1,0.25,pos,1,1
2015-09-01,"Two Schools of Thought, Adding Up to Success",Three funds that were among the top performers of the fourth quarter of 2014 combined elements of both growth and value investing.,2,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE']",0.25,0.25,pos,1,1
2015-12-01,"Roche to Buy Majority Stake in Foundation Medicine, Leader in Tumor Testing",The Swiss pharmaceutical giant Roche will pay more than $1 billion in a deal aimed at improving both cancer treatment and drug development.,2,"['NORP', 'ORG', 'MONEY']",0.25,0.75,pos,1,0
2015-12-01,PC Market Exited 2014 With a Whimper,"Many people and businesses haven’t found compelling reasons to buy new personal computers in recent years, and PC companies didn’t discover any new gimmicks to change their minds over the holidays.",3,"['DATE', 'DATE']",0.1787878787878788,0.4265151515151515,pos,1,0
2015-12-01,Parents Challenge President to Dig Deeper on Ed Tech,"While President Obama endorsed a voluntary student privacy effort by ed tech companies, some parents seek more comprehensive legislation.",0,['PERSON'],0.5,0.5,pos,1,0
2015-01-14,Bigger Settlement Said to Be Reached in Silicon Valley Antitrust Case,"Apple, Google, Intel and Adobe are said to be offering $415 million to settle accusations that they conspired against their own employees.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'MONEY']",0.6,1.0,pos,0,0
2015-01-14,Daily Report: Tech Giants Said to Offer Bigger Settlement in Antitrust Case on Hiring,"Apple, Google, Intel and Adobe say a new deal has been struck to settle a lawsuit that asserts the companies had agreed not to directly solicit one another’s employees.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.11818181818181818,0.42727272727272725,pos,0,0
2015-01-14,Two Ex-Googlers Reunite at Venture Capital Firm,"Felicis Ventures, a small company (for Silicon Valley) has had some notable investments: Twitch, the video game streaming service that was sold to Amazon, and Rovio, the maker of the Angry Birds video game.",1,"['PERSON', 'LOC', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.21000000000000002,0.5399999999999999,neg,0,0
2015-01-14,Video Feature: Getting the Most Out of Apple iOS 8,"The new operating system can help you monitor battery use better, help take better photos and make Siri easier to use.",2,['PERSON'],0.37878787878787873,0.48484848484848486,pos,0,0
2015-01-14,"In Detroit, Google Makes a Case for Driverless Cars","Google hopes to have fully autonomous vehicles on the road by 2020, taking the driver out of the equation and handing the virtual wheel to software.",3,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.4,0.7,pos,0,0
2015-01-15,Morning Agenda: Profit Slides at Bank of America,Bank of America reports uninspiring fourth-quarter results. | New York’s attorney general seeks expanded reporting on data breaches. | A strategy in the fight over Dodd-Frank. | BlackBerry’s stock goes on a wild ride.,0,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.09545454545454546,0.4515151515151515,pos,0,0
2015-01-15,Google Glass to Leave ‘X’ Research Lab as Nest’s Tony Fadell Takes Over Project,The wearable device will soon be a lot harder to buy as the Glass Explorer program will shut as part of the shift.,2,['ORG'],-0.1,0.0,neg,0,0
2015-01-21,Video Feature: Conjuring the Most From Google Android,"All of these tips work on the latest version of Android, known as Lollipop, but many of them work on the previous version, too.",2,['GPE'],0.2777777777777778,0.5222222222222223,pos,0,0
2015-01-21,"At Windows 10 Event, Microsoft Jumps Into Augmented Reality With HoloLens Headset","The HoloLens could help renew some of the luster Microsoft has lost in the last decade, when it reacted late to critical new technology trends.",3,"['GPE', 'ORG', 'DATE']",-0.04090909090909091,0.48030303030303034,neg,0,0
2015-01-21,Marissa Mayer’s Plan for Yahoo Takes Hold. The Question Now Is Time.,"Marissa Mayer has made sharp acquisitions and rebuilt crucial products, but her future may depend on reaction to her plans for the Alibaba investment.",1,"['PERSON', 'NORP']",-0.041666666666666664,0.625,neg,0,0
2015-01-21,SpaceX Is a Throwback to the 1990s,"Google is investing in Elon Musk’s company, which is planning a broadband network of 4,000 satellites. The pioneering Teledesic tried something similar two decades ago but failed, notes Robert Cyran of Reuters Breakingviews.",3,"['ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.25,0.35,neg,0,0
2015-01-22,Morning Agenda: Goldman Trumps Volcker Rule,Goldman Sachs’s investments are testing the Volcker Rule. | The European Central Bank is expected to announce it will begin its bond-buying program. | Uber closes $1.6 billion in financing from clients of Goldman’s private wealth arm. | Regulators address “too big to fail.”,3,"['ORG', 'FAC', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'MONEY', 'ORG']",-0.09999999999999999,0.23749999999999996,neg,1,0
2015-01-22,"Button, a Mobile Start-Up, Looks to Link Apps With Commerce",The idea is similar to what Google did for search more than a decade ago.,2,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.25,0.45,pos,1,0
2015-01-22,Technology Leaders Define Digital Fault Lines,"Panelists at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, discussed the benefits and challenges of a rapidly changing digital landscape.",2,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']",0.1,0.1,pos,1,0
2015-01-23,Vice Uses Virtual Reality to Immerse Viewers in News,"The directors Chris Milk and Spike Jonze, in partnership with Vice News, have created an eight-minute virtual-reality experience that catapults audiences into the center of the Millions March protest in New York in December.",3,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'TIME', 'EVENT', 'GPE', 'DATE']",0.018181818181818174,0.2772727272727273,pos,1,0
2015-01-23,Online Storage Company Box Has Strong Debut in First Day of Trading,"Shares in the online file storage company closed 66 percent higher than its I.P.O. price, surpassing the $2.4 billion valuation that it fetched in its most recent private financing round.",3,"['PERCENT', 'ORG', 'MONEY']",0.075,0.3541666666666667,pos,1,0
2015-01-26,Price Cuts for Crucial Microsoft Products Eroded Holiday-Season Profit,"The company said the weak personal computer market hurt its Windows business, as second-quarter net income dropped to $5.86 billion from $6.56 billion a year ago.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'MONEY', 'MONEY', 'DATE']",-0.125,0.30833333333333335,neg,0,0
2015-01-27,Twitter Adds Group Messaging and Video Recording,"In an effort to catch up to rival services like Facebook, Twitter will now allow people to shoot, edit and post video directly from its mobile apps. Also, private messages on the service can now be sent to as many as 20 people.",0,"['PRODUCT', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL']",0.19999999999999998,0.425,pos,0,0
2015-01-28,Avoiding Botnets With a Mac,"Windows PCs are often the main targets of malicious software that loops infected computers into remote-controlled networks called botnets, but Macs are not immune.",0,['PERSON'],0.16666666666666666,0.3333333333333333,pos,1,1
2015-01-28,Sony Teams Spotify With PlayStation for Music Streaming Plans,Sony announced that Spotify will effectively replace Music Unlimited this spring in 41 countries.,3,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.6,0.8,pos,1,1
2015-01-29,Morning Agenda: Yahoo as Takeover Target,Spinning off its stake in Alibaba may make Yahoo a takeover target. |Deutsche Bank swings to profit. | McDonald’s replaces its chief executive. | A push for a greater government role in housing finance.,3,"['GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.5,0.5,pos,0,0
2015-01-29,F.C.C. Sharply Revises Definition of Broadband,The new broadband benchmark sets downloads at a speed of 25 megabits per second and uploads of 3 megabits per second. The standard is used to guide policy in some areas.,3,"['CARDINAL', 'ORDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORDINAL']",0.03409090909090909,0.11363636363636363,pos,0,0
2015-01-29,Reddit Issues First Transparency Report,The popular message board gives insight into how often government agencies request data on Reddit users.,0,['NORP'],0.6,0.9,pos,0,0
2015-01-30,Morning Agenda: Crackdown on Car Title Loans,Car title loans are drawing scrutiny from regulators. | Law firm founds a project to fight “revenge porn.” | Shake Shack is going public with big dreams. | How Apple beat Microsoft.,3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.06666666666666667,0.18888888888888888,neg,0,0
2015-02-02,"In Net Neutrality Push, F.C.C. Is Expected to Propose Regulating Internet Service as a Utility","Tom Wheeler, chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, is expected to propose reclassifying high-speed Internet as a telecommunications service.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.1,0.4,neg,1,0
2015-02-02,Uber to Open Center for Research on Self-Driving Cars,"The ride-hailing service is partnering with Carnegie Mellon University, a hotbed for research in robotics and other artificial intelligence.",3,['ORG'],-0.3625,0.6875,neg,1,0
2015-03-02,Obama’s Budget Seeks International Minimum Tax for Corporations,"A tax on foreign earnings trapped overseas is best thought of as a jobs-friendly international minimum tax, writes Victor Fleischer in the Standard Deduction column.",3,['PERSON'],0.135,0.08499999999999999,pos,1,1
2015-09-02,Morning Agenda: U.S. Takes On Payday Lenders,The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau seeks to limit payday lenders. | The prime minister of Greece says he will carry out his campaign to roll back austerity. | Hidden cash is flowing into high-end real estate. | Shares of HSBC fall on tax avoidance claims.,3,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.008333333333333338,0.15833333333333333,pos,0,0
2015-10-02,Yelp Pays $134 Million for Food-Ordering Service,"The move is a departure for Yelp, whose main business has been selling advertising bought by local businesses with those reviews.",3,['ORG'],0.08333333333333333,0.16666666666666666,pos,0,0
2015-11-02,Survey of Foreign Companies in China Finds Pollution a Growing Problem,The report by the American Chamber of Commerce reflects on-the-ground attitudes that large Chinese cities have become less hospitable places to work.,1,"['ORG', 'NORP']",0.011904761904761904,0.1238095238095238,pos,0,0
2015-11-02,Twitter’s Chief Sees Plenty of Money in Tweet Flow,"Dick Costolo, chief executive of the social network, sketched out his plans for bringing in new revenue, from showing more ads in the feeds of Twitter users to helping brands hire popular users to create sponsored video content.",2,"['PERSON', 'PERSON']",0.3174242424242424,0.48030303030303034,pos,0,0
2015-12-02,"Aiming to Ease App Discovery, Apple Pairs With Pinterest","App Pins aims to do for smartphone apps what Pinterest’s service has done for photos, recipes and many other types of websites. In short, the service is a type of digital corkboard that lets visitors save, or “pin,” items they like or places they want to go.",0,['PERSON'],0.09375,0.29375,pos,1,1
2015-02-13,Daily Report: Obama Heads to Security Talks Amid Tensions,A long history of quiet cooperation between Washington and America’s top technology companies has been shattered by tension over the government’s use of technology companies for its intelligence purposes.,3,"['GPE', 'GPE']",0.15,0.41111111111111115,pos,0,0
2015-02-13,Morning Agenda: Standoff Over Greek Debt,All sides in the negotiations on Greek debt are betting others will blink first. | Lyft is is talks to raise about $250 million. | Expedia agrees to buy Orbitz. | Law schools are adding business-related offerings.,0,"['NORP', 'ORDINAL', 'MONEY', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.125,0.16666666666666666,pos,0,0
2015-02-13,"China’s Internet Restrictions Are Hampering Business, Foreign Companies Say","Businesses are growing increasingly frustrated by obstacles to Internet access, according to a survey by the European Union Chamber of Commerce in China.",3,"['ORG', 'GPE']",-0.25,0.06666666666666667,neg,0,0
2015-02-18,Photoshop at 25: A Thriving Chameleon Adapts to an Instagram World,"Adobe, which introduced the image-editing program in 1990, has moved to a less expensive subscription-based model in an effort to democratize access.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE']",-0.3333333333333333,0.3833333333333333,neg,0,0
2015-02-18,Microsoft Has Suddenly Gotten Serious With Mobile,"There’s a new strategy afoot at the company, which has brought apps and services to the Apple and Android devices people actually use, rather than ones that run Windows.",2,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.06818181818181818,0.2772727272727273,pos,0,0
2015-02-19,Daily Report: Microsoft Zeroes In on Mobile,"There’s a new strategy afoot at the company, which has brought apps and services to the Apple and Android devices people actually use, rather than ones that run Windows.",2,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.06818181818181818,0.2772727272727273,pos,0,0
2015-02-19,Yahoo Courts Mobile App Makers with New Tools,"Building on its acquisition of the start-up Flurry last year, the Internet company is seeking to broaden its influence with mobile application developers by offering them better analytic and advertising services.",0,"['GPE', 'DATE']",0.25,0.2833333333333333,pos,0,0
2015-02-19,F.D.A. Reverses Course on 23andMe DNA Test in Move to Ease Restrictions,The agency approved a test that would be administered to parents to see if they carry mutations that could cause a rare disorder called Bloom syndrome in their children.,3,['PRODUCT'],0.3,0.9,pos,0,0
2015-02-23,IBM Tries to Paint the Computing Cloud Blue,"IBM is going deeper in the plan of its chief, Virginia Rometty, to rebuild the computing giant as a cloud company. At a giant show in Las Vegas, the company announced new kinds of security and services for cloud applications, along with data centers in new countries.",0,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE']",0.06818181818181818,0.7272727272727273,pos,0,0
2015-02-23,Google Guns for Apple in Mobile Payments Race,The use of so-called proximity payment services is expected to accelerate in the coming year and Google isn’t ready to cede the market to companies like Apple and Samsung.,0,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.05,0.45,pos,0,0
2015-02-24,Tough Talk From European Commissioner About U.S. Tech Companies,"Günther Oettinger, the European Commission member in charge of the digital economy, said that if companies did not comply with European data rules, they “ultimately, perhaps, may be thrown out of the single market.”",2,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'NORP']",-0.014285714285714285,0.24285714285714283,neg,1,1
2015-02-25,A Google Computer Can Teach Itself Games,"A team at Google has developed a way a computer can sense inputs, learn rules and successfully play a number of classic video games. That’s a step up from the Jeopardy!-winning Watson, which was taught rules.",2,['ORG'],0.33888888888888885,0.47222222222222227,pos,1,0
2015-02-25,Privacy Group Files F.T.C. Complaint Against Samsung’s Voice-Operated TVs,The Electronic Privacy Information Center accused Samsung of violating federal laws with a technology that allows viewers to operate the company’s Internet-connected smart TVs with voice commands.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.057142857142857134,0.37142857142857144,pos,1,0
2015-02-26,"F.C.C. Approves Net Neutrality Rules, Classifying Broadband Internet Service as a Utility","The agency’s 3-2 vote is intended to ensure a level playing field for Internet content providers, with no so-called pay-to-play fast lanes.",1,['CARDINAL'],0.2,0.6,pos,1,0
2015-02-26,Will.i.am Start-Up Hires Sony Electronics Executive,"Phil Molyneux, who most recently was president and chief operating officer of Sony Electronics in the United States, will take on the same role at i.am+, a 60-person wearables start-up.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL']",0.16666666666666666,0.2916666666666667,pos,1,0
2015-02-26,"Amazon Hires Jay Carney, Former Obama Press Secretary","Amazon has hired Mr. Carney as senior vice president for global corporate affairs. The move is unusual, as Amazon is known for grooming employees from within.",3,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.06666666666666667,0.3333333333333333,pos,1,0
2015-02-27,"At Aetna, a C.E.O.’s Management by Mantra","Mark Bertolini, the chief executive of Aetna, is betting that bringing yoga, meditation and higher wages to his employees will be good business.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",0.475,0.55,pos,1,0
2015-02-27,Google Unveils Plan for New Corporate Campus,Google unveiled a radical proposal for a new campus that would replace its current headquarters in Mountain View.,3,"['ORG', 'GPE']",0.06818181818181818,0.42727272727272725,pos,1,0
2015-02-03,Microsoft Presents Low-Cost Phones and Windows 10 for Mobile,"At the Mobile World Congress, the company for the first time showed off the operating system for phones and continued its evolving strategy of delivering low-cost Lumia devices.",2,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG']",0.25,0.3333333333333333,pos,0,0
2015-02-03,"Daily Report: The Apple Watch Is Nearly Ready, but Is the Public?","The Apple Watch is scheduled to start selling in April, but will buyers want it? While consumers have shown little interest in smartwatches so far, few people wanted tablets or smartphones before the iPad and iPhone were released.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.09583333333333333,0.5333333333333333,neg,0,0
2015-02-03,Mark Zuckerberg Goes on Charm Offensive for Internet.org,"The chief of Facebook outlined why he thinks Internet.org, a service to provide people in emerging markets with free access to some online applications, would help telecommunications carriers persuade customers to spend more on streaming content to their cellphones.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.45,0.65,pos,0,0
2015-03-03,Nextdoor Social Network Digs Deep Into Neighborhoods,"The start-up and its investors see opportunities in the company’s more than 53,000 microcommunities.",3,['CARDINAL'],0.5,0.5,pos,1,1
2015-06-03,Troubleshooting Android in Safe Mode,Third-party apps and recent operating system updates are often the cause; starting the phone in Safe Mode can help narrow down the search for a culprit.,2,['PERSON'],0.02888888888888888,0.3077777777777778,pos,0,0
2015-11-03,Google Offers Cheap Storage for Certain Kinds of Data,"Google just matched Amazon for cheap online storage, with an important difference: While Amazon promises to fetch the cheap data in hours, Google offers to do it in three seconds.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'TIME', 'ORG', 'TIME']",0.32500000000000007,0.6,pos,1,0
2015-11-03,Review: Google Chromebook Pixel,"The top-of-the-line Google laptop, back in a new version, is meant more as a testing ground for new technology than a mass-market product.",3,['ORG'],0.19318181818181818,0.3522727272727273,pos,1,0
2015-11-03,Utah Passes White-Collar Felon Registry,"The Utah Legislature has approved legislation to build the nation’s first white-collar offender registry, affixing a scarlet letter of sorts on the state’s financial felons.",3,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL']",0.125,0.16666666666666666,pos,1,0
2015-12-03,Zuckerberg Lawsuit Documents Show Animosity With Would-Be Neighbor,Documents filed Wednesday accuse the Facebook chief executive of reneging on a promise to introduce a would-be neighbor to powerful Silicon Valley friends.,3,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.3,1.0,pos,1,1
2015-03-17,Recent Commercial Transactions,"Notable properties that have been recently listed for sale, sold or leased in New York City.",3,['GPE'],0.21212121212121213,0.40151515151515155,pos,0,0
2015-03-18,"Suddenly, Plenty of Options for Cord Cutters","Here are some prominent services offering live TV, à la carte networks and other on-demand streaming options in the United States.",3,['GPE'],0.17045454545454544,0.625,pos,1,1
2015-03-18,Microsoft Backs Further Away From Selling Software,"Microsoft’s move to make Windows 10 upgrades free in China echoes a shift at the company and the software industry’s around the world. The days of charging customers for an operating system are slowly coming to an end, piece by piece.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'DATE']",0.04999999999999999,0.6,pos,1,1
2015-03-19,Elon Musk Says Self-Driving Tesla Cars Will Be in the U.S. by Summer,The automaker’s chief executive says a software update will allow the Model S to navigate highways without the driver’s touching the wheel or pedals. But is it legal?,0,['FAC'],0.35,0.35,pos,1,1
2015-03-19,"Take Google to Court, Staff Report Urged F.T.C.",An internal Federal Trade Commission report recommended that the agency take action against Google for anticompetitive practices. The F.T.C. voted not to bring charges.,0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.05,0.05,pos,1,1
2015-03-20,European Lawmaker Pushes Europe to Take Stronger Stance on Google,"The antitrust case against Google in Europe has already gained more traction than in the United States. But like their American counterparts, competition officials at the European Commission in Brussels have been loath to bring formal charges against such a successful and powerful company.",3,"['ORG', 'LOC', 'GPE', 'NORP', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.25833333333333336,0.4916666666666667,pos,1,1
2015-03-20,A Real-Time Peek at Traffic to U.S. Government Websites,"This week, the federal government unveiled a new tool that makes public the user analytics for many government websites.",0,['DATE'],0.21212121212121213,0.34040404040404043,pos,1,1
2015-03-23,Restoring the iCloud Drive Icon,"With a few steps, the icon — and any other deleted icon on a Mac — can be brought back. Also, why Windows sometimes must restart when updating.",0,['PERSON'],-0.10833333333333334,0.15833333333333333,neg,1,1
2015-03-23,Microsoft Partners With Android Makers in Its Latest Mobile Push,"Microsoft is serious about making its most lucrative business, Office, relevant for mobile users. What is less clear is how much money it will be able to make from them.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.17142857142857143,0.4773809523809524,pos,1,1
2015-03-23,Google Fiber Plans Experiment With Targeted Ads for Television,"While Google Fiber is growing fast, it is still minuscule compared with its traditional rivals. But it shows the potential for delivering specific kinds of ads to local markets.",3,['ORG'],0.04,0.495,pos,1,1
2015-03-24,Google Hires Finance Chief Ruth Porat From Morgan Stanley,"Ms. Porat, who has been Morgan Stanley’s chief financial officer since 2010, will become one of the most powerful women in Silicon Valley.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'LOC']",0.26666666666666666,0.5,pos,0,0
2015-03-24,Slack Said to Be in Talks to Raise Money at More Than $2 Billion Valuation,"The talks come just four months after Slack, which is run by the entrepreneur Stewart Butterfield, raised $120 million at a valuation of more than $1 billion.",2,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'MONEY', 'MONEY']",0.5,0.5,pos,0,0
2015-03-24,Google Should Feel Lucky in Its Finance Chief Hire,"The challenge for both Wall Street and Silicon Valley is to create more women like Ruth Porat, with financial, tech and government know-how.",3,"['LOC', 'PERSON']",0.25,0.25,pos,0,0
2015-03-24,YouTube’s ‘Sunshine Girl’ Comes to Print,"Paige McKenzie, known for her mockumentary web series “The Haunting of Sunshine Girl,” is trying to extend her brand with a series of young adult novels.",1,"['PERSON', 'WORK_OF_ART']",0.1,0.35,pos,0,0
2015-03-24,Wall St. Stars Join Silicon Valley Gold Rush,"Ruth Porat, Morgan Stanley’s chief financial officer, is leaving for Google in the most visible example yet of the flow of talent from Wall Street to Silicon Valley.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.25,0.25,pos,0,0
2015-03-25,Daily Report: Trying to Sway the Jury in Kleiner Perkins Discrimination Trial,"In closing arguments on Tuesday, top litigators from both sides presented their cases in the gender discrimination trial against Kleiner Perkins.",0,"['DATE', 'PERSON']",0.5,0.5,pos,1,1
2015-03-25,Parrying the Latest Predictions of Facebook’s Demise,A theory making the rounds in Silicon Valley warns that Facebook relies too heavily on app ads from start-ups inflated by venture capital. But the threat is overblown.,3,['LOC'],-0.2,0.5,neg,1,1
2015-03-25,F.T.C. Addresses Its Choice Not to Sue Google,The agency issued a rare statement defending its choice not to take legal action after investigating Google for anticompetitive behavior in 2011 and 2012.,0,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE']",0.19999999999999998,0.4000000000000001,pos,1,1
2015-03-26,Facebook’s Yann LeCun Discusses Digital Companions and Artificial Intelligence (and Emotions),"The head of Facebook’s Artificial Intelligence Lab foresees a day when we all have artificial helpers that understand us, all of the information in the world, and what we need to know next.",3,['ORG'],-0.39999999999999997,0.6666666666666666,neg,0,0
2015-03-26,"New Google C.F.O. Gets $70 Million Pay Package (and $7,500 to Move)",Google’s new financial chief will join the search giant in May after a long career at Morgan Stanley.,3,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG']",0.021590909090909088,0.4636363636363636,pos,0,0
2015-03-27,Google and Johnson & Johnson Team for Robotic Surgery Projects,Google and Johnson & Johnson announced a partnership to develop new robot-assisted surgery technologies but offered few details.,3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",-0.03181818181818183,0.2772727272727273,neg,0,0
2015-03-31,"Investing Early On for Insights, Not Profits","BBVA, the global Spanish bank, has established a venture capital fund in Silicon Valley that is more interested in fruitful partnerships than profits.",0,"['ORG', 'NORP', 'LOC']",0.1875,0.25,pos,0,0
2015-02-04,Uber Hires a Security Chief From Facebook,"Joe Sullivan, the ride-hailing company’s new chief security officer, will work in areas like securing driver data, and driver and passenger safety.",3,['PERSON'],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,0,0
2015-06-04,ZenPayroll Start-Up Raises $60 Million From Group Led by Google Investment Arm,"The funding round valued the payroll processor, which was created in 2012, at $500 million.",0,"['DATE', 'MONEY']",-0.2,0.4,neg,0,0
2015-08-04,Dear Diary: My Week Wearing an Apple Watch,"Spending seven days learning to use, and getting used to, the Apple Watch proved to be a mostly rewarding experience.",2,"['DATE', 'ORG']",0.5,1.0,pos,0,0
2015-08-04,Amazon Web Services Takes Fuller Aim at Enterprise Computing,AWS kicked off the first of 16 meetings with a daylong direct assault on the existing corporate computing business. The Seattle-based cloud giant is now offering features and services for so-called hybrid clouds.,0,"['ORDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE']",0.0875,0.43333333333333335,pos,0,0
2015-09-04,The Must-Attend Event for Education Technology Investors,The annual ASU+GSV Summit has become the central event for investors and companies scouting for the next big thing in ed tech — a melting pot for executives from a wide range of companies.,0,['DATE'],-0.025,0.1875,neg,0,0
2015-09-04,Amazon to Sell Predictions in Cloud Race Against Google and Microsoft,"Amazon Web Services, the world’s biggest cloud company, is now selling cheap data analysis and prediction. It’s likely to get baked into all kinds of applications, bringing pain to the old guard.",0,['ORG'],0.16666666666666666,0.6333333333333333,pos,0,0
2015-12-04,Formal Charges May Be Next in Europe’s Google Antitrust Inquiry,"Margrethe Vestager, Europe’s antitrust regulator, is expected to change course with her predecessor and file charges that could hasten a settlement.",2,['LOC'],-0.1,0.4,neg,1,1
2015-04-14,Google Expected to Face Antitrust Charges in Europe,"Europe’s antitrust chief is expected to accuse the search giant of using its dominant position to favor its own services, a case that could force a change in its practices.",3,['LOC'],0.16666666666666666,0.7999999999999999,pos,1,0
2015-04-15,Nokia Agrees to $16.6 Billion Takeover of Alcatel-Lucent,The combined company is expected to become the world’s second-largest telecom equipment manufacturer behind Ericsson of Sweden.,2,"['ORDINAL', 'GPE']",-0.25,0.55,neg,1,1
2015-04-15,Case Against Google May Be Undercut by Rapid Changes in Technology,"As the antitrust case against Microsoft showed, the giants that look most unbeatable can falter in ways that have nothing to do with the actions of government regulators.",3,['ORG'],0.5,0.5,pos,1,1
2015-04-16,Cycling Start-Up Peloton Raises $30 Million,The new round of funding is the latest sign of interest in Peloton’s bikes — sleek black spinning cycles with customized tablet displays.,3,['ORG'],0.06742424242424241,0.5469696969696969,pos,0,0
2015-04-16,A Yale Graduate Leaves a Trail of Ventures and Debts,"Joshua Bryce Newman seems to fit the part of the young, successful entrepreneur. But the lawsuits filed against him paint a different picture.",0,['PERSON'],0.3125,0.5875,pos,0,0
2015-04-22,Backers Say USB-C Is the Cable of the Future,"A successor to the USB connector, it is smaller to work with thinner devices, and it is designed to handle high speeds for data transfers and lots of power.",0,['ORG'],0.08,0.52,pos,0,0
2015-04-22,Google Introduces Wireless Service Called Project Fi,"The service aims to blend several communication tools — cellular calls, online calls like Skype — into a single phone number and service.",3,['ORG'],-0.03571428571428571,0.10714285714285714,neg,0,0
2015-04-22,"Facebook’s Growth Slows Slightly, but Mobile Shift Intensifies",The company said that three-quarters of its first-quarter ad revenue and most of its visitors came from mobile devices.,0,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE']",0.5,0.5,pos,0,0
2015-04-24,Google’s Eric Schmidt Plays the Adult in D.E. Shaw Investment,"The Google executive chairman makes a big bet that is far afield from the frivolity of, say, a sports team investment like Steve Ballmer’s.",1,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.05,0.55,pos,0,0
2015-04-27,Facebook Adds Free Video Calls to Messenger App,"The social networking company has allowed free voice calls on its Messenger app for about two years, but now it is adding video calling, matching a key feature offered by rivals.",2,"['PRODUCT', 'DATE']",0.14444444444444446,0.6222222222222222,pos,1,0
2015-04-27,"Apple’s Earnings Surge, as iPhone Sales Jump and China Business Rises","More than one-quarter of the company’s revenue last quarter came from China, which is becoming an increasingly vital part of Apple’s business.",3,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.2625,0.4541666666666667,pos,1,0
2015-04-27,"Twitter’s Dick Costolo Delivers on Change, but the Right Mix Remains Elusive",Twitter has introduced new features but continues to wrestle with an old problem: how to help new users enjoy the best of the service.,3,['PERSON'],0.35454545454545455,0.38181818181818183,pos,1,0
2015-04-29,Google Tripled Spending on Lobbying in Brussels Last Year,"The company multiplied its spending by three from 2010 to 2013, and again in 2014, spending at least $4.2 million and as much as $4.8 million last year, according to its latest disclosure report.",2,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'MONEY', 'MONEY', 'DATE']",0.1,0.3916666666666667,pos,0,0
2015-04-29,Microsoft Takes Steps to Close Its App Gap on Mobile Devices,Microsoft has steadily lost influence in the technology industry as software developers gravitated to mobile technologies like Google’s Android and Apple’s iOS.,0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.16666666666666666,0.5,pos,0,0
2015-04-29,Twitter’s Costolo on Earnings,"CNBC interviews Dick Costolo, chief of Twitter, who discusses the company’s earnings, which were released early and missed expectations, as well as Twitter’s new ad partnership with Google.",3,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.11818181818181818,0.37727272727272726,pos,0,0
2015-04-29,"A Founder of Secret, the Anonymous Social App, Is Shutting It Down",Secret’s rapid rise and fall illustrates the flash-in-the-pan nature of Silicon Valley’s current technology boom.,3,['LOC'],-0.2,0.55,neg,0,0
2015-04-29,Twitter Troubles Lie in Marketers’ Reluctance to Buy New Kind of Ad,Twitter’s shares have been punished since it reported its earnings because advertisers and investors are having trouble figuring it out.,2,['PERSON'],-0.2,0.2,neg,0,0
2015-04-30,"Microsoft (Yes, Microsoft) Has a Far-Out Vision","The reshaped Microsoft that Satya Nadella, the new chief executive, envisions has fewer internal fiefs and is more willing to favor big bets on new technologies over protecting legacy cash cows.",3,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.17045454545454544,0.3765151515151515,pos,1,1
2015-01-05,What an Android Update May Get You,"An Android update may be particularly helpful to users of Nexus 7 tablets, and resources on the web can give users an idea of what to expect.",2,"['GPE', 'CARDINAL']",0.16666666666666666,0.3333333333333333,pos,1,0
2015-01-05,The Rise of Emoji on Instagram Is Causing Language Repercussions,The use of emoji — the collection of happy faces and other images that can be used to communicate feelings and sentiments — has become so pervasive on Instagram that the use of Internet slang formed from letters has decreased.,1,['ORG'],0.09166666666666667,0.6916666666666668,pos,1,0
2015-01-05,"Tidal, Music Streaming Service, Seeks Footing After a Stumble","Music and technology executives say that it is far too early to judge Tidal, particularly given the expected arrival of Apple’s new streaming service.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",0.08060606060606061,0.49757575757575756,pos,1,0
2015-02-05,"Dave Goldberg, Half of a Silicon Valley Power Couple, Dies at 47","Mr. Goldberg was a serial Silicon Valley entrepreneur and venture capitalist who was married to Sheryl Sandberg, the chief operating officer of Facebook.",3,"['PERSON', 'LOC', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.25,0.25,pos,0,0
2015-03-05,"40 Busy Years Later, Paul Allen, a Microsoft Founder, Considers His Creation","Paul Allen, who founded Microsoft with Bill Gates 40 years ago, says the most daunting task the company faces is getting momentum in the mobile market.",0,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'DATE']",0.5,0.5,pos,1,1
2015-05-05,"European Union Delays Action on Apple, Amazon and Starbucks Tax Inquiries","The competition commissioner, who took office in November and did not set new deadlines, cited difficulties in obtaining information.",3,['DATE'],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,1,1
2015-05-05,Snapping the Windows Screen,"How to take screenshots on a Windows tablet, Also, how to use iPhoto after the latest Mac update replaces it with a different app.",2,['ORG'],0.25,0.75,pos,1,1
2015-05-05,The Lessons Google Ventures Learned From Secret,Bill Maris of Google Ventures explains why the firm was only willing to invest in the start-up Secret up to a point.,0,"['PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.08750000000000001,0.7124999999999999,neg,1,1
2015-08-05,Daily Report: Facebook Use Polarizing? Site Begs to Differ,"Almost 29 percent of the news stories displayed by Facebook’s News Feed present views that conflict with the user’s own ideology, the study found.",3,"['PERCENT', 'ORG']",0.3,0.5,pos,1,1
2015-08-05,"Spotify’s Revenue Is Growing, but So Are Its Losses","The music streaming service said $197 million in losses in 2014 were the result of product development, international expansion and new personnel.",3,"['MONEY', 'DATE']",0.06818181818181818,0.22727272727272727,pos,1,1
2015-11-05,Chinese Smartphone Makers Try to Make Inroads in India,"As domestic sales slow and the country’s economy cools, China turns to the much smaller but fast-growing market in India.",2,"['GPE', 'GPE']",-0.10000000000000002,0.3333333333333333,neg,1,0
2015-05-13,White House and Labor Advocates Praise Move by Facebook for Higher Wages,Facebook announced on Tuesday that it would require its contractors and vendors to provide better benefits and a minimum hourly wage of $15.,3,"['DATE', 'TIME', 'MONEY']",0.5,0.5,pos,1,1
2015-05-13,Verizon’s Deal for AOL Is a Push Into the Technology of Advertising,"In a merger with Verizon, AOL would gain a wealth of consumer data that it could use to personalize and target marketing messages. Others are skeptical of the effort.",2,"['GPE', 'ORG']",-0.5,0.5,neg,1,1
2015-05-13,Verizon Takes to the Battlefield,"Verizon’s deal to buy AOL, which barely registers in financial terms, may be the signature transaction that vanquishes all perceptions of the company as a stodgy utility.",2,"['GPE', 'ORG']",0.025,0.05,pos,1,1
2015-05-14,Rdio Introduces a Cheaper Limited Subscription for Music Streaming,"The new service, Rdio Select, will cost $4 a month, significantly lower than the industry’s $10 standard price.",3,"['PERSON', 'MONEY', 'MONEY']",0.17045454545454544,0.4431818181818182,pos,1,0
2015-05-18,"Daily Report: Kijiji, the Craigslist of Canada, Run by eBay","The eBay-owned website, whose name means “village” in Swahili, attracts three times as many users in Canada as Craigslist, which dominates in the United States.",2,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'NORP', 'GPE']",0.5,0.5,pos,0,0
2015-05-18,"YouTube Wrongly Forced to Remove Anti-Muslim Movie Trailer, Appeals Court Rules","A ruling reverses a “weak copyright claim” that had forced the website to remove the video on “Innocence of Muslims,” which set off protests in 2012.",1,"['WORK_OF_ART', 'DATE']",-0.3375,0.4125,neg,0,0
2015-05-19,Tech Giants Urge Obama to Reject Policies That Weaken Encryption,"A group of prominent technology companies, including Google and Apple, have sent a letter to President Obama asking him to reject any proposals that would weaken their products’ security.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON']",0.5,1.0,pos,1,0
2015-05-20,"A Tech Boom Aimed at the Few, Instead of the World","The industry once thought big, but today’s wave of start-ups is characterized by a rise in services aimed at the wealthy and the young.",0,['DATE'],0.19999999999999998,0.5,pos,0,0
2015-05-20,Minecraft Stars on YouTube Share Secrets to Their Celebrity,"A group of gamers act as solo tour guides for millions of Minecraft players, gradually creating their own genre of entertainment.",3,"['CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.6,1.0,pos,0,0
2015-05-26,"Daily Report: As Facebook Sweeps Across Europe, Regulators Gird for Battle",The European Court of Justice is expected to issue a preliminary decision over whether the social network giant can continue transferring data between Europe and the United States.,2,"['ORG', 'LOC', 'GPE']",-0.01666666666666667,0.3666666666666667,neg,1,1
2015-03-06,Yahoo Wins Rights to Live Stream Bills-Jaguars N.F.L. Game,"The company said that it had struck a deal with the National Football League to host the first free, live global webcast of a regular-season game, which will be played in London on Oct. 25.",3,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'GPE', 'DATE']",0.07727272727272727,0.4066666666666666,pos,1,1
2015-03-06,Europe’s Next Generation of Venture Capital Funds,A new generation of venture capitalists are betting that their local knowledge and industry expertise can still find the latest start-ups hoping to compete with American rivals.,3,['NORP'],0.1590909090909091,0.3386363636363636,pos,1,1
2015-03-06,Changing the Look of Excel,"Microsoft Excel provides for changes in the typeface, point size and other characteristics of files that a user creates.",0,['ORG'],-0.125,0.375,neg,1,1
2015-03-06,Computer Scientists Are Astir After Baidu Team Is Barred From A.I. Competition,The team from China’s leading search engine was disqualified when it was discovered it had broken rules in a way that could give it an advantage in the competition.,2,['GPE'],-0.4,0.4,neg,1,1
2015-04-06,Sacca’s Tweaks for Twitter,"In a recent note, Chris Sacca, a former Google employee and early investor in Twitter, criticizes the social media company and recommends changes.",2,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.03333333333333333,0.15416666666666667,pos,0,0
2015-04-06,Beware a Bluff From Dish’s Poker-Playing Boss,Charles Ergen would be making a bold bet by merging his satellite operator with T-Mobile US. Yet he is also known for playing his cards very carefully.,2,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE']",0.10166666666666666,0.8333333333333333,pos,0,0
2015-05-06,Selling E-Commerce While Avoiding Amazon,Amazon is by far the largest e-commerce player. Six hundred smaller fry gathered in Chicago this week to work out strategies for competing against or even cooperating with the Seattle giant.,2,"['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'GPE']",0.03333333333333333,0.8333333333333334,pos,0,0
2015-07-06,"HackerOne Connects Hackers With Companies, and Hopes for a Win-Win","HackerOne’s co-founders are betting they can persuade the world’s hackers to spend their free time solving security’s problems, not causing them, and that businesses will pay them a bounty for their service.",0,['ORG'],0.4,0.8,pos,0,0
2015-08-06,Square Unveils Mobile Wallet-Friendly Credit Card Reader,Square announced a new credit card reader that accepts mobile wallets like Apple Pay.,1,['ORG'],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,1,1
2015-08-06,"Looking for Robots That Will Cooperate, Not Terminate",A Darpa robotic competition in California focused on machines that can perform ordinary tasks that were the furthest thing from the killer automatons of science fiction.,3,"['ORG', 'GPE']",-0.175,0.35,neg,1,1
2015-10-06,"Gemvara, an Online Jeweler, Branches Into Resetting","The five-year-old custom jewelry design company began the service in January, to overwhelming demand.",0,"['DATE', 'DATE']",0.5,1.0,pos,0,0
2015-10-06,What Apple’s Tim Cook Overlooked in His Defense of Privacy,"When Apple’s chief executive gave a speech on the tech industry’s privacy practices, he failed to fairly explore the benefits of free, ad-supported services.",0,['ORG'],0.19999999999999998,0.6666666666666666,pos,0,0
2015-10-06,Britain Offers Itself as a Proving Ground,"With support from the British government, three pilot projects have started to test the rules and develop the hardware for autonomous vehicles.",2,"['NORP', 'CARDINAL']",0.2,0.35,pos,0,0
2015-11-06,"Top Executive at Kleiner Perkins to Make Rare Silicon Valley Shift, to Menlo Ventures","Matt Murphy, who had close connections to Google and other prominent tech investments, is joining Menlo Ventures as a managing director.",0,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.1875,0.6875,pos,0,0
2015-11-06,Kevin Rose Moves On From Silicon Valley to Watches,"Kevin Rose, a founder of Digg and a longtime Silicon Valley entrepreneur, is moving across the country to become chief executive of a venture dedicated to wristwatches.",3,"['PERSON', 'GPE', 'LOC']",0.6,0.95,pos,0,0
2015-11-06,Daily Report: Google Sets Its Sights on Improving City Life,"Google’s new venture, Sidewalk Labs, will pursue technologies to cut pollution, curb energy use, streamline transportation and reduce the cost of urban living.",3,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",0.06818181818181818,0.22727272727272727,pos,0,0
2015-06-15,IBM Invests to Help Open-Source Big Data Software — and Itself,"IBM plans to invest heavily in accelerating the adoption of the open-source big data software, Spark. With the move, IBM is investing as much in its own future as in the open-source project.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.12,0.385,pos,0,0
2015-06-15,Companies Move On From Big Data Technology Hadoop,"If you’re up on big data, you’ve heard of something called Hadoop. It may be worth billions, but some of Hadoop’s biggest backers look like they are moving on from it.",3,"['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.15,0.1,pos,0,0
2015-06-18,"In Report on Data Collection Practices, WhatsApp and AT&T Fail the Test","In a report about data privacy published by the Electronic Frontier Foundation this week, tech companies like Yahoo, Apple and Adobe earned top marks, while WhatsApp and AT&T came in last.",0,"['ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.25,0.2833333333333333,pos,1,1
2015-06-18,New Rules Let Companies Sell Stakes to Investors of Modest Means,"Complex and controversial, the regulatory change allows businesses to advertise their offerings online, giving fans a chance to buy shares.",1,['PRODUCT'],0.12500000000000003,0.675,pos,1,1
2015-06-19,Google to Remove ‘Revenge Porn’ Images From Search Results,"If Google deems an image revenge porn, it will still be accessible to someone who knows the direct web address of the image. But once delisted from Google, the image could not be found through the search engine.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.2375,0.3875,pos,1,1
2015-06-19,European Regulators Lay Out Demands and Fines in Google Antitrust Case,Regulators say that Google uses its 90 percent market share in Europe to favor its own services over those of rivals like Microsoft.,0,"['ORG', 'PERCENT', 'LOC', 'ORG']",0.6,1.0,pos,1,1
2015-06-23,European Officials Push Telecom Regulating for Tech,Many regulators in Europe say the divide between telecom companies and American tech companies is fast eroding.,0,"['LOC', 'NORP']",0.2333333333333333,0.3666666666666667,pos,0,0
2015-06-23,Credit Karma Raises $175 Million,"With the new capital, the online personal finance company is said to be valued at $3.5 billion.",3,['MONEY'],0.06818181818181818,0.37727272727272726,pos,0,0
2015-06-23,Tech Companies Line Up Behind ‘Containers’ and the Cloud,"So-called software containers got backing from companies including Cisco Systems and Google, while another group of companies detailed plans to automate certain aspects of cloud computing.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.30714285714285716,0.6607142857142857,pos,0,0
2015-06-24,"Video Feature: Apps for Summer Travel, Concerts and Grilling","Specialized apps provide help with many seasonal pursuits, including planning vacation activities, packing for a trip and even grilling the perfect steak.",2,['ORG'],0.75,0.75,pos,1,0
2015-06-24,"Amazon Echo, a.k.a. Alexa, Is a Personal Aide in Need of Schooling","The Amazon Echo is an artificially intelligent personal assistant answering to the name Alexa. It’s not yet heavy on the “intelligent,” but could one day be useful.",1,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.34,0.52,pos,1,0
2015-06-25,Michael Wolff’s New Book Celebrates the Success of Old Media,Michael Wolff’s latest book is a thoughtful essay on the state of the cultural and financial wars besieging the media industry.,1,['PERSON'],0.25,0.375,pos,0,0
2015-06-25,Prison Term Sought for Private Eye Who Hacked Email,"Despite a court recommendation otherwise, prosecutors want Eric Saldarriaga to serve time to send a message about illegal hacking.",3,['PERSON'],-0.5,0.5,neg,0,0
2015-06-26,‘Drunk Wedding’ Faced Too High a Bar to the Big Screen,"Paramount Pictures’ microbudget comedy “Drunk Wedding” had a successful screening and the studio’s support, but it was still left at the altar.",0,"['ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART']",0.08333333333333333,0.65,pos,1,1
2015-06-29,AOL in Deal With Microsoft to Take Over Display Ad Business,"AOL will take over management and sales of display, mobile and video advertising that appears on Xbox, Skype and other Microsoft products in several countries.",2,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",-0.0625,0.1875,neg,1,1
2015-06-30,U.S. Chamber of Commerce Works Globally to Fight Antismoking Measures,The American trade group and its foreign affiliates pit countries against one another and lobby on behalf of the tobacco industry around the world.,0,['NORP'],-0.0625,0.0625,neg,0,0
2015-06-30,E.U. to End Cellphone Roaming Charges in 2017,"The new rules, which will apply to people who travel across the 28-member bloc, are accompanied by regulations on so-called net neutrality.",2,['CARDINAL'],0.06818181818181818,0.22727272727272727,pos,0,0
2015-01-07,A Venture Capital Giant Says: Bubble? What Bubble?,"Andreessen Horowitz says there is cause for concern at the rapid increase in tech start-ups with high values, but the recent exuberance in Silicon Valley differs from that of the dot-com era.",3,"['PERSON', 'LOC']",0.08,0.39499999999999996,pos,0,0
2015-01-07,Google Photos Mistakenly Labels Black People ‘Gorillas’,Google apologized after a user posted a photo on Twitter showing that the Google Photos app had labeled black people as “gorillas.”,0,"['ORG', 'PERSON']",-0.16666666666666666,0.43333333333333335,neg,0,0
2015-08-07,An Offline N.Y.S.E. Makes Barely a Ripple in a Day’s Trading,"As the stoppage on Wednesday showed, the modern world of stock trading is much quicker, more complex and reliant on sophisticated computers — and in many cases able to adapt.",0,['DATE'],0.3,0.5035714285714286,pos,1,1
2015-12-07,Sundar Pichai of Google Talks About Phone Intrusion,Google’s senior vice president of products speaks at length about how Google products and apps try to balance giving you information with letting you live your life.,0,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.13636363636363635,0.5,pos,0,0
2015-12-07,Asian Tech Start-Ups Quietly Earn Backing,"So far this year, Asia has created 11 tech companies with valuations of $1 billion or more, compared with 19 in North America.",0,"['DATE', 'LOC', 'CARDINAL', 'MONEY', 'CARDINAL', 'LOC']",0.3,0.75,pos,0,0
2015-07-13,"CrowdStrike, Cybersecurity Services Provider, Raises $100 Million","The investment was led by Google Capital, in what it says will be the first of several cybersecurity deals.",1,"['ORG', 'ORDINAL']",0.125,0.16666666666666666,pos,0,0
2015-07-13,"Uber Out of the Running for Here, Nokia’s Digital Mapping Service","Uber’s global plans will not include the multibillion-dollar purchase of Here, the main competitor to Google Maps.",0,"['MONEY', 'ORG']",0.08333333333333333,0.16666666666666666,pos,0,0
2015-07-14,FanDuel to Announce It Has Raised $275 Million More,The money is meant to help the daily fantasy sports start-up gain customers and expand its global presence as the popularity of online sports betting draws big new entrants like Yahoo.,3,"['DATE', 'ORG']",0.03409090909090909,0.13863636363636364,pos,0,0
2015-07-15,"Video Feature: Before the Music Festival, Know the Lineup and the Lyrics","Apps can help fans know when their favorite performers are appearing, navigate the concert site and even learn the words to the songs they might hear.",2,['PERSON'],0.5,1.0,pos,1,0
2015-07-15,Lawrence Summers to Join Board of ‘Hyperdata’ Start-Up,"The appointment of the former Treasury secretary is a coup for Premise, whose local-data-amassing app has the potential to track global prices more quickly than official sources.",2,['ORG'],0.16666666666666666,0.4,pos,1,0
2015-07-16,Twitter’s Communications Chief Leaves as It Seeks New Message,"Gabriel Stricker is leaving his position as the troubled social networking company’s chief spokesman, and the company said it was shifting its communications strategy and direction.",2,['PERSON'],-0.23333333333333334,0.5333333333333333,neg,0,0
2015-07-16,Google Revenues Up 11% as Earnings Surpass Forecast,"The search company’s new chief financial officer, Ruth Porat, said the results “reflect continued growth across the breadth of our products.”",3,['PERSON'],0.06818181818181818,0.22727272727272727,pos,0,0
2015-07-20,Morgan Stanley’s Profit Tops Estimates,Strong revenue from trading at the Wall Street bank drove performance for the second quarter.,3,['DATE'],0.21666666666666665,0.36666666666666664,pos,1,0
2015-07-21,"Apple Profit Up 38%, but iPhone Sales Disappoint Wall Street","While the quarter’s phone sales were one-third higher than a year ago, at 47.5 million, they fell short of analysts’ estimates, and the stock fell.",2,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']",0.125,0.4,pos,1,0
2015-07-21,Facebook Loses Appeal on New York Search Warrants,"A New York appeals court agreed with a lower court that only a defendant could challenge a search warrant, and then only during a hearing before a trial.",3,['GPE'],0.04545454545454545,0.8181818181818182,pos,1,0
2015-07-21,A $7 Billion Charge at Microsoft Leads to Its Largest Loss Ever,A $7.5 billion accounting charge for the company’s acquisition of Nokia was a drag on the software maker’s fourth-quarter.,0,"['MONEY', 'ORG', 'DATE']",-0.1,0.07083333333333333,neg,1,0
2015-07-21,"Yahoo Posts Loss, Despite Rise in Its Display Ad Business",The uptick in Yahoo’s core display advertising business accompanied strong growth in newer businesses like video and mobile advertising.,2,['ORG'],0.4333333333333333,0.7333333333333333,pos,1,0
2015-07-22,Keeping Dictation on a Mac Private,"Also, how to move documents and photos to a new computer after switching to Windows 10.",2,['ORG'],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,1,0
2015-07-23,"Amazon Reports Unexpected Profit, and Stock Soars","A reason for the company’s success has been its cloud computing division, Amazon Web Services, which generated $1.82 billion in revenue last quarter.",0,"['ORG', 'MONEY', 'DATE']",0.15,0.03333333333333333,pos,0,0
2015-07-24,Daily Report: Amazon Shows Profit for a Change,"A reason for the company’s success has been its cloud computing division, Amazon Web Services, which generated $1.82 billion in revenue last quarter.",0,"['ORG', 'MONEY', 'DATE']",0.15,0.03333333333333333,pos,1,1
2015-07-24,The New Stars of the Tech Sector,"James B. Stewart, on CNBC, discusses how chief financial officers like Ruth Porat of Google are bringing new success to technologies companies.",3,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.14545454545454545,0.15151515151515152,pos,1,1
2015-07-24,Donald Trump’s Wealth and Poll Numbers Complicate News Media’s Coverage,With each moment of Trumpian bravura — such as reading the cellphone number of Senator Lindsey Graham — news outlets must weigh whether it is worthy of a story. They most often decide yes.,3,"['NORP', 'PERSON']",0.27777777777777773,0.6666666666666666,pos,1,1
2015-07-28,Daily Report: Jack Dorsey Readies for His Close-Up,The interim Twitter chief will make his most extensive comments in quite some time during Twitter’s earnings report briefing later Tuesday.,3,"['PRODUCT', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'DATE']",0.16666666666666666,0.27777777777777773,pos,1,1
2015-07-28,"As Tech Booms, Workers Turn to Coding for Career Change","Schools that offer accelerated training in digital skills are drawing more and more “career changers,” and graduates can make six-figure base salaries.",1,['CARDINAL'],0.04999999999999999,0.5,pos,1,1
2015-07-28,Windows 10 Review: A Throwback With Upgrades in Software and Security,"The Start button is back, in a more modern fashion, and the tablet mode, while perhaps intimidating for longtime Windows users, has familiar touches.",2,['NORP'],0.26875,0.325,pos,1,1
2015-07-29,How Many Times Has Your Personal Information Been Exposed to Hackers?,Find out which parts of your identity may have been stolen in major hacking attacks over the last several years.,3,['DATE'],0.020833333333333332,0.18888888888888888,pos,1,1
2015-07-29,Yahoo Offers New Mobile Chat Service Featuring Silent Video,"Last year, Yahoo all but gave up on updating its Messenger mobile apps. Now, the company is introducing a new, decidedly quirky messaging app with a surprising combination of features.",2,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT']",0.20909090909090908,0.5053030303030304,pos,1,1
2015-07-30,A Facebook Project to Beam Data From Drones Is a Step Closer to Flight,"The company said its unmanned aerial vehicle, intended to bring Internet access to remote areas, is ready for tests in the upper atmosphere, most likely in the United States.",0,['GPE'],0.12,0.44000000000000006,pos,1,1
2015-07-31,Microsoft Said to Invest Big Sum in Uber,"Microsoft has agreed to contribute a substantial amount of the financing in a recent round, which totals about $1 billion, people with knowledge of the matter said.",0,"['ORG', 'MONEY']",-0.1,0.325,neg,0,0
2015-07-31,"Yahoo Buys Polyvore, a Site Focused on Shopping","Yahoo has acquired Polyvore, a social shopping site that lets users pick and share clothing ensembles — and purchase all items shown.",2,['ORG'],0.03333333333333333,0.06666666666666667,pos,0,0
2015-01-08,Joel S. Marcus on Taking the Ego Out of Leading,The chief executive of Alexandria Real Estate Equities talks about the value of trying to let employees persuade you when you’re making decisions.,2,['ORG'],0.2,0.30000000000000004,pos,1,1
2015-04-08,Siebel Institute Seeks to Make the Smart Grid Smarter,The new Siebel Energy Institute is backing research into the software needed to deliver the energy-saving promise of smart-grid technology.,3,['ORG'],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,0,0
2015-04-08,Netflix Offers Expanded Maternity and Paternity Leave,The company said it was offering unlimited leave for new mothers and fathers for one year after the birth or adoption of a child.,0,['DATE'],0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,0,0
2015-05-08,‘Right to Be Forgotten’ Online Could Spread,Some countries’ demands for the erasure of search engine results on privacy grounds could soon affect even information available in the United States.,3,['GPE'],0.4,0.4,pos,1,1
2015-06-08,Daily Report: Google and the Spread of the ‘Right to Be Forgotten’,"Unlike so many things that happen on the Internet, it might be outside of Google’s control.",1,['ORG'],0.25,0.275,pos,0,0
2015-09-08,"Vogue Ads Skip a Step, Linking Readers to Target","Using their smartphones, readers of the fashion magazine scan items tagged with Shazam’s logo to learn more or buy them immediately.",1,['ORG'],0.5,0.5,pos,1,0
2015-10-08,Google to Reorganize as Alphabet to Keep Its Lead as an Innovator,"Under the new name, Alphabet, the company is signaling that it has essentially become a collection of disparate businesses.",3,['GPE'],0.06818181818181818,0.37727272727272726,pos,0,0
2015-10-08,Sundar Pichai Will Lead Google With Users in Mind,The newly appointed chief executive owes his new job to his success in making Google products easier to use and thus more popular.,2,['ORG'],0.3345454545454546,0.4618181818181818,pos,0,0
2015-12-08,Daily Report: What Google’s Reinvention Means Is Far From Clear,"When Google splits into smaller parts under an umbrella company called Alphabet, one section of the company will be extremely profitable. The rest? That has not been explained.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']",-0.0625,0.75,neg,0,0
2015-08-13,Google Unveils New Chrome Operating System for Business Customers,"Google and Dell show off the next version of Chromebooks. They look nice, but what really matters is changes in the back end to get older applications online.",3,"['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']",0.19333333333333333,0.30666666666666664,pos,1,1
2015-08-13,"Even in the New Alphabet, Google Keeps Its Capital G","Google’s name is a protected trademark, and the company has fought to keep it from becoming generic, as brands like thermos, cellophane and others have.",0,['ORG'],0.225,0.42500000000000004,pos,1,1
2015-08-14,Daily Report: Google Stays in the News with Chromebooks and Antitrust Issues,"Google unveiled a new version of its Chrome operating system, along with Chromebook computing devices made by Dell. It’s been busy week for the company that’s reinventing itself as Alphabet while dealing with antitrust concerns in Europe.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'LOC']",0.11818181818181818,0.37727272727272726,pos,1,1
2015-08-14,Where to Find Symbols on Tablets,"Locate copyright, trademark and other symbols on Android and iOS tablets; and find how much free space is available on a Windows 7 drive.",0,"['GPE', 'FAC']",0.225,0.525,pos,1,1
2015-08-17,Daily Report: Where to See the Inequality Gap Wrought by the Tech Boom,"Perhaps nowhere is the inequality gap created by the latest technology boom as evident as in San Francisco’s Tenderloin neighborhood, a longtime low-income area that is now increasingly populated by tech start-ups.",3,"['GPE', 'NORP']",0.375,0.575,pos,0,0
2015-08-18,Unicorns Hunt for Talent Among Silicon Valley’s Giants,"Unicorns, start-ups like Uber and Airbnb valued at $1 billion or more, are hiring people from the likes of Google, especially in fields like mapping.",0,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'MONEY', 'ORG']",0.25,0.75,pos,1,0
2015-08-18,Pivotal Software Gets a New Leader and Announces Strong Cloud Revenue,"Paul Maritz is stepping aside as chief executive of Pivotal Software. Pivotal, the cloud-computing spinoff of EMC, also announced strong growth in cloud subscriptions.",0,"['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.4777777777777778,0.7777777777777778,pos,1,0
2015-08-19,"Daily Report: In Silicon Valley, Start-Up Recruiting Battles Heat Up",You know there’s a boom under way in Silicon Valley when it gets even tougher to hire top engineers and other personnel.,0,['LOC'],0.1875,0.4375,pos,1,1
2015-08-19,Chromebooks Gaining on iPads in School Sector,"Last year, about 3.9 million Chromebooks were shipped in the education sector, an increase in unit sales of more than 310 percent compared with the previous year, IDC said.",0,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'NORP', 'PERCENT', 'DATE', 'ORG']",0.11111111111111112,0.24444444444444444,pos,1,1
2015-08-21,Unseen Burdens in Chrome That Can Lead a Mac to Lag,"Determining whether a browser might be the source of a computer’s sluggishness, and a look at Facebook’s “authentic identity” policy.",3,['PERSON'],0.5,0.75,pos,1,1
2015-08-24,Intel to Invest Heavily in Software That Enhances Cloud-Computing Capabilities,An expected $100 million in funding to be directed to cloud-computing software and a related start-up reflects the company’s view of its own future.,0,['MONEY'],0.125,0.48125,pos,1,1
2015-08-26,The Appeal of Free: 75 Million Users Download Windows 10 in First Month,"The early audience-building of both users and developers is crucial for Microsoft, and the early results look encouraging.",2,['ORG'],0.06666666666666667,0.5333333333333333,pos,1,1
2015-08-27,Google Rebuts Europe on Antitrust Charges,The American technology giant would face fines worth billions of dollars if it is found to have broken the European Union’s competition rules.,3,"['NORP', 'MONEY', 'ORG']",-0.020000000000000007,0.3,neg,1,1
2015-08-28,Uber Hires Two Engineers Who Showed Cars Could Be Hacked,"The company’s latest talent grab snared Charlie Miller and Chris Valasek, who recently startled the auto industry by hacking remotely into Fiat and Chrysler vehicles.",1,"['PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.13333333333333333,0.44999999999999996,pos,0,0
2015-08-31,Daily Report: Educational Software Gets Attention from State Politicians,"In the past year, 182 bills intended to protect student data have been introduced in 46 states as legislators attempt to draw a red line around the privacy of children.",0,"['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']",-0.125,0.125,neg,0,0
2015-08-31,Hotels Fight Back Against Sites Like Expedia and Priceline,"Hotel chains are using rewards points and benefits to encourage guests to book directly, while the industry fights a merger of Expedia and Orbitz.",1,"['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.1,0.4,pos,0,0
2015-01-09,European Firms Team Up to Target Google in Civil Lawsuits,A law firm and public affairs company have created an online platform to help European companies sue Google for financial damages from anticompetitive practices.,0,"['NORP', 'ORG']",-0.05,0.11666666666666667,neg,0,0
2015-01-09,Daily Report: Hotel Chains Get Tough With Travel Websites,"For years, hotels have grudgingly let websites make arrangements for their customers. But now they are fighting back with customer perks and outreach to regulators to keep the sites from getting too powerful.",0,['DATE'],-0.09999999999999999,0.6666666666666666,neg,0,0
2015-01-09,"Google Antitrust Inquiries Spread Over Globe, With India the Latest Problem","While Google’s biggest regulatory challenge remains in Europe, authorities around the world are investigating its practices, with a report from India’s competition commission its latest problem.",0,"['ORG', 'LOC', 'GPE']",0.5,0.9,pos,0,0
2015-02-09,Scrutiny of Security Start-Ups May Signal Shift in Venture Funding,Cybersecurity companies have had an easy time raising money in Silicon Valley over the last few years. But investors are starting to ask about profit and sustainability.,0,"['LOC', 'DATE']",0.058333333333333334,0.275,pos,1,1
2015-02-09,Daily Report: Google’s Driverless Car Learns to Navigate an Imperfect World,"Google’s self-driving cars continue to do the right thing in road tests. Unfortunately, the same can’t be said of humans.",3,['ORG'],-0.07142857142857144,0.5535714285714285,neg,1,1
2015-02-09,Competitors Accuse Google of Using Search to Diminish Apps,"In November, Google will start penalizing the search rankings of sites that show “please install our app” ads, a move that rivals say has less to do with providing users with a good experience and more to do with protecting Google’s business.",3,"['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG']",0.3444444444444444,0.3888888888888889,pos,1,1
2015-07-09,"Marketing to Sports Fans Online, With Help From Google and Social Networks","As brands try to align themselves with football games beyond television, Google, Facebook, Twitter and Snapchat shop around new marketing products.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG']",0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,1,0
2015-09-09,"Apple Unveils iPhone 6S, and Breaks Own Taboos With Other Offerings","The smartphone, and the larger 6S Plus variant, took center stage at Apple’s product announcement event, but a bigger iPad and a beefed-up Apple TV had turns in the spotlight.",2,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']",-0.03333333333333333,0.3666666666666667,neg,0,0
2015-09-09,Getting Updates on Android and Nexus,"For its Nexus devices, Google will provide major system updates for at least two years after the release date, and security patches for three years.",3,"['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE']",-0.11875,0.45,neg,0,0
2015-09-09,Apple’s iPhone Keeps Going Its Own Way,"Unlike other tech devices that have become commodities, Apple’s iPhone remains in demand as both a highly useful item and a status symbol.",0,['ORG'],0.0875,0.1875,pos,0,0
2015-10-09,Answers to Questions About Apple’s New Products,Here are our responses to reader queries about the new Apple devices introduced at a company event on Wednesday.,3,"['ORG', 'DATE']",0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,1,0
2015-10-09,A Venezuelan in Silicon Valley Finds a Niche in Finance,Meyer Malka of Ribbit Capital became a rising force in Silicon Valley by betting on financial technology when few others did.,3,"['ORG', 'LOC']",-0.1,0.05,neg,1,0
2015-09-14,"With ‘Brandeis’ Project, Darpa Seeks to Advance Privacy Technology","The Pentagon’s advanced research arm is supporting research in privacy technology. Strong privacy protection, it says, is essential for the data economy to flourish.",2,['ORG'],0.2708333333333333,0.4708333333333333,pos,0,0
2015-09-14,Russian Authorities Rule Google Broke Antitrust Regulations,"Officials said that the company had abused its dominant market position with Android, its mobile operating system, by favoring the company’s own own services over those of its rivals.",0,['ORG'],0.6,1.0,pos,0,0
2015-09-14,YouTube ‘Dancing Baby’ Copyright Ruling Sets Fair Use Guideline,"In a case symbolic of clashes over copyright online, a federal court ruled that copyright holders must consider fair use before asking YouTube to remove content.",3,['ORG'],0.7,0.9,pos,0,0
2015-09-15,Salesforce Plans to Give Customers Amazon-Type Analytics,A well-known programmer says he’s building advanced data analysis that thousands of companies could use on the cloud-computing platform provided by Salesforce.com.,0,"['CARDINAL', 'ORG']",0.4,0.6,pos,1,0
2015-09-17,Pinterest Crosses User Milestone of 100 Million,"Pinterest said it has crossed 100 million monthly active users. That exceeds user estimates for the online scrapbooking start-up, though it remains dwarfed by other digital contemporaries.",2,"['CARDINAL', 'DATE']",-0.0861111111111111,0.325,neg,1,1
2015-09-21,France Rejects Google’s Efforts to Limit Application of Privacy Ruling,"Several European privacy regulators, particularly in France, have urged that the so-called right to be forgotten be applied to all of Google’s search domains.",3,"['NORP', 'GPE', 'ORG']",0.11309523809523808,0.21726190476190477,pos,1,1
2015-09-21,"4chan Message Board Sold to Founder of 2Channel, a Japanese Web Culture Pioneer","4chan, an anonymous online message board with more than 20 million monthly visitors, is being acquired by the founder of 2channel, a Japanese message board that inspired 4chan’s founder.",2,"['TIME', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'NORP', 'PERCENT']",0.25,0.25,pos,1,1
2015-09-22,"Uber Introduces Carpooling Service for Commuters, Starting in China","Uber is aiming to push deeper into China, launching a new commuter-oriented ride service on Wednesday in Chengdu, China.",3,"['GPE', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'GPE']",0.13636363636363635,0.45454545454545453,pos,0,0
2015-09-25,BlackBerry to Sell Android-Based Smartphone,"In its latest earnings report, the company said it was not giving up on the BlackBerry 10, even as it announced the Android phone.",3,"['LAW', 'GPE']",0.5,0.9,pos,0,0
